In 20 years of working in enterprise
tech, I've never seen a shift happen so
fast. It's very much been a slowly
slowly then all at once kind of feeling.
Agents like OpenClaw and Claude Co-work
are showing us the near future of how
the internet will work. Agent first and
human second. And every SAS CEO is
pivoting hard to catch up. There's some
big opportunities happening if you're
paying attention to the right things.
All new technology shifts start with
developers. They are the early adopters,
the builders, the creatives playing at
the edge of what's coming next. And
we've seen that with the likes of
OpenClaw and Claw Code. Next comes the
companies that serve the developers. The
likes of Stripe, Verscell, AWS, and then
the entire consumer and B2B market comes
afterwards. So, right now, we're at
stage two. And there are some new
releases in the last 24 hours that we're
going to talk about to help you
understand that. So stay with me on this
one because by the end of the video
you'll have a completely different
picture of where agent power development
is heading and I'll show you exactly how
I'm setting up my own projects to take
advantage of all of this right now. So
Andre Karpathy coined the term agentic
engineering. It's the idea is that human
don't need to write most of the code
anymore. But here's the part that most
people are missing. Coding was actually
the easy bit to automate. The hard part
was always the infrastructure around the
code. So the other 70% is provisioning,
setting up databases, configuring
authentication, integrating pay
payments, managing hosting, dealing with
environment variables and juggling API
keys across a dozen different services.
So just to get your head around why this
is such a big deal, this article here is
probably just over a year old at this
stage, but Andre Kaparthi talks about
how he's trying to set up a simple menu
generator application. Now the code
generation is the easy part but then you
have to go and connect to the open AI
API replicate AI for image generation
you need to actually deploy this app
somewhere via versel you have to manage
bills etc then you need to have clerk
authentication in place so you can
actually secure it and of course you
want to manage payments and that would
be via stripe so in that context let me
show you what stripe just did stripe
projects it's at projects.dev dev and
the pitch is dead simple. Provision and
manage your entire application stack
from the CLI. So how does all this work
practically? Well, you basically just
install and initialize the Stripe CLI.
You add in whatever services you want.
So that might be Neon DB, Postgres,
Payments, and then Stripe will manage
your tokens, your credentials, and your
payments and upgrades to any of those
different services. And from a security
perspective, have all your ENV variables
brought down from the cloud and synced
into your projects safely so you can
work across multiple different projects
and teams. You can see already the value
of this. If your agent has access to
hosting and provisioning like Verscell
and Railway databases via Neon and
Superbase, analytics and authentication,
this is going to be a big speed increase
for developing your projects, improving
your safety, and allowing agents to do a
lot more work for us. So, if you want
access to this, it's in early alpha.
Everyone is going to have to sign up to
the waiting list, but hopefully we'll
see this rolled out in the next couple
of weeks. Don't worry, I'm going to talk
about another project you can use right
now and later on the video, how I
personally have approached this workflow
for building out my projects over the
last couple of weeks. So, I'm fascinated
by this idea of an autonomous company
where all of your company data becomes a
single source of truth that AI agents
can then operate on. So, our sponsor
today, monday.com, is headed exactly in
that direction. It's not just a
productivity tool anymore. It's morphing
into an entire company operating system
augmented by agents and driven by
humans. It can be timeconuming to set up
a new workspace and put in all your
project trackers etc. But Monday will
actually build out your workspaces for
you based on your customized prompt. So
for instance here I got it to set up a
client management tracker. Based on my
prompt, it filled out projects, tasks,
registration forms, but I don't even
have to get down into the weeds in
editing everything manually. I can now
use Sidekick to have a conversation with
the data that's in here, change it, ask
for reports, manipulate it in any way
that I want. I can plug in automations
and use Monday's powerful API. So, I can
use it alongside co-work claw or even
open claw. And of course, I saved the
best for last. We have a brand new vibe
tool. So, I could do things like build a
roadmap planner, feature tracker. So,
here's a quick content calendar app that
I vibe coded with just one prompt. We've
got timelines, matrix, view, and I can
add in any new objectives that I have.
Thanks to monday.com for sponsoring this
video. Check out the link in the
description down below. Now, Stripe
Projects solves the provisioning problem
beautifully for the services it
supports. But your agents like Claw
Code, Cursor, and OpenClaw need access
to way more than just that list. They
need to be able to call Slack APIs, hit
GitHub, interact with your CMS, talk to
monitoring tools, potentially hundreds
of different types of services,
including anything you would need to run
a business like Gmail, Google Drive,
etc. And that's where Gent comes in. It
sits between your agents and all the
different APIs, MCPs, and tools that are
out there. So, one of the biggest
problems with having agents run the web
for us is they're going to need security
credentials and they're going to need
various levels of permissions to use
those credentials. Already I've got 20
of them connected in co-work to help run
my project, the self-driving business.
And already it's become a bit of a
security nightmare and a pain to
provision each one. And that's what Gent
is really setting out to solve. So,
Gentic runs in its own Docker container.
You can spin that up locally on your
machine. You can put it on a railway,
AWS, wherever you want. and that's where
you're going to store all your
credentials and all your connection
information for your agent. Very simple
to set up. You just need Docker running
in the background. So basically just get
clone the project, change into the
directory and then run docker compose.
So once that's installed, you just need
to open in your browser local host on
port 8,900.
So what it does then is it helps
generate a key that you're going to give
to your open claw or claw coworker,
whatever agent that you're using. So
this is where it gets really cool. when
you're actually inside in the API
catalog here, you can see the number of
APIs that Gentic has access to. So, what
you do then is essentially search for
any API that you want to be able to
interact with or that you want your
agent to be able to interact with. So,
pretty much anything you can do with the
Google Gmail API, you can enable here.
The next cool thing that's interesting
about Gentic is how it manages
workflows. Every time our agent is going
to do things for us in a
non-deterministic way, it's going to be
burning a ton of tokens. So, Gentic
takes this a step further with the idea
of workflows and using a protocol called
Arzo basically figures out how a task is
commonly done, codifies that in JSON so
it can be replicated over and over. You
can imagine over time as we start to use
agents for everything. This is going to
be a huge economic saving. Okay. So,
let's say I want to set up uh notion.
So, add credential. Let's just search if
it's in the list. Yes, it is. Uh we need
to put in our API key here and then it
gets saved. So you can find the
integrations in your profile and then go
to connections and then develop or
manage integrations. So in notion just
go to your internal integrations create
new integration. So that gives me a
token so that my agent open cloud claw
code whatever you want can now talk to
everything that I have in notion and I
can set the level of access there as
well. Now once you've got it set up you
can see here's all the operations that
the API allows because what Gentic has
done is basically pulled in all the
different operations. my instance of
claw code successfully connected but
then it said hey you don't have
permissions set up and this is so
important for agents and particularly
for businesses that want to be AI first
you can give access to your agent but
what is it allowed to do what
permissions does it have so you can set
that up through toolkits you can have
different toolkits and credentials set
up depending on who's accessing it step
through getting access it hit a
permissions problem it asked me to sort
out and then boom it went and created
this page within notion so essentially
this is kind of the next level of
infrastructure we need for working
securely with agents We've had all these
novel applications like OpenClaw which
is powerful but hugely insecure. Gentic
and the likes of Stripe and other
providers are stepping in now to solve
those infrastructural problems which I'm
here for. Okay, so it's very clear how
this is going. Agents are going to
outpace humans as the main operators on
the web. It is going to become primarily
an agentic web and we are going to
become secondary users. We need to start
addressing what all that looks like.
First thing I would do is if you're
building any kind of company in 2026, it
needs to be agent first. It needs to
have great APIs, MCPs, even a CLI and
very clear markdown driven documentation
on how an agent should interact with
your services. If you want to know how I
personally developed with an AI
infrastructure and CLI first mentality,
here's the stack I'm currently using and
I teach via my course and community at
switchdimension.com.
So number one, GitHub. I have stopped
visiting github.com. I'm using the CLI
for everything. Just using that simple
gh command. I'm doing all my version
control, pull requests, uh, CI/CD,
everything now happens from the command
line and the agent is running this for
me. Second of all, databases. Before you
used to have to go to Superbase or Neon
and get the credentials, set it up in
your environment files. No, just plug in
the Neon DB CLI as an example and it
will actually do all that for you. So
when I say, "Hey, we probably need a
Postgres database in the background
here." Instead of me going and setting
that up via the dashboard, via the Neon
CLI, it just goes and provisions one,
sets it up, spins it down as needed.
Huge timesaver. Use Versell deployment.
Use the Verscell CLI. It will basically
go and check the build logs. It will
deploy for you. It'll provision any
instances that you need. All managed
again by the agent and getting you out
of the way. Clerk for authentication. So
in terms of using test users, setting up
users, managing users, all done via
clerk off and the clerk CLI. And then of
course for managing payments, you've got
the Stripe API which is going to become
hugely important in the coming years.
And you can use Post Hog for analytics.
Get your agent to check on processes to
make sure everything is up and running,
if there's any errors, and to make sure
that all your system and all your
systems are in good health. You can do
pretty much everything you want via
CLIs. Now, in terms of development, in
just the last two weeks alone, I've seen
a huge shift in how companies are
thinking about this. Absolutely. think
about a CLI MCP and API first approach
for the agent web going forward in 2026.
So the other thing I've been using to
speed up my development and also secure
my development is by using one password
to manage all my environment variables.
So in a nutshell, you set up a new
environment in one password for whatever
project you're working on. And in there
you store all the critical environment
variables. And then what one password
can do is actually mount those variables
into whatever project folder that you're
using so that your agent doesn't get to
see them or nobody else gets to see them
and they're kept safe. And if you've got
multiple different projects running and
you suddenly learn that your project is
compromised in some way, you can
actually edit them all from one password
if you need to rotate the keys or
anything else like that. And what's more
than that, it's just a great time saver.
I'm constantly spinning up new projects
that need entropic or open AI keys. I
have them stored in a temporary
environment container I can give to the
agent to drop in. I don't need to go
provisioning new API keys or anything
else like that. Let me leave you with
the bigger picture. What we're seeing
right now is the early phase of a
platform shift. Just like when we went
from desktop to web, web to mobile,
we're going from a human first interface
to an agent first interface. So
companies that get this, Stripe, Neon,
Railway, Gent, Clerk, they're going to
win the next era. The tools that are
easiest for agents to use will get
chosen first. So we've come from the
concept of page rank with Google. So
basically, if your content is popular,
lots of people click on it and they link
back to it. It rises up and up and up,
gets higher in the search results.
That's how you get to number one. I
think we're entering a new era of the
agent rank. So, basically, your service,
your company, whatever it is, is going
to be ranked by agents. Now, it's not
going to be reading your emotional copy
on a homepage. It's going to be
realizing, does it have a CLI? Does it
have a good MCP? Has it got great API
with good documentation? What's the
performance like? What is the cost of
this service? and what other trust
variables do I need to ensure this is a
good choice for the process I'm about to
do as companies we need to think about
how we manage around this and as
builders we need to think about what we
build and how we build in this agent
first world personally I think the best
way to understand and take advantage of
this new shift is to become a builder
yourself right now we're in the phase
where developers are using these kind of
CLI to build out applications and move a
whole lot faster it's at the cutting
edge of what's possible it will be quite
some time before the rest of the market,
e-commerce consumers, the rest of B2B
catches up with this. If you understand
how agents are starting to interact and
what developers are building now to
solve their problems, you can
extrapolate those and start to apply
them to any domain you are interested
in. If you want to go deeper on building
this kind of autonomous workflow, check
out the switch dimension course. The
link is in the description down below.
We cover exactly this kind of stuff step
by step. Also, drop me a comment. What's
the one service you wish your agent
could set up for you right now? I'm
building a list and I want to know what
is blocking people. And if this was
useful, hit subscribe. I'm covering the
agent first shift every week and it's
moving fast.