In this video, we are going to explore
how we can create highle architectural
diagram using MCP server capabilities of
draw.io and xali draw. And to interact
with these MCP servers, we are going to
use cloud desktop and visual studio
code. So let's get started with that. So
first thing I'm just going to open my
cloud desktop. So once you open your
cloud desktop, you need to go to in your
settings. So I'm just going to go to
file and then I'm just going to go to
settings. And under this you can see
these connectors over here. I'm just
going to click on this connector. And
you see this connector. I'm just going
to click on this browse connectors. So
these are the connectors which are built
by third parties and already reviewed by
Enthroy for safety. You can just use
like any of the connectors from here. As
of now, if I search for draw.io,
then there is no connector as such. But
there is a connector for Xkelly Draw. So
let's get started with Xkelly Draw. I'm
just going to click on the connect
and you can see like this is already
over here. It has been connected. If you
just want to have a look like which
connector is already in place. There is
also you can also check it from this
customize button. You can also click on
click over here. Then you can go to
connectors and here also you could see
okay this connector has been listed
here. This particular connector comes
with these specific tools. Now let's go
back to our chat and let's try to draw
something out here. I'm just going to
say use Xali draw to create an
architectural diagram for a modern web
application. It should include a react
front end fast repair back end
postgsql database and there are some
specific details. So you can pass your
prompt like this model is default one
which is set 4.6 and you can see I'm on
free plan. So it's going to work in the
free plan also. So I'm just going to go
ahead and submit this.
And first thing you can see claude is
searching for a tool. It has identified
a tool. And now actually it has started
creating this particular diagram. And
you can see like this particular diagram
in real time how it is you know creating
and it's very cool to see put out all
the boxes based on the description what
we have provided and at the bottom it is
just sharing the details around it. What
you can do if you want to edit the you
can also open this one in excal draw web
page or you can also edit it over here.
So if I just click on edit then you can
see like this particular window has been
opened and I can also just click on any
of the part and can edit it or I can
just directly open it in the web browser
of excelling
permission. I'm just going to say open
link. So from here also actually you can
edit your images and it's very easy to
connect with cloud desktop considering
they do have inbuilt connectors. So you
don't have to pass any kind of config as
such. Now what about draw.io. So when we
see draw.io MCP server then there are
basically three options to connect with
this particular server. One is like we
can just pass this remote URL to connect
to the MCP server. That's one option.
The second option is going to be where
if you're running something on your
local and for that actually you just
have to power this command and other
option is where actually you can pass it
as a skill. So let's see it one by one
because we are using a claw desktop
version so we cannot pass this remote
MCP server we can pass only this
particular command now. So I'm just
going to take this and if I need to add
it into my clot then I'm again going to
go to settings and from here I will just
go to developer. You can see like it's
already added as a local MCP server but
if it is not added then you can just
click on edit.config config and it's
going to open you this claw desktop
config file which you can open it in any
kind of notepad and then in the command
section actually you have to pass you
have to pass the command like this where
we have to pass this npx and then in
arguments we have to pass this
particular section. So we are passing it
here. Now once it has been added into
cloud desktop then you will also see
this in a connector. So if I go over
here in the customize in the connectors
then you can see one is a web version
which xcaly draw and the other is a
desktop one which is a local dev once it
is configured I try to ask this question
where I have specifically asked is to
use draw.io to create a highle payment
diagram and it has created over here. So
I can just open this particular URL and
it has created a payment kind of diagram
like this here also actually it's a
editable version. So it has opened it on
the draw.io and we can just go ahead and
you know modify things accordingly. The
first option was this remote MCP server.
If you want to just try it out where you
want to see the diagram in the inline
chat then I cannot do it on the cloud
desktop. We have to do it on the web
version. But rather than doing over
there, I'm just going to do it in the VS
code. So in the VS code, if you have to
add like any kind of MCP server, then we
have to just click on control shift NP.
I'm on Windows and here I just have to
say add server
and you can see like all these options
because this is going to be the remote
server. So I'm just going to select this
HTTP and it's saying like URL of the MCP
server. So here I can just say this is
going to be the URL and I can just pass
it over here. And then it's saying enter
server ID. I'm just going to say draw
IO. And you can see like it has created
a configuration like this. It's going to
come up with three tools. I'm just going
to start this server. And here we do
have like one particular tool available.
So let me just open GitHub copilot chat
and let's chat with this particular
server. So I can just pass the same
prompt but instead of xkelly draw I'm
specifically asking to use draw.io. Now
it's trying to create a diagram for us
and you can see like it has created it
using draw.io mcp server. In this case,
it's coming in line because it is
rendering MCP app and as mentioned over
here, if you are using this particular
remote MCP server, then the diagram is
going to come in line in the AI chart
interface only using MCP apps protocol.
So, same thing is being reflected over
here. So here we are getting the diagram
in the chart itself. We can zoom out or
zoom in just to see specific section but
it's not going to get opened on the web
portal. It's going to be opened here
only. Now the third option what we have
is creating draw.io diagram using
skills. So I'm just going to go to
skills and I'm just going to click on
this
and I'm just going to say upload skill
and I just need to pass an MD file over
here. So to do that I'm just going to go
to this full documentation which is
here. From here I will go to the parent
one. And here we do have this skill.md
file. So I'm just going to download it
from here. And the same file I can
upload it here.
So this is a skill.md file and this is
going to be the custom skill which we
are uploading. And now you can see I do
have this draw.io IO diagram skill and
it has been listed in the my skill
section and it has been on by default.
Now if I have to invoke that skill then
I can just say use draw IO skill to
create highlevel payment design
diagram
and it has started reading this draw
your skill which we have just added it
and you can see like it has started
creating the diagram in the XML format.
So let's wait for this to be completed
and it has automatically routed us to
the web URL where actually we can see
and edit our diagram
and same thing it has listed here also
so with the details like what kind of
layers has been included. So that's how
actually you can interact with Xkelly
draw and draw.io using multiple options.
That's all what we have in this video.