Today we're going to be looking at how
to use obsidian with open claw and
clawed code to basically create like a
memory where you have more context. You
have a much powerful agent and it can
basically have full context wherever you
go whether that's to for example claude
code whether that's to claude directly
whether that's to open claw etc. Now the
main point of this is a free way to give
your AI agents full context on what you
do. So you can download Obsidian and
once you've done that, it's going to
look something like this. Now you can
add personal information like you can
see right here. And essentially this
allows you to connect it with as much
sort of ideas and information as you
want directly to whatever AI agent you
want to. Right? So for example, what we
can do here is if we go back to Claude
Co-work now, which I was just using for
computer use a second ago, we can
connect this to Obsidian. And then
inside obsidian we put all our context
or our data. Now why would we want to
add more context and data directly to
something like claude co-work or any of
these AI agents because the quality of
the outputs comes down to the quality of
the data it gets right the more
information you give to these AI agents
the better they can help you and the
better they understand how to help you.
Right? That's the net with the game. So,
we're going to get started with this
now. And I'm going to say, now I think
one of the easiest ways you could
probably do this is you could connect it
directly with something like an MCP.
I don't think it's got a connector for
Obsidian yet, as far as I'm aware. And
we can do the same thing inside
Open Claw, too. Now inside claw as well
because it's working off local files
right we can actually connect this
directly to the files that we've created
inside obsidian right so inside obsidian
anytime you create any information or
journals or that sort of thing you can
use
this as a folder on your laptop like
this right and so we can connect
Obsidian fault to our claude co-work so
it has full context on us so let's try
that. Now, we're going to create a new
project inside Claw Co-work, which is a
new feature they've just launched
recently, which helps us connect to
Obsidian even easier. And this could be,
for example, managing your personal
life. It could be, for example,
organizing your work. Whatever contexts
you want to put inside Obsidian, you can
link. And also, it's not just limited to
one AI agent. So, for example, if you're
using claw day-to-day, you could use it
memory. But the problem is that you
can't export that memory to open claw as
easily and it's not updated in real
time. If you link your folder from
obsidian to open claw and claw co-work
running locally then anytime you add
information to it that's new it's going
to get updated right that's the point.
So we can open up our obsidian vault
like and now it's got access to it right
as you can see. So it's got access to
the files as you can see right here. So
if we now go inside Obsidian
and we put information about whatever
your business is. So I'm going to use
for example the AR profit boarding
example. We go inside here and I'll put
rename this. We add some information
about us. Right. This. So we've got
details of what we do, what we sell,
etc. And then if we go back to Claude Co
now, it's got those details right here.
Right. is uh now I'm going to say okay
use Obsidian to write a new sales page
based on
the AIPB data in there. All right. So we
got details of what we sell here. Then
if we go back to Claude Co-work it's
looking at the business database details
right here. Right. So it's got all the
information from right there. Now we can
do the same thing inside openclaw to
sync these up as well. Right. And so now
I'm going to say okay use my local
obsidian vault plus connect to it so
that you have all my data. Now obviously
you only share stuff that you're
comfortable with sharing inside here.
So, you know, if you're not comfortable
with connecting this to open claw or to,
for example, claw to co-work, then you
don't have to, right? And you could
create a separate folder for another
obsidian bolt that you don't want to
share with AI agents. But the main thing
is
that now these AI agents can read these.
Now, also the other cool thing about
this is everything that's stored inside
Obsidian is in a MD file, right? It's a
markdown file. What does that mean?
means that AI can easily look through
the page and understand okay here's what
this guy's doing here's what it's about
here's you know some of his best content
etc and so it can easily read the files
directly inside here right you can see
here it's even understands like the
pricing from the offer because it's got
it directly from the information on our
business inside Obsidian right [snorts]
now you can also do something like you
can periodically sync the Obsidian vault
content into workspace and it's already
got access to this locally as well. So,
that was super easy. And you can see
here is, okay, what would be most useful
to you? What's the goal here? I'm going
to say, okay, use Obsidian
as context for what I do. Plus, I'll
update it regularly with new info.
Inside here, you could have a section
that's okay, here's my goals. Right now,
you'll see here there's four different
types. You got new note, canvas, folder,
and base. Right? So you could have like
for example a folder here that's for
work and then you add your files
underneath it, right? So you could plug
that in right there. You could have a
new folder for example for personal and
then you just add in personal
information about you. And then also
what's quite cool about this is like it
makes it easy for the AI to connect
different information about you, who you
are, what you do, etc. Right? Because
it's got all this stuff in one folder.
So the AI just understands you better.
And so now it says inside openclaw done
up all your vault from whenever I need
context with what you're working on your
business etc. And so if we said okay
create a new sales page inside open claw
and bear in mind like we've already
created the sales page for this with
claude now so it's already understood
the information and what we do etc
pulling it directly from obsidian and
the same inside Google Chrome right so
there you go it says you already got a
sales page it's solid what do you want
me to do with it if we say okay build it
as a live HTML page plus host it
locally. It can now take that
information from obsidian that's just
referenced right there and now it's got
all that context on us. Right? That's
how easy it is to link to claude and to
open claw directly. Right? So easy. So
let's talk about this. What even is
Obsidian? So Obsidian is a free app
where you write notes. But here's the
thing that makes it special, right?
Every note you write saved as a simple
markdown file on your computer, right?
These are sitting on your laptop. Now,
why is that useful? It's because open
claw and clogged co-work directly work
locally, right? And so the AI can read
everything you've written, every idea,
every piece of research, every random
thought that you jotted down at 2 a.m.
That's your unlock. And so the smart
play here is you're using Obsidian as a
structured brain that feeds directly
into your AI agents. That's why it's so
powerful, right? Now, why would you use
it for example to create like your own
sort of personal agent? Here's how I
would do it, right? So, you have your
vault, your AI brain, right? This is
your obsidian vault, the folder where
all your notes live. So, you want to
think of it as the hard drive of your
AI's brain. Without good notes, your AI
has nothing to work with. The more you
put in, the smarter it gets. So, you
start by capturing everything. Ideas,
research, meeting notes, content angles,
customer questions, things you learned.
One note equals one idea. Simple. It's
clean. It's organized. How simple and
easy is it to just add some information
about you, what you do, what you sell,
etc. who you are, your goals, and then
you've also got the connection, right?
And so, literally all you do is whether
you're using Claude code, whether you're
using Claw Codework, whether you're
using Open Claw, etc., right? We've
already got the sales page by the way
created right there. Basically, whatever
you're using right now, you can just
point it at the folder locally. So, it's
so easy to connect. You don't even need
an MCP server or a API token. You don't
need to worry about any of that. You've
got it all living inside your AI agents
locally, right? And then you've got the
retrieval. So now you can ask Claude or
Open Claw about your own notes. Not
questions about the internet, but
questions about your research, your
ideas, your business. For example, what
are the top five topics I've written
about this month? Find every note where
I mentioned customer objections. So
summarize everything that I've captured
about AI agents in the last 90 days. And
it pulls the answers from your vault,
not from Google, not from Wikipedia,
from you. And that's where the gold is,
right? That's the magic of this. And
then this is where it gets really
interesting. So layer number four inside
this framework is that Claude can find
patterns across notes you wrote weeks or
months apart. Right? It can connect
ideas you never realized were related,
right? So you can say, for example,
okay, based on my last 50 notes, what
themes keep showing up? Find gaps in my
research. What content angles have I
captured but never turned into a piece
of content? This is like having a
research analyst who's read everything
you've ever written and can see the
bigger picture because they have and
it's got the analytical brain of AI
which is exactly what you want. And then
finally, you got the output, right? You
want to build real things for this. You
want to actually implement it. So this
is the final layer. You're not just
asking questions anymore. You're asking
Claude to build things from your notes.
For example, draft a blog post based on
my last 10 research notes. Create a
content calendar from the topics I've
been capturing. Write an email sequence
using the customer objections I've
documented. Generate a training document
for my team. Your notes go in, the
finished work comes out. And that is the
engine, my friends. So why is this so
useful? For example,
this basically works 24/7 as an AI
agent. So you could have inside your
Obsidian vault, we've actually got a
30-day road map inside the AI profitable
and video notes, but you could have five
star folders. You could have ideas,
research, content, clients, and systems.
And then you can paste in a prompt
that's personalized to you. You could
also just do, you know, something where
you take obsidian and you create one
note for every idea, a process or piece
of knowledge stuck in your brain, right?
Number one, it helps you get organized
just in terms of journaling day-to-day.
But number two, it really helps the AI
understand who you are, what you do. And
also the other thing here is like you
could store this inside something like
open core but open core breaks and if
you have to reinstall it or it bugs out
or it just accidentally deletes
everything. You've lost it all. It's
very hard to keep this organized. If you
link it directly to obsidian instead, it
instantly has context that you don't
just use inside open core. You share it
across cloud code and everywhere else.
Right? And that's the beauty of this.
That's how it works so well. So that's
basically it for how to use it, how to
get access to it. It's completely free
and you can link it to open claw and
it's super easy to use. All right, it's
not a technical way to use this. It's
super easy. Some people say my notes are
too messy and disorganized for AI to
use. The good news is AI doesn't care
about the messy stuff, right? It reads
everything and finds the patterns for
you. You can have something that's
really messy and that vault just gets
organized over time because the AI helps
you see what's connected, right? You can
start messy if you want to and just let
the AI clean it up. Your notes are just
raw material, right? The AI does the
organizing. Your job is just to capture
and give it context.
So that's basically it. And then also
some people say, I've tried note
takingaking apps before and always stop
using them. That's because those apps
never gave you anything back, right?
You'd put notes in there and they just
sit there collecting dust. Obsidian and
Claude and Open Core is different
because your notes start working for
you, right? They write your emails. They
draft your content. They answer your
business questions. So, when your notes
save you two hours a day, you don't stop
using them. You use them more and more,
right? And so, if you've used
note-taking apps before and stopped, you
know, it's not cuz you're lazy, it's
because the old apps never gave you a
reason to keep going, right? This one
does. That's what this game is about.
So, if you want to get 100 prompts, a
30-day road map for using Obsidian, the
full framework for using this, and all
my best trainings of Clawude and Open
Claw and the new daily updates that come
out every single day, I show you how to
do all of it inside the AI profit
boardroom link in the comments in
description or you can go to the
aprofit.com. We have all my best
trainings inside here, an amazing
community of great people that you can
ask questions to 24/7. Inside the
calendar, we have all of my best
automation calls. You can meet people in
your local area from the map and then
inside the classroom you get access to
all my best trainings. So you can go
from beginner to expert with AI
automation and learn how to build your
first AI agent in under five minutes.
You can get my best business playbooks
on how to automate Twitter and the AI
avatar videos and Instagram and shorts.
If you want to see my new daily updates
and the notes from today, check out the
SAP update section. If you want to learn
how to get more clients, check out the
agency course. If you want to watch
about the coaching course, watch them
here. If you want to learn how to rank
them more inside Google and AI search
engines, check this out. And also, if
you want to learn how to grow a YouTube
channel or you can check it out right
there, right? So, thanks so much for
watching. Appreciate as always and I
will see you on the next one. Feel free
to check this out. Link in the comments
description. Let's see what questions
we've got, my friends. Purpose says,
"How can I reach out to you in person?
Come join the AR profit boardroom."
That's where I personally connect with
people. Hello builder says, "This is
valuable." Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you, Julian, for the amazing
share. Happy to help. Does Nema claw
offer similar to Claude co-work? No,
it's very different. So Nema Claw is
literally just open claw but in a more
secure environment. Like that's the
difference. Dave says the way the
project panel instructions and cord
hooks snap together is oddly satisfying.
Thanks for being on the public. Thank
you very much, sir, for watching. And
yeah, I would agree like it's very
satisfying using it. It's an amazing
tool. So, thanks very much for watching.
I will see everyone on the next one.
Cheers.