Claw just changed how we use the
internet forever. And it's all because
of this new skill it got called
firecrol. And you see browsers were
originally built for people. So every
login screen, capture, or are you a
robot checkbox was initially designed
assuming a person was on the other side.
So when an AI agent tried to use the
web, it was fighting a system that it
was never built for. And this new
firecall skill changes that. It makes
the web agentic, meaning Claude can now
log in and stay logged in into your
accounts, access apps and dashboards it
could not touch before and run dozens of
browsers in parallel. So everything it
does on the web is finally fast,
reliable, and actually works. I've been
actually using this for the past few
weeks, and it's literally changed how I
work. So in this video, I'm going to
break it down in three levels so you can
do the same. First, we're going to get
set up. We're going to install
Firecrawl, connect it to Claude, and
I'll show you what it can do. Then we're
going to give Claw the ability to log
into your apps and access sites that
blocks every other tool. And level
three, we're going to give Claude the
ability to run multiple browsers in
parallel so that everything it does on
the web is fast, reliable, and most
importantly actually remembers what
you're working on and keeps that context
of what you're trying to accomplish over
time. And even if you have zero
technical background, you'll be able to
do this because all we're doing is
simply speaking to Claude. Let's get
into it.
Okay, before we set anything up, let me
quickly explain why what we're doing is
so important. Cuz right now, if you
wanted to give Claude browser access,
you'd basically be handing it the keys
to your actual browser, the one you use
every day. So, your Gmail, your banking,
your passwords, everything. And sure,
Claude has good intentions. But do you
really want an AI agent roaming freely
through your personal browser with
access to everything on your machine?
One wrong move. And it's potentially
touching stuff you'd never want it near.
So, we're going to be using Firecrawl to
solve this by giving Claude its own
dedicated browser completely separate
from yours. So, Claude gets a sandboxed
environment that's isolated, private,
and controlled. And my personal favorite
part about this is that this cloud
browser stays logged in. So, once Claude
authenticates to a service you need,
that session is saved and persisted. So,
next time you need it, Firecrawl lets it
remember. So, you can control whatever
access you give Claude. That's the
difference between giving your AI agent
your card versus giving it its own cars.
And that's how we should stay safe and
use tech like this
to set it up. First things first, we
want to make sure we have claude desktop
enabled. Okay, cloud desktop download.
I'm just going to Google that really
quick. And then scroll down and then you
want to install
one of the cloud desktop for Mac or
Windows. Okay, and then you want to open
up Cloud. So here I have Cloud up and
now I'm going to show you the next step.
So next what we want to do is head over
to firecrawl.dev dev and it's also in
the link in the description if you just
want to follow that. So I'm going to
Google firecrawl.dev
and right here you just want to log in
here dashboard and you see you have a
couple different things and notice how
there's this new browser that's
available and to give you a quick peak
of what is inside. If I click browser
uh you see I already have two agents
that are working for me doing stuff in
their own browsers and I'm going to show
you how to set that up. So your agents
have their own browser, their own login,
all of that. Okay. So what you want to
do is first you want to go back to
overview and then what we want to do is
notice this API key. We want to use that
API key and this data over here. So
we're going to need to give Claude
access to the stuff by copying and
pasting it to do the setup. Okay. So let
me show you how to do that. Okay. To do
that, what we're going to do is we're
going to go back to Claude and then
we're going to hit this plus button
right here and we're going to hit
connectors. And what a connector is is
basically we're giving our cloud access
to use firecrawl, right? So we're going
to hit manage connectors. So what you do
is you go here, you hit this plus, you
hit add custom connector and then you
let's name this firecrawl
and then you paste this in and this will
be in the link in the description or the
guide if you want, but it's just
https/mcp.firecrawl.dev
and then your API key where you just
take it from here and then you paste it
here. Okay, so I just pasted mine and
then I'm going to hit add. Okay, so
after you add it, you should see there
should be a fire crawl right here. And
if you hit that fire crawl, you can see
it's going to ask need approval. So I'm
just going to hit always allow. And now
I don't have to keep pressing go. It's
actually going to do it for me. Okay,
great. So now we have our connectors
enabled. Now what we want to do is go
back to our chat. So let me just do
that.
So now right here, if you hit plus and
you can see if you go to connectors,
you'll have this fire crawl enabled.
Make sure you check this. And now we're
ready to use our firecrawl. Okay, so
that's level one. Now, let's go to level
two. And I'm going to be showing you
what you're going to be building now
that you have firecrawl set up.
But first, I need to explain how Claude
plus firecrawl actually works. Because
once you get this, everything else is
going to click. So, think about a really
talented new employee. First day on the
job, you sit them down, walk them
through everything, and they're sharp,
so they do a great job. But they go home
and come back the next day and remember
absolutely nothing. not because they're
bad at their job, but because every
single day they wake up with a blank new
complete memory. And that's Claude. It's
incredibly capable within a session. But
the moment you close it, the context is
gone and you're starting from scratch.
Furthermore, because browsers were
designed for people, which means it's
going to run into issues like hitting
buttons, solving captures, doing the are
you a robot checks, all of them were
built with a person in mind, and that
fills up Claude's context, and it starts
degrading over time. So when an AI agent
tries to browse the web the same way you
do, it keeps constantly hitting walls.
You can do this, but it's slow and
unreliable. Why we're using a fire crawl
is because firecrawl flips [snorts] this
whole thing on its head. It makes the
whole web agentic. Meaning instead of
claw trying to fight through a human
first interface, it's going to get a
clean structured access to the data
directly, which means the reliability
goes up and the speed goes up and the
amount of failures you have drops
dramatically, which means you have to
use less tokens and everything is way
more efficient. So, let me show you how
I've been using this so you have a clear
use case in mind. All right, so the
first thing I'm going to be showing you
how to build is this thing. You see how
there's like a little cat right here?
And this cat is responsible to make
daily posts in my school community and
also help out members with if they have
Claude type questions. So, for example,
it's doing a bunch of stuff like right
here, I made a little trading bot with
Claude and uh you can see right here,
it's also interacting with members.
It's uh helping them out with questions
like look, this guy loves it. [snorts]
And it's also like, you know, explaining
how this stuff is happening as an
assistant. that's also technical because
it has all that brain behind it and you
can see how it's talking about the
skills and heartbeat, MD, etc. So, it's
a pretty cool agentic assistant in my
school community that I'll show you how
to build right now. All right, so to do
our build, what we're going to be using
is Claude Co-work. So, I'm going to hit
co-work right here. And right here, I'm
going to make a new folder. So, right
here, let me just call this fire crawl.
Um, I'm going to open it always allow.
Great. And I'm going to check if this
has access to the connector. Cool. Right
here. Okay. Now I want to be like, "Hey,
can you use Firecrawl to spin up a
persistent browser?" And in that
persistent browser, I would like you to
go to school.com and log in with this
credentials. Make sure you don't forget
and you're always logged in. So, we're
going to be running a lot of tasks there
later. Okay,
great. Now, I'm just going to give it my
school username and password. So,
username. And again, this is for a bot
that you just make on your own. So you
can give it the email. I'm going to hide
this for now. And password.
And I'm going to hide this one, too. And
then you just hit go. Okay. So I'm going
to fill in my username and password for
my bot in school. And then I'm going to
hit go. Okay, great. So now it's saying
login was done. And this is really cool.
Let me show you. If I go back to
firecraw and if I go to browser
and you see this is kind of cool that it
I can see it uh being active and logged
into school.
Normally you can't do this with co-work
but now I have a persistent login. Now I
can get my bot to be doing stuff. So for
example, now I can go back and I can be
like, "Hey, every morning can you make a
schedule task to do research on uh
Reddit or something?" and then see
what's the new trending topic that's
brewing in Claude or make some
actionable user insight and then make a
post with that so we can help users
and then also if you see someone
struggling or asking a question make
sure to set up a schedule task so every
day at one time you can answer these
questions.
So, this is really cool. And notice how
I said schedule task because what we're
going to be doing is we're going to be
taking advantage of Cloud Co-work's
schedule tasks. Okay, so you see right
here, Cloud Co-Work has the ability to
do schedule tasks. So, if I hit the
schedule, you can see normally Cloud
Co-Work won't have access to a browser.
So, what Firecrol lets it do is have its
own persistent login and background on
its own. And it's going to be creating
these things and creating these
scheduled tasks. So, I don't have to
touch everything. And we already made an
agentic assistant inside our school.
Okay, let me hit schedule. And you see
every morning it's going to do this. If
I go back to my scheduled and you see
right here, see that's pretty cool,
right? And I can run it now if I would
like to. Let's actually do that and test
it out. Okay, great. So, it's done doing
the scheduled tasks. So, it says every
day at 9:05 is going to make these
morning insights and 12 it's going to,
you know, respond to any questions or
anything like that. And if we go back to
the scheduled task, you can see these
are already up. And I can see that it's
built a skill. It's running a new little
thing. And I want to see this happen.
And if I go into that, I can see that,
hey, there's an existing school post.
It's crafting an insight. It's loading
these tools to the browser, and it's
going to actually make this post. This
is pretty interesting. So, I just went
back uh right here uh just to see and
it's actually like typing it in which is
um pretty interesting to see. So, now in
my browser sessions, I can actually see
my agents working live. And the nice
part about what we're doing here with
Firecrawl is you can spin up multiple
sessions. So, you can work on many
different things each with its own login
actually doing the stuff in real time.
Okay, cool. So, it actually just made
its first post and we can see right here
we can say, "Hey, uh, it researched
because this literally happened like
today that the claude gave us 1 million
context window for everyone for free or
with the max plan. You can see it just
posted right here. If I go to my actual
account in school, I can see uh, one
load one new post and there we go.
Awesome. All right. So, we have our
Aentic Assistant now. It's going to be
looking out. It's going to be responding
to other people over time. And you can
set it in any schedule you'd like.
Great. Now that we've built this, now
let's take it a next step further.
All right, so level three, I'm going to
show you this with a real use case I've
actually been using a lot. So I run this
company called Booked AI. We build voice
agents that qualify leads for a lot of
businesses. And one of the best fits we
found is real estate wholesalers. These
wholesalers tend to run a lot of ads and
then they get flooded with a lot of
inbound leads. And those voice agents
whenever they fill that form, they call
those leads, they qualify them before
anyone has to pick up the phone, then
set an appointment with people that are
qualified. and the results have been
really strong. So, naturally, I wanted
to find more real estate wholesalers who
are actively running ads and show them
what kind of results we're getting for
them. The problem is that finding them
in the US is a nightmare. You'd have to
manually dig through Google or Facebook
ads or websites one by one. And that's
exactly the kind of problems Parallel
Agents was built for. So, here's what
we're going to do. We're going to get
Claude to help us find a lot of
qualified real estate wholesalers in the
US who are actively running ads and grab
their company name, their website, what
market they're in, and their contact
information. And then once I have the
list, I'm going to get Claude to draft a
personalized outreach message for each
one based on what it found. So watch
this. Okay, so I'm back on Claude. I
just opened up a new tab. And now I'm
just going to be speaking to it. So hey,
um, I need you to find me real estate
wholesalers across the US who are
actively running ads. Use Firecrawl to
search 10 major markets in parallel.
Maybe Atlanta, Dallas, Phoenix, Houston,
Tampa, Charlotte, uh, and a couple more.
Find each one. Scrape their website.
Grab their company name, their website,
their market, phone number, and email.
Then I want you to draft a personalized
outreach message for each one. Here's
the context you need. We are Booked in
AI. We build AI voice agents that
instantly call and qualify inbound leads
for real estate wholesalers. The agent
will call every lead within 60 seconds,
ask qualifying questions, and only
passes the warm leads to your human
closer when they're qualified. So
wholesalers running paid ads are
probably our best fit and are always
losing deals on the time their closers
are spending qualifying these people and
you know we've seen strong results in
the space. So for each message mention
their specific market reference to the
fact that they're running ads and
explain where that speed to lead system
is one of the biggest factors. Maybe
tease what our voice agents do as well.
I think I have uh some demos on my
website. Keep it short conversational
not salesy and maybe a soft ask with a
quick quick call. give me a table first.
Um, the company, website, the market,
the phone, email, then outreach messages
to match inside the table.
So, I just word dumped whatever was on
my mind. And right now, since I already
have access to it, I'm just going to hit
go and then watch it work. Okay, so
right here you can see Firecrawl is
really quickly searching for these
people and it's getting structured data
really fast without me having to burn a
lot of tokens doing one by one by one.
It's everything is happening in
parallel. And look how fast it is. It's
kind of cool.
All right. Awesome. So, it looks like
it's done. So, it got me a couple
contact data. And this is pretty cool.
And you see it's drafted me the messages
as well. [snorts]
Okay. Now, I can just connect this to my
cold email service and then make this go
out as well. But this is one cool way
where all I would have to do is just use
firecrawl to spin up these instances and
it's doing all the verifying, all the
scraping, whatnot. And it makes my life
a lot easier where I can just chill and
it's doing the stuff. You see, this is
all cool, but it's all useless if you
don't use these abilities properly and
manage it with the right skills. So,
watch this video next to learn about how
I get Clawed Asian Teams to do my
bidding on its