As an engineer, I've been using
different forms of generative AI for
years now. I could think of first it
was, you know, a coding assistant in my
IDE back in maybe 2022. And then, of
course, that progressed to us getting
those early versions of GPT back in
2023. And then we were adding our data,
right? We were doing techniques such as
rag or retrieval augmented generation to
pull in our PDFs and other data sources.
And that led us to of course other types
of APIs and services with agents and MCP
back in 2025. And who knows what's going
to happen in 2026 and the years after.
The thing is, as I've been using all of
these different AI models and AI
services, all of this has been through
public APIs and I've been both sending
my data but also sending my money to
thirdparty APIs in order to use their
models. And now as organizations are
looking to deploy their own private and
sovereign AI solutions to power all of
these applications like rag and agentic
AI well how can they be sure that
they're keeping firstly their cost down
when they're deploying their own AI but
also ensuring that they have that data
privacy and sovereignty while also
having governance and being able to
scale this up to not only just a couple
engineers but an entire team of
developers and at the end of the day end
users.
Well, you probably know what's going to
be the answer. It's a technique that's
known as models as a service. So, just
as we've had, you know, software as a
service back in the day to provide us
Gmail and storage and a lot of other
utilities that we use every day, well,
models as a service is kind of this new
pattern that's emerging that's allowing
us to serve multiple models, whether
it's vision or language models through
one singular API. an API that's
providing us transparency behind the
billing and cost of our GPU utilization,
the data privacy and and sensitivity of
our data and governance, but also
observability all through this API
gateway, right? Um, but we're also able
to then share this to variety of
different users and developers who will
then be consuming the model. So the IT
team here or platform engineers are
serving these models and then the end
developers or users here are the final
consumers of these artifacts. And this
my friends is what we call models as a
service. And I'm really excited to show
you how this works behind the scenes and
why models as a service is becoming a de
facto standard for how organizations can
scale and deploy models where they work.
In fact, I bet that you've already used
models as a service in your own work.
So, I want you to think about the AI
giants, right? So, they're not actually
giving you access to these huge data
centers that they have, right? They're
giving you access to individual models,
but they're doing so in a way that's
actually quite similar to models as a
service. So, think about these different
versions of models that you can access,
right? You're not accessing them
directly. you're going through some type
of app or API for example uh just as we
have the API gateway that we just
mentioned earlier so that you can then
you know uh ensure that you've got
billing or authentication or or
something like that that you need as a
prerequisite to then access for example
the app or the API. So our devs here can
now use that API of the model to build
out really cool applications maybe rag
or agentic AI apps and then the users
down here are you know our happy little
users that are consuming the AI
application and so this is exactly what
models as a service is and it's already
being used today but the only difference
that we're talking about is that instead
of renting thirdparty services and
servers or paying for tokens you're able
to run your own models as a service to
maintain control over cost, the access
of the models, and the maintenance of
the models. And let me tell you that
maintenance part is super important
because for example, each time a new
Frontier model is released, let's say a
version seven or something of this
model, the older versions are typically
depreciated and sometimes it's with or
without notice. So let's say for
example, we get rid of that V5. And this
means as a developer if your application
is already or currently using that
model, you're now forced to upgrade to a
newer version of the model. But what
happens if the prompt template for
example for version five is different
than that of the version six model?
Well, as we know, the model behavior
might change and those bugs are then
going to impact the developer down here,
which then he has to spend time or they
have to spend time fixing their
application for the users to consume at
the end of the day. So, it kind of
creates this downstream effect. And so,
with models as a service, you're able to
have full control over the models that
you're releasing and the maintenance on
how they are released in the life cycle.
So if you want to go to hugging face and
search for a new model, you can then add
that here to your models as a service
infrastructure with your IT team and be
able to manage what's currently being
used most by your teams and maybe
depreciate of what you don't need
anymore. Now I want you to think about
environments that are sensitive. So for
example when we typically think of data
sensitive environments it's something
like healthcare or say financial
services where you have a lot of
personally identifying information or
PII and the data that is within these
organizations need to be handled with uh
a lot of scrutiny because one it's you
know customer data but secondly there's
a lot of government regulations and
practices around the handling of that
data. So, it's not easy to just, you
know, go connect to some type of, you
know, third-party LLM with that data,
right? Because when we're going to a
third party LM, what we're sending maybe
what might not be sensitive data, but
there could be risk of a data break or
leakage. And so, all of this information
is typically kept on premise. And it's
not just the database, right? It's also
the applications that are being used. It
might also be the for example hardware
so GPUs and CPUs. All of this can
typically run on prem or maybe in a
mixed hybrid cloud environment where
it's onrem but also in the cloud and
other data sources. But the cool part
about models as a service is you become
your own private AI provider. So in
addition to the applications and the
databases, we can also run these local
large language models alongside of our
applications so that we have this fully
airgapped and disconnected environment
so that we can deliver these secure uh
LLMs but without having to uh depend on
a public cloud provider but we still get
the benefits of rag or retrieve
augmented generation for private
documentation with AI or aentic AI that
can call our different services and it's
all within in this disconnected
environment. So how does this look in
action? Well, let's architect it out
starting with the base layer of
infrastructure and orchestration using a
technology like Open Shift or
Kubernetes. So these are the open-source
technologies that allow us to bring
together a variety of different
environments such as on prem for example
or cloud providers or say for example
edge if we're running our workloads and
AI out there as well. So we can bring
together for example GPUs all in one
place to be able to dynamically scale
them when needed. Now let's also talk
about our AI platform layer. So the AI
platform layer is really important in
this situation because vanilla
Kubernetes by itself can use additional
capabilities such as inference engines
with VLLM or other projects such as
KSERve that allow us to uh orchestrate
individual LLMs just like microservices.
And this gives us a lot of flexibility
when we're running AI workloads. And at
this point, yes, technically we can run
a model, but to expose the endpoints for
our organization and teams to use in a
standardized way. Well, this involves
some type of API uh gateway. So the API
gateway here is the way for us to add
these additional enterprise
capabilities. So for example, rate
limiting or maybe authentication for our
users or the ability to do usage
tracking and much much more and have
observability throughout this entire
process, right? Because it's not just
the kind of infrastructure itself but
the observability for uh telemetry for
example or logging or for example with
AI applications we need to understand
why did they make the decision they
made. So this could be the traces of how
the LM is going to an MCP server to call
a database and get that information
back. So all of this additional
information is really important to have.
But because of the open- source projects
like Prometheus and Graphfana and Jerger
and many more that we're pretty familiar
with for traditional applications uh
using open source technologies as well.
Well, we're able to apply this to our AI
applications and be able to get a more,
you know, behindthe-scenes look when it
comes to building AI apps. And with this
centralized AI infrastructure, instead
of having to work from a single model
that we've maybe deployed from our IT
team to a single team or user and have
to do that multiple times and spread
that across, well, we're able to
individually uh call LLMs that are all
managed by this, you know, models as a
service infrastructure up here to be
able to support various teams from our
organization as they independently
scale up their AI efforts, but also make
sure that we have cost control in
effect. We've got data privacy and full
control over our AI adoption so that we
can scale things up when we're using AI.
So, models as a service, it's just one
of the many approaches that you can use,
but it's quickly becoming the standard
for in-house and sovereign AI
infrastructure. Now, if you learned
something today, please be sure to like
the video and hack the algorithm and
stay subscribed for more content on AI
and open-source technology. We'll see
you.