Claude's new AI auto mode runs itself.
Now, that's not a headline I'm using to
just get clicks. That literally just
happened. Anthropic dropped auto mode
for Claude Code today. It hit 2.4
million views on X within hours. Not
because of hype, because people looked
at it and thought, "Wait, is this
actually real?" And it is. Here's what
changed. Before today, Claude Code
stopped and asked you to approve almost
everything. Every file it wrote, every
command it run, every single action.
You'd sit there clicking yes, yes, yes
over and over, like hiring a brilliant
assistant and then making them ask
permission every time they touched a
pen. What did people do? Well, they
turned off the safety system entirely.
There's a flag called dangerously skip
permissions, and almost everyone was
using it. One developer posted about it
on X and got about 2,000 likes in hours.
Not controversial, just everyone in the
reply saying, "Yeah, same." One reply
said, "Dangerously skip permissions is
how I run my life." Another reply
compared it to $8 and paying $8 for a
coffee and then being asked to approve
every sip. So, Anthropic had a real
problem. The safety system was so
disruptive that everyone just turned it
off. And that's not safety, that's
theater. And it wasn't a small number of
people doing it quietly. It was the
standard workflow. The dangerous option
became the normal option because the
alternative approving every single micro
action was killing productivity. Auto
mode is their answer to it. And here's
where it gets interesting because what
they built is not just we made the
pop-ups less annoying. Instead of
approving every file right and bash
command or skipping permissions
entirely, auto mode lets Claude make
permission decisions on your behalf. But
the key detail, the thing that makes
this different from just turning off
safety is how the decision gets made.
Before each tool, a classifier reviews
it for potentially destructive actions.
Safe actions proceed automatically.
risky ones get blocked and Claude will
take a different approach. That
classifier is a separate AI model, not
Claude judging itself, a completely
different model, watching every action
before it happens. Think about what that
actually means in practice. You give
Claude a task, it starts working. Every
time it tries to do something, move a
file, run a command, write to a folder,
a second AI checks it first. You're not
in that loop. The two AIs are handling
it between themselves. And here's the
small part. Claude's reasoning text and
tool results are stripped before
reaching the classifier. Meaning, if
there's a hostile instruction hidden
inside a file Claude opens or buried in
a code comment somewhere deep in a
project, the classifier never sees it.
The watcher only sees what you
originally asked for and what Claude is
about to do, nothing else. That's a real
architectural decision, not marketing.
Actual prompt injection defense built
into the structure of how the two models
talk to each other. The classifier is
specifically looking for three threat
patterns. Number one, is Claude doing
more than you asked? Second, is it about
to touch something it shouldn't? And
third, is it suddenly behaving
differently like it got steered by
something it read along the way? That
third one is important because prompt
injection where malicious instructions
get embedded in content the AI reads is
one of the biggest active security
concerns in autonomous AI systems right
now. Anthropic built a specific defense
against it directly into auto modes
architecture. Now out of the box what
does it actually block? The default
block list covers for example force
pushes, data exfiltration attempts,
curl, pipe, bash patterns. That's where
someone hides a script in a URL and
Claude runs it blind. Production deploys
a mass file deletion. All blocked by
default. No setup needed. The classifier
only trusts your working directory and
the current repos configured remotes.
Everything outside that gets
scrutinized. If Claude hits a block
three times in a row or 20 total times
in a session, auto mode actually pauses
completely and reverts to asking you
manually for each action. That's a hard
fail safe. If something keeps pushing
against the limits, the whole system
stops and it puts you back in control.
Teams can customize it through an auto
mode settings block with three sections.
Environment covers trusted
infrastructure. Allow covers permitted
actions written in plain alkaline and
soft deny covers what gets blocked also
in plain language. The classifier reads
your pros instructions and reads about
them, right? It reasons about them. It's
not just pattern matching on command
names. And here's a security detail that
matters. The classifier does not read
from shared project settings in the
clawed settings.json.
So, a file sitting in a shared or public
repo cannot inject its own permission
rules. That's a real attack vector being
closed. Someone can't just check in a
config file that grants themselves
elevated access. Three CLI inspection
commands let you see exactly what the
classifier is working with. So, Claude
auto mode defaults to see the built-in
rules. Claude auto mode config to review
your custom setup and claude auto mode
critique to validate it. So how do you
actually turn it on? Well, if you go
into claude and you type in dash
enable-to-
mode in the terminal first and then
cycle to it with shift plus tab during a
session that rotates through the
permission modes in order. You've got
normal, auto, accept edits, plan mode
and auto mode. You can also use this in
the virtual studio extension and desktop
app as well, right? Sorry, visual code
extension. You toggle you toggle auto
mode on its settings first, then select
it from the permission mode dropdown. On
the desktop app specifically, auto mode
is disabled by default and requires
explicit activation through organization
settings. Now, if you want to use it,
it's live right now as a research
preview on the team plan. Enterprise and
API access are rolling out in the coming
months. It runs on Claude Sonic 4.6 and
Opus 4.6 only, so you can't use it with
other models. And enterprise admins also
get full control. Auto mode can be
disabled organizationwide, too, if
you've got a team. And you can do that
through MDM managed preferences on Mac
OS Windows registry policies or a
crossplatform managed settings.json
file. So if you're running a team and
want to lock it down or customize it
centrally that's fully supported. Now I
want to zoom out at this point because
the permission problem auto mode solves
is actually a symptom of something much
bigger. The real shift happening right
now is that AI is moving from answering
questions to running tasks and not just
for like a quick task. This is for hours
unsupervised. You could for example give
it a go. It works. You check the result.
That transition from chatbot to
autonomous agent is what makes the
permission model matter so much. When AI
just answers questions, you are always
in the loop. But when AI is for example
running 200 actions to complete a
project, you can't be in the loop for
each one. The old model breaks down
completely. Auto mode is built for the
new one. And we can see that shift in
the numbers. A survey of 500 developers
actually found that Claude Code won 67%
of blind quality tests against
competitors. But the constant
interruptions and permission friction
were the number one complaint stopping
people from using it for longer
sustained work. One highly upvoted
comment captured it exactly. Burning
through most of your session just
getting through a single complex prompt.
The quality was there but the workflow
wasn't. And auto mode fixes the workflow
problems with Claude. This is also
happening inside a very specific
competitive moment. Anthropic is not
shipping auto mode in isolation. This
March alone, Claude Code reviews, a 1
million token context window expansion,
dispatch for co-work, and a separate
research preview of Claude operating a
full [snorts] Mac desktop autonomously.
Each one of those extends how long and
how independently Claude can work before
checking in with you. The pattern is
clear. Every single release, the window
of unsupervised work gets longer. Every
single release, the human is further
from the action. But here's what I
really want to get into because this is
not just a developer story, and it has
never been a developer story really.
Right now today, non-technical people
are using claude code to build real
things for their businesses, agencies,
freelancers, e-commerce owners, content
creators, and the permission system was
the biggest blocker for them
specifically because when you're not
technical, you can't evaluate whether a
given terminal command is safe or
dangerous. You might see a bash prompt
appear and freeze. Do I click yes? Is
this going to delete something? There's
no way to know if you don't have the
background. Auto mode removes that wall
completely. The classifier handles the
judgment. You don't have to understand
what a bash command is or does to know
it's been reviewed and cleared. Writer
and researcher Dan Shipper ran Claude
Code Comp, which attracted around 400
subscribers. They built expense
trackers, analyzed data sets, generated
marketing pipelines, and most of them
were not technical at all. Eleanor
Burger published a full guide called
Claude Code for non-coders. Her entire
thesis was that you don't write a single
line of code yourself. Claude does it.
You just describe what you want. She
runs weekly sessions for nontechnical
users and the demand has been
consistent. One analysis put the agency
impact in direct numbers. Agencies
typically charge between $2,000 and
$15,000 to build a portfolio site. Now
with core code you can have a fully
functional version in under 45 minutes.
That's not a hyperetical future. That's
what agencies are reporting right now.
Freelancers on platforms like create
with have already started positioning
themselves specifically as claude code
experts building things for business
owners who want the output but don't
want to operate the tool themselves. And
that's an entire new service category
that didn't exist 12 months ago. So what
does auto mode do for all of these
people? What removes the last major
friction point? Long autonomous tasks,
building a site, for example, migrating
data, running a content pipeline, now
run without you watching every step and
approving every action. You describe
what you want. You come back when it's
done. The classifier runs quietly in the
background the whole time. If you want
to actually learn how to use this for
your business, not just understand it,
but build real workflows with it, the AI
profit boardroom is where that's
happening. 2,600
business owners already inside. Four
live coaching calls every single week.
Daily tutorials with step-by-step
videos. 30-day road maps so you know
exactly what to do and in what order.
Prompts for everything you can imagine,
a local map so you can find and connect
with people near you building the same
things. and 247 support because the
community is global so someone is always
online. If Claude auto mode is relevant
to your business and it is that's where
you actually go deep on it. Link in the
comments description or go to the
apiprofitb.com.
Now is auto mode perfect? No. And I want
to be completely straight with you about
that. Security researchers at Lasso
documented real prompt injection
vulnerabilities in Claude code. Hostile
instructions buried in readme code
comments and dependency files could
hijack Claude's behavior during a
session. A researcher by Gual in 2026
tested 314 attack payloads embedded
across those same services and recorded
an 84% success rate at redirecting
Claude's actions. That's not a
theoretical concern. That's a measured
result. Checkpoint disclosed two real
CVEes in Claude code last year. Both
were patched, but the fact they existed
matters. This is a product running code
on your machine with elevated
permissions and it has documented
vulnerabilities.
There was also a real event, a real
incident where claw code deleted an
entire user's home directory. Real user,
real data gone. That made it to hacker
news. That kind of story is exactly why
the permission debate matters in the
first place. And security firm Griff.ai
made the deeper architectural argument.
The auto mode still asks the agent
ecosystem to approve its own actions.
The judge and the defendant are in the
same process even with a separate
classifier model. Techrunch noted that
Anthropic hasn't published the specific
criteria the classifier uses to decide
what's safe and what isn't, which
matters if you're trying to understand
what it will and what it won't catch in
production. and Anthropic themselves
right at the top of their own
documentation recommend running auto
mode in isolated environments sandboxed
setups feature branches with protected
mains scoped read only tokens
credentials kept out of the workspace
that's not a footnote that is the
official guidance so the honest summary
is that auto mode is structurally better
than turning off permissions entirely
the separate classifier is real The
prompt injection defense is real. The
fail safes are real. But reduced risk
and eliminated risk are not the same
thing. The research previewed label is
there for a reason. This is going to
keep changing. But here's what hasn't
changed. The old system wasn't working.
People bypassed it universally. Auto
mode is better and it will keep getting
better. Let's talk about the business
context this is landing in because it
matters. Anthropic's annualized revenue
has reached approximately $20 billion.
Their valuation hit $380 billion
following a $30 billion funding round in
February 2026. And Quarter Code alone
has exceeded $2.5 billion in annualized
revenue. So, Auto mode isn't a side
experiment or a nice to have feature.
It's central to where their biggest,
fastest growing product is heading. And
the competitive pressure is real too.
OpenAI's codeex is the main alternative
developers are benchmarked against. In
those 500 plus developer surveys, Claude
Code wins on output quality
consistently, but OpenAI has been
pushing hard on workflow and agent
autonomy features of its own. Auto mode
is anthropic saying we're not going to
lose on workflow anymore. The million
token context window that's also shipped
this month is part of the same story
because bigger context means claude can
hold an entire large codebase a full
project history every relevant file in
one session. Auto mode means it can work
through that context autonomously
without stopping every few minutes. And
those two features together what make
truly long complex unsupervised tasks
possible for the first time. So, here's
what I want you to take away from all of
this. The gap between what AI can do and
what most people are actually using it
for gets wider every single week. Not
because the tools are too hard, but
because most people aren't paying
attention closely enough. A second AI is
now watching the first AI work.
Autonomous tasks run for hours without
supervision. Agencies build full client
deliverables in 45 minutes. Non-coders
ship working tools. The permission wall
just came down. That is the world today,
March 2026.
The people building real fluency with
these tools right now, learning the
right instructions, setting up the right
environments, running the right
workflows, well, they're going to look
very different from everyone else in 12
months. And not because they're smarter,
but because they started earlier. And
that's the whole game right now. If you
want to be in that group, the AI profit
boardroom is where you do it. 2,600
members, four live calls a week, daily
tutorials, 30-day road maps, real
workflows, real results. Thanks for
watching. You can check it out, link in
the comments description, and I hope to
see you inside there. Thanks for
watching.