There's this GitHub repo we need to talk
about with over 2100 stars in just one
week. This repo replaces your entire dev
team in just seconds. We're going to be
talking about it and how we can use it
and implement it in our open claw setups
to help buy back some of your time and
hit the ground running if you're just
getting going with AI agents. So, like I
said, this thing just hit 2100 stars in
a week and there's a good reason for it.
You know, if you've been using Codex at
all or Claude code and or open claw, you
know, this is very powerful. You know,
you open it up, you give it a task, it
writes code, it does it in a sandbox
environment, and then that's great. But,
the thing that most people don't realize
and most people are using Codex
basically like a single generalist, same
thing with Claude code. You can say
like, "Hey, you know, build me a back
end or you know, review this code, fix
my CES, things like that, right?" And it
does it, gets the job done. But, you're
basically asking one person to be a
doctor and a lawyer and a plumber and a
chef all at the same time. They can do
all of those things, but wouldn't you
rather have a specialist? That's where
these AI agents are pretty much drag and
drop. 136 of them to be exact. I have
the repo linked down below. You got to
check it out. So, this is exactly what
the repo gives you. Basically, 136
specialists. I know that sounds
overwhelming, but I want to break down
the key ones in this repo. So, you got
sub agents. Basically, each one is
designed to do one specific type of
development task very, very well. What
exactly is a sub agent because there's a
lot of confusion around this whole AI
agent space. If you're not familiar,
Codex has this feature where you can
create a custom agent that live in a
specific directory on your machine. You
put in a little tunnel file config and
basically your global agents folder,
your project agents folder, and now
Codex can call on that specialist
whenever it needs to. So, you can think
of it like building a team, basically.
Your front end developer, your security
auditor, your API designer, basically a
database expert, things like that,
right? Each one has their own
instructions, you know, their own model
preferences, their own sandbox
permissions. But, this is what Vault
agent built. 136 categorized sub agents
into 10 categories. I'm going to walk
you through some of them because this is
where it gets more interesting is
category one is the core development
team. This is where your bread and
butter is like you have a back end
developer agent, a front end developer
agent, a full stack developer, a mobile
developer, an API designer, and a
GraphQL architect, a microservices
architect, a web socket engineer,
basically a engineer and designer that
focuses on UI as well. So, right there
is like 10 specialists just for building
things. The back end developer knows
about scalable APIs, the server
architecture, the front end developer
specializes in React, Angular. The
mobile developer does cross-platform
work. Each one has deep specific
instructions about how to approach that
type of work. The second category is
more language specialists and this one's
a huge one because if you're working in
a specific language, you want an agent
that actually knows that ecosystem
deeply. So, they have agents specific
for Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Go,
Rust, Java, C#, C++, Ruby, PHP, Swift,
all of them, guys. Flutter, Django,
Angular, Next.js. It They the It's a
little bit overwhelming this what this
repo offers. That's why we're making a
video about it. Real quick, before we
keep going, if you're watching this and
you want to actually build with some of
these tools, not just watch videos about
them, then you're going to want to check
out our community down below, Shipping
School. We have a full Claude code
course, a full open claw course, and
four live bootcamps every single week
where we actually help you get set up
from scratch. Like actually set this
thing up, not just watch a tutorial and
figure it out by yourself. And we also
provide one-on-one coaching, so you can
book a call with me, we can share
screens, and I can help you get Claude
code or open claw running on your
machine. That's it, no fluff. I built
this community because watching
YouTube's only gets you so far. We
launched it just 3 days ago and we have
over 55 members. You need people around
you who are actually building, people
who hold you accountable, and coaches
who can help you when you get stuck.
I'll put the link in the description
down below. Get in now before the price
goes up. Each one is not just a generic
coder that happens to know the language.
Each one has deep framework knowledge
specific to that stack. So, let's say
your Django developer knows Django 4+
patterns. Your Laravel specialist knows
Laravel 10+ conventions. Your Next.js
expert knows app router. That
specificity matters because generic
advice leads to generic code. We've all
been there before when you vibe code a
landing page, it looks like every other
vibe coded landing page in existence.
That's why it's important to have
specialized agents with specialized
skills and knowledge to be able to stand
out and build a unique product. Here is
something that's really smart about what
they did with model routing. Each sub
agent has model field in its config file
that routes it to the right AI model
automatically. So, your security auditor
and your architecture reviewer, you
know, the ones that need deep reasoning,
those run on GPT-54. And that's the
heavy hitter. But, your search
specialist and your docs researcher, and
the ones doing more of the lighter work
like scanning and synthesis, those run
on GPT-53,
Codex Spark, which is much faster and
cheaper. So, you're not burning most of
the expensive model on simple task.
You're running routing intelligent. That
is cost optimization built right into
the agent design. And if you've been
watching my videos, you know I talk
about this all the time. The number one
people mistake they make when getting AI
agents up and running, you know, they
get the most expensive model, which you
should for the coordination agent. You
know, I I run it on Opus 46. But, you
don't need Opus 46 for simple things,
you know, like searching and web
scraping. You're going to blow through
your usage limits in an hour. You know,
and the same principle applies here is
like figure out what models can be
delegated to handle the simpler tasks
that a you know, more more token
efficient LLM can do. You know, they
also thought about this when they built
the repo. You know, they thought about
security, which I always appreciate.
Each sub agent has basically a sandbox
mode setting. Reviewers and auditors are
set to read only. They can only look at
your code, but they can't modify
anything. Developers and engineers that
actually need to write files, those get
workspace right permissions. So, you
have got this nice separation of
concerns where not every agent can touch
everything. That is exactly how you
should be thinking about agent
permissions. So, I'm going to talk about
some of the categories that really stood
out in this huge repo. Category four is
quality and security. You have a code
reviewer, a security auditor, a
performance profiler, a test architect,
an accessibility expert, and a tech debt
analyst. So, if you think about that for
a second, you could have a dedicated
agent whose entire job is to look at
your code base and find tech debt. Or
one that specifically audits security
vulnerabilities. Or one that checks your
app for accessibility compliance. These
are the things that most solo devs and
even small teams just skip because they
don't have the time. Now you have a
specialist for each one sitting in a
tunnel file ready to go. Category five
is the DevOps team and infrastructure.
CI/CD engineer, you know, a Docker
specialist, a cloud architect, monitor,
and all of that. You know, if you're
deploying apps and managing
infrastructure, you basically now have a
team of agents that know exactly how to
handle all of that. And the fact that
they separated this into its own
category tells you how important
infrastructure automation is becoming.
The sixth category is data and AI. So,
the database expert, data pipeline
builder, the machine language the
machine learning engineer, vector
database specialist, analytics dashboard
builder, you know, just the fact that
they have a vector database specialist
tells you where the industry is headed.
Everyone is building with embeddings and
semantic search now, and having an agent
that specializes in that is generally
useful. The machine learning engineer
knows about experiment tracking and
model optimization. The data pipeline
builder understands ETL workflows and
data quality checks. Category seven is
documentation and research. So, you have
a technical writer, an API docs
generator, a search specialist, a change
log manager. These are all tasks that
nobody wants to do, but everyone needs
it to be done. So, having an agent that
specifically writes clean API
documentation or manages your change
log, that saves hours every single week.
I know from building out our mission
control here that documentation is the
thing that I was always putting off.
But, having an agent dedicated to this
will help greatly. Category eight is
specialized domains. So, this is where
it gets more interesting for people
building actual real products. Fintech
engineer, healthcare compliance
specialist, e-commerce developer, real
estate tech developer, game developer.
These agents know domain specific rules
and regulations. So, like your Fintech
agent understands financial compliance
and PCI standards. Let's say your
healthcare agent knows about HIPAA
requirements. Your real estate tech
developer understands MLS integrations.
These are not generic coders now. We're
past that. These are agents with real
domain expertise baked into their
instructions. So, if you're going to be
building one of in one of these
industries, this alone is worth cloning
this repo. Category nine is agent
automation. So, which is where the real
meta is at. You know, you have got an
agent installer, an MCP developer for
building model context protocols, a
workflow orchestrator, and an agent
communication specialist. So, you have
agents that help you build more agents.
That is the pattern we are seeing
everywhere now. The tools are building
tools. The category 10 is utilities, so
you have a Git specialist, a regex
expert, config manager, log analyzer,
migration specialist. These are all
little tasks that eat up your entire day
if you let them, and we're all trying to
optimize to get our time back. I am at
least. So, having a dedicated regex
expert that you can delegate to and
instead of spending 30 minutes on Stack
Overflow trying to figure out the right
pattern, having a migration specialist
that handles database schema changes
cleanly, that's time back in your
pocket. So, how do you actually use all
this? Like, if you're a beginner
watching this, this probably is
overwhelming. I'm only making this video
because AI agents is the hot topic now,
and a lot of people get Open Claw going
or Codex going or Claude Code going, and
they're just working at it out of the
box, default level. Your agents need
domain-specific knowledge. They need
skills to be able to execute tasks and
get good quality output. You know, it's
really dead simple. You go to the link
in the description, you clone the
you clone the repo, you copy the TOML
files, and you put them in the Claude
Code, you put them in the Codex, give
them in the Open Claw. If you're
struggling to keep up with content, what
I'm about to save you about 40 days
worth of work. [music] I built something
called Content Machine. It's 10 AI
agents that run on the Open Claw
orchestration, and they handle
everything. Scripts, thumbnails, X
posts, [music] blogs, outreach, clips,
newsletters, all of it. So, I went from
1,000 subscribers to 4,000 subscribers
on YouTube in 7 days using this exact
system. Every single morning I wake up
and [music] the content's already done.
I spend maybe 15, 20 minutes reviewing
and approving them, and I move on with
my day. It works for any niche, fitness,
[music] finance, real estate, marketing,
whatever you are building, and it is
100% completely customizable to your use
case. So, you get the mission control
dashboard, all of the cron jobs,
everything I've built over the last 40
days helping me gain more and more
people to subscribe and join the
community. So, you plug in your own
thing and it molds it to you, it learns
how you talk and it writes [music] so it
doesn't sound like AI slop. $97 one
time, it's not a subscription. I'll put
the link down below and you'll thank me
later. You know, if you want them
available globally across all your
projects, you put them in your home
directory under .codex/agents.
Likewise, just give the repo to your
Open Claw agent and let them do the
rest. So, if you want them in specific
to one project, you put them in that
project's So, project agents take
priority over global ones if there's a
naming conflict, you know, which is
pretty smart design. Then you just
restart your session and you can start
delegating
to them explicitly, you know, in your
prompts. One thing to note is that Codex
does not auto-spawn custom sub-agents,
so you have to tell it which specialist
to use. So, you would say something
like, use the security auditor to review
or pull or use the do this pull request
or delegate this database migration to
the database expert. It's like being a
project manager and assigning tasks
right to the team member. Here's what
makes this more powerful and why it
connects to what I've been doing. You
know, I run the entire content operation
in my business of specialized AI agents
on the Mac Mini over here, and I've got
the Rizza handling video outlines,
Inspector Deck handling everything on X,
Ghostface doing intel research, Method
Man doing clips, Gizza running the
security. You know, each one has
specific jobs and specific personality.
That is the pattern that works.
Specialization beats generalization
every time. I learned that the hard way
by trying to make one agent to do
everything and it would just fail over
and over again. This repo proves that
the developer community is figuring this
out at scale. You know, 2,100 stars in a
week doesn't happen by accident. People
are realizing the way to get the most
out of AI coding tools is not to use one
agent for everything. It is to build a
team of specialists and orchestrate them
intelligently, but not one doing
everything. And that's what Vault Agent
also did, and I think that's really
smart. They built a companion of repos,
and they have awesome Claude Code
sub-agents for Claude Code users,
awesome Claude skills for Open Claw
users, and awesome agent skills that
cover skills across multiple platforms.
So, regardless of what tool you're
using, they're trying to give you that
specialist approach that tells you and
tells me that the team understands, you
know, the future is not about one
platform winning. It's a pattern of
specialized agents working for you
everywhere 24/7. The thing I want to you
to take away from all this is that the
era of generic AI assistant is
completely gone. We are moving into the
era of AI teams. Whether you're using
Codex, Claude Code, Open Claw, Cursor,
whatever you're using, the builders who
figure out how to create specialized
agents and orchestrate them are going to
absolutely crush the market because you
are not limited by your own time
anymore. You are limited by how well you
set up your team. And if you want to
learn how to actually build out these
agent teams for your business, if you
want to go from using AI as a tool to
using it as a real competitive
advantage, that's exactly what we teach
inside Shipping School. We are on day 13
of launching the community, and we have
134 members. We've got builders in there
right now running agent teams for their
businesses, real people getting real
results. We have people that are
non-technical getting Open Claw
installed and launching their landing
page within a day. Bunch of people from
all over the world, and we're really
focused on community first, which is why
we do six boot camp calls every single
week, and everything's recorded. We do
have courses in there as well, but we're
focused on human-to-human interaction.
So, like I said, I'll put that repo and
the link to the community down below.
Check it out. You know, we got awesome
Codex sub-agents on GitHub and many
other different types of repos that you
could plug and play to get your AI agent
orchestration going. You know, even if
you don't use Codex, for example, the
patterns they use and the way they
structure agents with specific
instructions and model routing and
sandbox permissions, you can apply those
same patterns to whatever tool you're
using. The framework doesn't matter
here. The pattern does. I just hope
you're taking advantage of all this AI
agent news and applying it to your setup
because that's what makes the
difference. If you haven't subscribed
already and you like AI news just like
this, make sure you subscribe, hit the
notification bell. We literally release
four to six videos every single day.
Have a blessed one. We'll see you in
about an hour.