Claude Code AutoDream was secretly just
released and it is here to be the
superhero we all need to save the world
from the tsunami of AI slop. And if you
haven't seen this before, it has quietly
popped up inside of Cloud Code. So
today, I just want to talk about what
Autodream is and the big problem that it
solves. I'm going to show you how you
can turn it on and actually manually
trigger it live. And then I'm just going
to tell you why this changes everything
for every Cloud Code user moving
forward. You like building cool things
with AI and want to start making some
money? All of my templates, workflows,
and challenges are available. The link's
in the description. It's only $9. So,
Claude Code has always had a memory
system in the form of these Claude MD
files. And a Claude MD file is a
usercreated file that basically tells
the system how you want it to behave.
And a couple months ago, Claude Code
released automemory, which is a memory
file that Claude Code writes itself and
automatically keeps up to date for you.
If you don't know, there are actually
two types of Claude MD files. one that
lives at the global level that is
accessed with everything that you do and
the other one lives at the project level
which is accessed individually per
project. So the two user created files
plus the cloud created memory file
creates the problem. So what is
happening is that automemory is
basically constantly firing keeping
track of all of the conversations you
had all of the projects that you are
doing. It is remembering everything and
learning from you as it goes, which
sounds really great because you would
think that this would improve itself
automatically over time without you
having to do anything. And so this
sounds all good and well and this is
great to an extent. When you first get
started, like you feel like things are
working and the system is remembering
things about you, but the more sessions
you have, by session 20, you have
overload. And this is a big problem with
all of these AI coding tools right now.
It's this idea of context rot. when you
have too much information for the
system, it doesn't know how to process
it. And it actually does a worse job
than if you had given it less. And so,
if you don't know, inside of this hidden
clawed folder inside of projects is
basically all of your memory files. And
this is a lot. If you go through here,
you can see how many memories and
transcripts and conversations and things
that the system is storing. So, all of
those files are everything that Claude
remembers about you and the interactions
you've had. So, who you are, what your
role is, what your preferences are, any
feedback or corrections that you've
given it, any projects that you've
worked on like goals, decisions,
deadlines, things like that, and any
references on where it should be looking
for other things. And each one of these
is stored in its own file, which is why
it gets so overwhelming. So, in walks
autodream to save the day. So, you can
basically think of AutoDream as this
little helper robot that sits between
all of your memory files and like the
ideal state. and its job is to go
through all of your conversations and
transcripts and keep the stuff that
matters and get rid of the stuff that
doesn't. So, in order to access
autodream, all you have to do is type
slashmemory when you're inside of the
terminal working with cloud code. So,
here you can see if I type /memory, now
we have this autodream feature. And
right now, it is set to never. So,
automemory is set to on, which means
it's going to keep track of all of our
conversations. And autodream is
currently set to off. So, what I'm going
to do is I'll just hit enter to turn
this on. But if you notice, they haven't
actually rolled out this feature here.
It says all you have to do is type
slashdream to run. But if you come in
here and type /dream, like you don't
have access to it. But what's cool is
that even though we don't have access to
the slash command, you can actually just
tell cloud code to use autodream. And so
you can see here that this is starting
to go through all of my files. And if
you want to see it in action, all you
have to do is type /tasks. So how does
it work? So to make the comparison, you
can basically think of cloud code like
humans. like we go about our day
committing things to short-term memory
and then at night a bunch of things get
dumped into long-term memory and all the
waste gets removed which is pretty much
why I can't remember what I had for
lunch yesterday. And so this is funny.
This actually says I'm not finding an
autodream posting method anywhere. But
if you look down here, this actually
says that we are currently dreaming. So
if I hit the down arrow and just hit
enter to view the task, you can see that
this memory consolidation is currently
running. What it is doing, it is
reviewing 97 sessions right now. And so
Autodream works in four phases. First,
it orients itself. Then it gathers
signal. It consolidates everything. And
then it prunes what's not needed and
indexes everything so that it can
retrieve it more easily later on. So
when it's orienting, it's literally
looking at everything. It's reading the
entire index of all of those memory
files that I showed you. It's skimming
the existing topics. Basically, it's
figuring out what it already knows. From
there, it's going to drill down a level
deeper. It's going to gather everything.
It's going to look at all of your recent
transcripts. It's going to identify any
drifted or like stale memories that are
just like not needed. It's going to
figure out what's new, what's old, and
any patterns across sessions so that
we're removing redundancy. From there,
it's going to consolidate everything.
It's going to merge new information into
existing topics and remove any
contradictions or anything that is
redundant and not needed. And then it's
actively going to write and update your
memory files. And the last thing it does
is just going to remove all of the old
entries that are no longer needed. It's
going to keep the memory.md file like
super concisely as an index that
references everything else and it's just
going to delete stuff that you don't
need. For all of you security people out
there, don't worry. Autodream only has
read only access to your project code.
So your project code is never actually
touched. It can only read it just to
kind of understand what's going on. It
does have write access, but only to your
memory files and nothing else. and it
does operate in a locked file. So if
you're operating like multiple cloud
code sessions, AutoDream is only going
to be running in one of those instances.
So there isn't any conflicts. What's
also cool is that this runs in the
background. So you can actually continue
your coding sessions without getting
interrupted by Autodream. Autodream runs
if it's been 24 hours since it last ran.
And if you've completed five sessions
since then, it's just going to happen
automatically and totally run in the
background. So you can now kind of think
of your memory as like a heartbeat, like
expanding and contracting over time. So,
your first sessions are going to be
super super clean. They're going to
expand and get more cluttered and then
autodream is going to come in to
consolidate and clean everything up
again so you can start back at the
beginning of this cycle. So, if we hop
back in here, you can see this worked
for 2 minutes. This improved four of our
memories from the session and everything
is nice and clean and tidy and optimized
moving forward. So, please join me in
giving a big round of applause to
Autodream for being the hero that Claude
Code needs. If you want to see how I use
Claude Code to gain 10,000 followers on
LinkedIn and over a million impressions,
just check out this video right here.