Today, I want to show you a workflow
that I've been using more and more
recently, and honestly, it's become one
of my favorite ways to build out AI
skills. It combines Notebook LM's deep
research feature with Claude skill
system. [music] And that result is
basically a way to turn raw research on
any topic into a working AI agent that
actually knows what it's doing. Here's a
problem I keep running into. Whenever I
wanted to build a cloud skill for
something specific, whether that was
SEO, copywriting, a specific industry,
whatever, I either have to write the
whole knowledge base myself, which takes
forever, or I just prompt Claude with
vague instructions and hope for the
best. Neither of those is great. What I
really needed was a way to get deep,
structured knowledge on a topic fast and
then feed that directly into a skill
that Claude can actually use. And that's
exactly what this workflow does.
Notebook LM does the research. Claude
builds the skill and then you got an
agent that can be dropped into any chat
or used inside Claude code that actually
knows the domain. Let me walk you
through this whole thing. Before we get
into notebook, let me quickly explain
what a Claude skill actually is. Because
if you haven't used them before, this is
the piece that makes everything click. A
skill in Claude is basically a
structured knowledge file, usually a
markdown document that tells Claude how
to behave in a specific context. It's
not just a system prompt. It's more like
a domain brief. You define what the task
is, what good output looks like, what
patterns to follow, what to avoid, and
you can include examples, frameworks,
step-by-step instructions, all of it.
When you load a skill into a project or
point Claude code at a skill folder,
Claude reads it and adapts his behavior
accordingly. So, if you have a skill
for, say, writing cold outreach emails,
Claude isn't just guessing what that
means, is working from a defined
playbook. That's the whole point. You're
basically training Claude to be really
good at one specific thing without
having to explain yourself from scratch
every single session. Now, the question
is, how do you build a good skill?
That's where Notebook LM comes in.
Notebook LM added deep research back in
November. And if you haven't tried it
yet, it's genuinely one of the more
useful AI research tools available right
now. And it's also free. Here's how it
works. You go into notebookm, you go to
the sources panel, you select web as
your source type. And then you get two
options. Fast research, which is a quick
scan, and deep research, which is the
one we want. You type in a question or
topic, and notebook LM literally goes
and browses hundreds of websites on your
behalf. It creates a research plan,
refineses a search as it goes, and then
spits out a structured source grounded
report in a few minutes. What makes it
different from just googling or using
another AI search tool is that the
output doesn't disappear. The report and
all the sources it pulled get added
directly into your notebook LM. So now
you got this rich knowledge base you can
keep curing, adding to, and cross
referencing. You can run multiple deeper
research queries on the same topic layer
in your own documents and build up a
really comprehensive picture of whatever
niche or subject you're working on. For
our purposes building skills, this is
incredibly useful because a good skill
needs real domain knowledge. It needs to
understand how professionals in that
space actually think and work and deep
research can pull that together for you
in minutes instead of hours. Okay, so
let me show you exactly how this works
end to end. Step one, pick your niche or
topic. For this demo, I'm going to use
something concrete. Let's say you want
to build a cloud skill for B2B sales
prospecting. You want a skill that can
help Claude write targeted outreach,
research prospects, identify pain
points, that kind of thing. Step two,
run deep research in Notebook LM. I'm
going to go into Notebook LM, open up a
new notebook, go to the sources panel,
select web, and hit deep research.
My question is something like, "What are
the most effective B2B sales prospecting
strategies in 2026, including
frameworks, outreach patterns, and show
how top sales team identify and qualify
leads?" You hit go, it runs in the
background, and in a few minutes, you
got a structured report or sources. Now,
I'll usually run two or three research
queries on the same topic to make sure
I'm getting good coverage. Maybe one
focused on frameworks and strategy, and
one on tools and workflows, one on
common mistakes, maybe. But each one
pulls different sources and all of it
gets layered into the same notebook.
Before we continue, we just launched the
universe of AI newsletter. If you want
to stay on top of AI news without having
to hunt for it, link is in the
description. Don't miss out. Step three
is to synthesize a notebook. LM. Now
that I got all this research loaded in,
if we take a look at this, we can see
that this article over here at the top
is a summary of all of these cited
sources and it kind of shows us what
database sales looks like, especially in
2026 and how it is transitioning to AI
intelligence and signal-driven
frameworks. So, we have frameworks, we
also have where it's heading and things
like that. I can now start asking
Notebook LM to help me organize it. I
can ask it things like what are the core
principles that come up across all these
sources? What frameworks are mentioned
most? What does good prospecting
actually look like step by step? And
notebook LM pulls from everything in the
notebook and gives me grounded cited
answers. This is the synthesis layer.
I'm not actually writing the skill from
scratch. I'm extracting structured
insight from real research backed in by
notebook LM. So we can see our notebook
LM has imported all the sources. We have
the summary document as well. We can see
already that we also have top sales
methodologies over here. If I wanted to
just learn about them, I can learn about
them over here. But for our purposes, we
want to take all this information and
feed it to Claude, especially for the
skill file. So, I'm going to show you
guys exactly how to do that. You have a
couple of options. You can take this
specific summary document, which
summarizes all of your, you know,
research from all the sources. But one
thing you'll notice is that it's pretty
vague, right? We have benchmarks, we
have AI, automation, and things like
that. Not specific frameworks,
everything. So you could do something
simple like this. You could ask it
specific questions like what are the
specific frameworks or strategies and
take that information for our purposes.
Let's say I want to learn about how to
write targeted outreach, research
prospects and identify pain points and
build the skill around that. I'll ask
that question and send it to Notebook LM
and then it's going to go through all
that research and give me a summary of
how to do that specific skill. So it's
going to do that and it's going to send
us an answer. So you can see that we
have an answer over here basically
telling us that how to research
prospects the five-minute habit
identifying pain points what we need to
do and how to write targeted outreach.
So once you're in claude all you got to
do is click on this sidebar click on
that and then click on customize and
then go to your skills and then click on
creating one over here. You can do
create with claude or you can write
skill instructions. For first timers try
to do create with cloud because it makes
the whole process much easier. So we'll
do that. You can see it gives you a
prompt. Let's create a skill together
using your skill creator skill. First,
ask me what this skill should do. So,
instead of us starting from scratch here
where most people would when they're
actually doing the skills, you now have
research and methodologies that you can
take from notebook LM and paste into
cloud instead of you typing from
scratch. So, we're going to take this
and we're going to give it a name. Then,
I'm going to create a section called
processes knowledge. And what I'm going
to do over here is paste in all the
information that we got from over there.
Then you might also want to specify how
you want the output to be for this
purposes. Obviously, I'm going to use
this in multiple formats. But I can just
tell it that in the output use the
knowledge base that we have given it
over here to help generate work that
aligns with the research. We want to do
that. Let's say if you're kind of
creating a skill for a specific writing
style, you could do some deep research
on that writing style. Bring that in and
tell it the same thing and it'll align
your output to that. Or if you're trying
to create an AI consultant, you can
study all these frameworks and you can
tell it to give you an output, specify
the output like implementation plan,
strategic takeaways, things like that.
This is very customizable. So you can
play around with this and you can
duplicate your skills and change your
output format. Or you don't have to
specify how you want the output and can
let Claude decide for yourself. But as I
said, it's going to be dependent on the
skill you're trying to create and the
specific domain knowledge you're trying
to understand as well. Right? So we'll
do that. So I'm going to press enter.
And what Claude going to do is going to
use that skill creator that you can see
over here that skill that it has. So
right now we are in a skill seion.
Basically it's using a skill file to
create another skill file and then it's
going to create that new skill which is
going to be called outreach skill. You
can see that it read that skill file but
it's also asking some clarification
question which is why sometimes building
skills with claude is much easier
because you know you might have missed
something in your head that Claude kind
of flags. For example, it's asking three
questions. Which output types, cold
email, LinkedIn, phone scripts, or full
multi- channelannel? What inputs Claude
should expect? How opinionated on
structure? Very rigid, flexible, or
loose. For our purposes, I'm going to
select the full multi- channelannel
sequence, which makes sense. Start off
with email, then go to LinkedIn, and
then phone. So, let's do that. And then
the second question is, what should
Claude need as input to use his skill?
Prospect name from company, signals,
triggers, your product, service,
context, a target person, or ICP. Let's
do your product or service context and
prospect name plus company. So, I got to
specify what I'm trying to sell and then
the company and then cloud will do the
rest. How opinionated should the skill
be about structure? Very opinionated.
Always follow the three-part structure.
Context value as flexible. Suggest the
framework but let context guided. Just
apply the knowledge. Don't enforce a
rigid template. So, this is really good
because Claude is saying, "Okay, you
provided me with this framework. Do you
want me to stick to it all the time? Do
you want me to be flexible or just apply
the knowledge and don't enforce a rigid
template? I'm going to do the middle
ground which is kind of flexible suggest
the framework but let me decide what I
want. So now it's going to build that
skill based off those clarification
questions. So now what you're seeing is
our whole skill packaged over here. We
can see apply the skill whenever the
user wants to write cold outreach, sales
sequences, prospecting messages. You are
an expert B2B sales strategist and
copywriter. Your job is to help the user
write outreach that is hyper relevant,
signal driven, and structured for
response, not volume. We already have
this AI agent or AI skill that's going
to help us a lot, save us a lot of time.
And it says step one, assess what you
have. Input available, prospect name,
everything like that, action, skip, ask.
So depending on what I give it, it also
figures out what it needs to do. Step
two, research mode when needed,
leadership changes, funding round,
strategic language, job posting,
competitive moves depending on the
situation, signal density rule, painoint
deduction. So determine what the pain
point is. I'll put right then this part
is probably more relevant to us which is
outreach writing core principles under
125 words signal first opening outcome
over features one ask only no buzzword
and three-part structure context value
as so it has all that framework that we
applied from notebook LM and then you
can build that sequence we can see day
one channel day one LinkedIn day two
email day four phone call day seven
LinkedIn. So we have that you know
length and everything like that. So, it
has this sequence already built in for
us. So, we can save a bunch of time and
we have subject lines and everything
like that. But you can see we now have
access to this skill and we can just
copy this to our skills and it's going
to be available for us to deploy
whenever we want. So, now what I'm going
to do is actually put my skill to test.
So, I've taken this snack company, a
snack company that I love. Uh, this is
like their product. They sell lotus
seeds. So, they have all these flavors.
And what I've done is I've created a
simple hypothetical situation which is
to build a cold email sequence for
Airbloom uh a snack company struggling
with order delivery and logistics. Then
I'm also going to ask it to try to
determine other pain points that they
might have. So this is all hypothetical
and I've given it a link and all I have
to do is now if I just press this I have
access to all my skills and then I can
go to over here and then you have skill
but we also have the outreach one. So
we'll click on the one that we just
created and we'll do that and then I'll
just press enter. So right now what it's
doing is actually reading the outreach
skill. So now you don't have to repeat
yourself multiple times or paste in
frameworks all over again. You have
access to this whenever. So now it's
doing that and just based off of that it
read the skill and it's given me
everything I need. For example, we have
these pain hypotheses which are like
order fulfillment gaps, maybe fragile
product in transit, cold change or
seasonal demand spikes, returns or
refund ops, everything like that. And
then what I have over here is couple of
emails that I can send to them. For
example, a 14-day sequence. So 14 days
worth of work is done now because of the
skill I have built. Number one, day one,
LinkedIn, what to say, what to do. Then
an email chain. Then if I want to cold
call them, what I can do is call them
over here. Everything like that. Then I
have another LinkedIn touch, another
email point touch up with them and
everything like that. So I have 14 days
worth of work just laid out for me
within a couple of seconds. And I also
did a couple of personalization notes
like who to target. So founder CEO is
saying that it's likely a small team of
one to three people. And right now it
says that this person Dave White
appeared in the searches. So I can use
his contact to you know reach out to him
whatever and then everything like that.
And then also I asked it to do a full
research on it. So this is the summary
of what the product is and on the bonus
pain points which I asked it to do
beyond the stated delivery and
logistical issues there are five other
areas I found as well. So all of this
work was done for me within couple of
seconds and I have not only one day's
worth of work done but 14 days worth of
cold emails or messages set up and this
was just in the chat feature. If you
were to use the co-work feature in cloud
as well you could do that. You could
also use it in the code feature because
you have access to this skill wherever
in co-work hypothetically for example
you can access your skills just like you
would access everything in uh your
normal chat feature but now you also
have access to your calendar in co-work
you have access to your actual email for
it to send drafts and everything like
that. You also have access to
automations and schedule tasks and
everything like that. So this skill once
you have built it from notebook LM you
have access to wherever you go in cloud
even you can transfer the skill into
other AI models like chatbt or even a
Gemini as well but I personally like
claude because of co-work and everything
like that. So I've chosen claude today
as my demo. So that's pretty much the
full workflow. You use notebook's deep
research to pull structured expert
knowledge on any domain you want. Then
you take that research into Claude and
build a scale file that turns that
knowledge into repeatable agent behavior
and you end up with Claude that doesn't
just kind of know your domain. It
operates from a real knowledge base and
gets better every time you update it.
The library of skills you build up over
time becomes genuinely valuable. And
it's the difference between using Claude
as a generic assistant and using it as a
specialized agent that knows your work.
If you want to see me apply this to a
specific domain, drop it in the
comments. I'll pick a few and maybe I'll
do a dedicated walkthrough for that as
well. But if you found this helpful,
make sure you guys like the video and
subscribe to the channel. But that's it
for today's video. Make sure you guys
are subscribed to the channel. Follow
our new newsletter as well at
universeai.behive.com
as well as subscribe to the main channel
World of AI and support us on X by
following the Universe of AIZ as well.
Until then, I'll see you guys in the
next video.