Building a second brain is one of the
most important things that you can do
for your life. But the problem is it
takes so much effort to maintain it that
most people give up within a month of
trying. Gene tried out every
methodology, every system, every
application known to man and nothing
stuck. But something changed. In the
beginning of 2026, he decided to combine
Obsidian with Claude code and all the
admins seemed to disappear overnight. So
today we're having a conversation with
Gene to try to understand why previous
systems fail him and why this system
that he's using now simply works. We're
going to go through his setup and we're
going to explore how he's using it and
how he's able to build applications
within Obsidian using AI tools like
Claude Code. Applications like your
personalized read it later app, source
processing, meeting processing, health
tracking apps, project management. All
of these tools you can now build without
any coding experience.
>> So strap in kids cuz this is going to be
fun.
>> Okay. So today we are talking with Jean
and Jean is a guy that went through one
of my three session builds where we set
up Obsidian. We integrate Claude code
into Obsidian as well. And it's just a
beautiful collaboration and he is
definitely an edge case. It's someone
who has
a lot of meetings, a lot of projects, a
lot of information thrown at him, more
than any of the other people that I
worked with. And I thought if this could
work for him, it could work for anybody
else. So, Gene has collected all of the
infinity stones related to knowledge
management. He's tried every system,
every app, and then finally found a
system that works. So, today we're just
going to explore his setup and what
works for him. So, Jean, tell us about
you. tell us about your use case and I
also just want to dig into the journey
of what have you tried up until now and
we'll get into why this system that
you're using null just works. So off to
you.
>> Yeah. So my name is Gene Ren. I am based
out in San Francisco and I work in tech
and middle manager at a tech company.
Yeah. So for me, you know, the tech
industry is going through a lot right
now with like all the AI advancements.
There's a lot of reals happening, lots
of leadership changes, new technology, a
lot of pressure on the bottom line. Um,
yeah, sometimes it just feels quite
overwhelming and my work life is all
consuming. I work very long hours. I'm
constantly going getting a lot of
information and having to process
through a lot of information and I'm
constantly being asked to do more with
less. So that's exactly why I became
obsessed with building a second brain
because I truly believe that if I have
the perfect system, the perfect
structure, the perfect recall and if I
can do this the right way to capture and
organize everything, I could finally get
on top of everything. So that's like,
you know, the promise of a second brain
is very very alluring to me. I think to
as well like the people that I speak to
is that is the dream. They want the
perfect setup.
>> So I don't think you're alone with this.
I think everybody's looking for that one
thing that would fix all of your other
issues.
>> Yeah. So I went all in. Like I I think
it's been a a few years now. So started
this journey probably about three to
four years building out the second
brain. I tried it all. I started with
David Allen's getting things done. I was
very much into Thiago's uh building a
second brain and which kind of brought
me a lot of knowledge into this how I
sort of structure my notes and work
through a bunch of other productivity
system and then I tried every app that
you can think of. So I've tried
Evernote, notion, ample node, capacity
but I have to say like nothing really
stuck. Yeah. So it's just tried
everything.
>> Yeah. for
me in university.
It's like five, six, seven years ago. I
was also looking for the perfect system
and I also went through the same journey
as you and I always felt like
when I was going to try out this new
software like notion was one of them.
Evernote was also one of them that I
initially tried out for journaling and
all of them 2 months later I would just
get to a point where I'm like this is
not useful anymore. I know there's a
better way of organizing this
information, but it felt like the
systems and the technology wasn't
developed yet in order to make it work
and that frustrates me or it frustrated
me quite a bit when I was university. So
my next question to you is what was the
actual problem you were trying to solve?
Like I want to understand what do you
feel was going wrong cuz I have my
opinions on what was wrong with the
systems before the one that I settled
on. So just walk me through your
process.
>> So I consume a lot of courses right like
I I'm very actively trying to learn um
all these different system. I think a
lot of the courses in the uh PKM space
is they're really good at the
methodology side. So they explain the
methodology but the when the rubber hits
the road right like when you're actually
implementing your life it's a quite a
different experience. And I found I mean
for my very complex use cases it just
wasn't able to just hold up. Um and then
in terms of the apps like I tried as I
mentioned every app out in there. So I
tried Evernote which is the OG. I didn't
really like the foldering system. And
then of course when all the new apps
came to market like you said right
notion beautiful app.
>> Yeah.
>> But man like learning notion is like a
full-time job. There's like so many
things to do just one thing right. I
really like capacities. Capacities is
it's a beautiful app. But then once you
get above a certain number of nodes that
even feels very bloated.
>> So nothing really stuck because the
maintenance was the overhead. All the
maintenance of like you know your second
brain system and then the learning the
the note is just way too high. And the
real problem is I know if I can get this
right, it's going to help me, right? But
maintaining it is like a full-time job.
I think that's the problem. So, I really
like tried out so many different ways to
to to set this up and I have this like
start and stop start and stop issue.
Like I started full of hope and then
life gets very busy and then I abandon
it and then because life is busy I'm
like oh I need that second brain system.
>> So and then I dig back in again. So like
I've been going through this cycle quite
a bit. So I came across your video about
a year ago and I really like your
approach. I think the way that you
actually show your thinking and the
workflow behind your system. Um you're
very opinionated. you think that
Obsidian is the right tool and then you
build a whole system around it
>> which I really really enjoyed and I that
really drew me to your your content and
so I bought your demo vault a year ago
started implementing it actually really
enjoyed the the build and like how the
structure actually works
>> but again right like life got busy the
maintenance piece is still quite high
>> and so I just decided I mean I could see
the potential but I, you know, tried to
build it, gave it up.
>> Yeah.
>> And then beginning of this year, I was
like, "Okay, well, I really need to do
something about this. I need to get this
right." So that's when I engage you on
the three session build.
>> The I'm curious, how many times do you
think you've started over with previous
tools?
>> Yeah, I I mean, it's embarrassing to to
admit, right? like I probably like
seriously like start and stop probably
five or six times and then every time
I'm like oh maybe I'm the issue right
like thinking about how
you know like if other people like I
look at you and you're like you have
this perfectly built system and you're
so disciplined about it so maybe I'm the
problem here not being able to to to
keep this up but I actually think that
that there must be an easier way to do
this right like can't just be so
difficult.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> a point a point on that is before the
end of last year,
every time when I engaged a client to
help them build out Obsidian and help
them map their lives, I kind of had to
give a preamble to say, "Hey, listen.
This will help you, but it's all going
to take a lot of work. It's it will make
your life easier than what it is now,
but there's still a lot of admin
associated with it." And that's what you
mentioned with the the cost like the the
work why last year when you had the
obsidian build that you could see like
oh this will help me if if I can just
start to capture information into the
system in the right way
but the maintenance of it I saw with a
lot of people was the problem and it
seems like that is also something that
got fixed for you. So where did it get
fixed? And then we're going to use parts
like how did we fix the maintenance
admin problem.
>> Yes, I think this is where the cloud
code and obsidian enters the picture for
me. So I did the three session build
with you. I think it was only a month
ago
>> and I think you know I was very happy
with the structure that I've set up. It
was just very helpful to have like a
system to basically contain like a
container to manage all the areas of my
life. And I remember you mentioned about
quad code to me a few times and you were
saying how like you know if you if you
do this like the admin part is going to
go away and I just could not really
picture how that even works like how
would quadcore and obsidian actually
work together. Right. So was going on a
long weekend holiday. uh you were doing
a group live session showing like clock
code how how it connects to obsidian and
your workflow and I didn't think that I
could join the session but my friend was
running late he was going to pick me up
was running late and so I was like okay
well I'm just going to jump on and dude
like that one hour session was probably
one of the most eyeopening experience
I've had
>> like I remember you were showing on your
terminal you basically just gave it a
prompt and today went to had a workout,
did legs today, did split squat and then
it just like this perfectly organized
note just popped up on your day log and
I was like what the hell just happened
like what is this? So that was a very
very helpful session for me to really
connect the dots like finally
understanding what that actually means.
And so when I was in Tahoe for that long
weekend, I spent the entire time on my
laptop playing with claw code. Like my
friends thought I was crazy. I was just
like every waking hour, I was just on
there just testing out all these
different things. Once I had Cloud Code
and Obsidian set up, like the terminal
setup within my Obsidian,
>> I was off to the races. I threw every
problem that I had to just like test it
out. I was trying to see what can it do,
right? And yeah, I think the the thing
that clicked for me was that claude code
removed all the administrative friction
that killed every one of my previous
attempt trying to build the second break
with claw code and the evergreen vault
system that you created. The capturing
and the retrieval now has become a
non-event, right? So it just does it for
you. And I think that's the part where
it's just like, whoa, like this is so
cool.
>> Yeah. So,
>> I I like the the wording of nonevent.
And I don't want to just skim over it
because a non-event is so trivial. It's
like, oh, you don't need to think about
it anymore. And I kind of went through
the same cycle as you as well with the
Claude code and Obsidian. The first time
I saw claude code was last year while I
was updating my my different demo bolts
that I have and I was doing everything
manually and I just saw this thing that
can talk to MD files, markdown files on
your computer and I was like, "Oh, this
could help me to just update everything
quickly." If I want to go through a tag
taxonomy change, like I want to change
this tag to this tag, I can update it in
all of my notes automatically through
this program. So that was my first use
case for cla code. And then when I first
installed it and pointed it to my
Obsidian, I had exactly the same
revelation. I was like, oh, all of that
admin that I had to warn people before
like, hey, this is going to take work.
All of that immediately disappears and
it makes it fun in the process. So that
non-event, it's changing the knowledge
management, personal knowledge
management landscape so quickly and
that's why I'm speaking a lot about this
because there's no reason for you not to
have a personal knowledge management
system anymore. In the past, it was too
much effort and now you don't have that
excuse anymore.
>> So no non-event need to remember,
>> need to rush.
I want to say something about that,
right? Like I was I felt very lucky that
I switched over to Obsidian a year ago
>> because what I have now realized is the
MD structure like the MD files
>> is essentially code, right? It's a type
of code
>> and CL code is very good at
understanding and creating code. And the
way that I have kind of understand my
second brain now is you have the MD file
which is your infrastructure layer right
that's all all the coding behind your
note-taking system happens and then we
have the evergreen vault that you
develop the the structure for like the
you know the tagging system and all the
different templates that sits on top of
the MD file right and so now we have
quad code that basically understands the
structure and the infrastructure layer
so that it's able to operate within that
because you can run cloud code in an IDE
you can run it in a terminal right
outside of obsidian and it it will just
run wild like it doesn't have an
organizing system to operate in
>> whereas with obsidian and then a
structure and then cloud code it's able
to have this container that it lives in
right to organize your life by using
that and I think that that is like where
when I understood with that then like
we'll show we'll show some of the things
that I built
>> almost like building an app within my
obsidian right because a lot of the use
cases that I'm that I'm solving for like
the automation is using obsidian as the
infrastructure layer to solve a lot of
these like automation problem that I
have.
>> Yeah. So what we mean with the folder
like you have a folder in your computer
and in that folder you have your
obsidian vault and what we are talking
about with like this evergreen or demo
setups is basically just a obsidian
vault that is optimized for daily note
takingaking. So we have the daily notes
first methodology which basically just
means that every day we have a daily
note and that's where we indicate what
we're doing and then we branch off to
different areas. take that structure
with the daily notes first. We have some
project methodology of of how to run
projects. You basically have your
project page and then underneath your
project you have all of the sub
projects. Underneath that you have all
of the meetings and work sessions and
then you basically complete the project.
So what you do now is you just take claw
code. It looks at your obsidian. It
understands how you do project
management and it's almost like a
missing puzzle piece that you can just
perfectly fit into your obsidian
structure. compared that to just a
folder on your computer and then you
link a tool like claude code to that
folder to say hey I want you to help me
with this project it has no structure to
go on so it's just going to go and
create its own structure which you might
not understand so that's why we go first
with structure and then we have the AI
tools which just helps with the
maintenance of your structure and it can
also help you upgrade your structure I
mean
>> you might have some preconceptions of
like this is the best way to do project
management and then you can go to claude
code and say go look at my current
structure and how I do things give me
improvement points it it definitely it's
it's like the perfect match obsidian
claude code obsidian for the structure
cla code for basically your personal
assistant that understands your
structure so when you say something to
it knows exactly what to do so we're
going to go through that so I think this
is a good transition point I want you to
walk us through your daily note so I've
taken some inspiration
from the color coding myself. I also
wrote an article about it as well cuz I
find it so interesting. Very short
article of how I deboard
unboard my Obsidian visual landscape. So
I think other people would also find it
valuable to see a real life example of
how you use this in practice and what
your obsidian looks like. So do you mind
sharing your screen?
>> Sure. Kim, I can see your screen. Tell
us what you're thinking. What What are
we looking at?
>> Yeah. So, everything starts with a daily
note, right? So, this is my daily note
structure. So, I just like do a quick
walk through and how like I I now log my
life essentially. So, there is I start
my day with a morning manifesto. It's
just essentially a bunch of things to
like journaling and just get my day
ready. And then throughout my day I just
basically live my life and then I log
all the different things that is
interesting to me. So like at any
administrative task, any work session
that I've done uh lunch for example
and then like workouts I think this is a
good one to kind of talk through. So
before cloud code right well I basically
have to remember okay well I need to put
in an emoji. I could type in the hashtag
logworkout,
what area does it fit into, which
project is it related to? And so now all
I do is just basically talk to my
computer. So I use Super Whisper. And I
basically just like talk to it and say,
um, I had a workout today at 300 PM. I
this is a push day. It was a good
workout. Seven out of 10. I hit six
personal best. Uh, had a pinch nerve on
my elbow, but it's improving. And then I
also did stand masters for 20 minutes.
So I basically just give it that prompt,
right? Like into plot code and then the
note just basically pops up and in an
organized way that I like it to be. And
so that's kind of like how I actually
all of the logs done through just like
talking to to call. Now
>> a quick note about that. So whisper flow
just audio to text. So do you mind just
quickly showing what it looks like if
you have it activated? I don't use
Whisper Flow, but I use Super Whisper,
which is a very similar app. So, I
basically just hit command and go, "Hey,
I worked out today at 3 PM and I had a
really good workout, 7 out of 10, and
today is push day. It's my fourth
workout for the week. I hit six personal
best. And had a pinch nerve on my elbow,
but it's improving. And then I did
cardio in the stand masters for 20
minutes and had a 200 calorie bread.
>> Okay.
>> And then basically just shows up and
then I hit enter. And then basically
that's b essentially how this notes
popped up with this prop.
>> Yeah. And then for the daily logging,
the reason why we use the structure, the
log workouts, log health or area health
and then point it to a specific project,
that is the structure Obsidian needs in
order to go send it to those specific
projects. So it needs to be in a very
specific that's the admin part that
we're talking about. It needs to be a
specific syntax.
It needs to be in a specific format. it
needs to have exactly the right project
linked to it in order for it to go to
the different places.
>> So that's why Claude is also so powerful
is there's no more manual or human error
that comes into play with oh I forgot it
to put it in the specific format. I
forgot to link the project. I forgot to
put in the right tag which means that it
won't show up at the right places. Now
you just teach your personal assistant
Claude code to do this perfectly for you
and then you can just talk to it through
natural language which I think is quite
cool. Okay, so we have your daily notes.
It's already pre-populated. So maybe
let's give them an example. Let's give
the audience an example of what this
would actually look like in real life.
>> Yeah. Okay. So just like as a demo,
right? Like as an example. So, say I
also went for a swim at the 300 p.m.
session and I want to log that. I can
just basically talk to it, right? So, I
go, "Hey, so for the 300 p.m. workout
session yesterday, I also went for a
swim for 15 minutes. It was a good swim.
Can you please log it?"
And the cool thing about this is
if you make mistakes in what you say, it
generally picks up the meaning behind it
well enough. So it feel like it gets to
know you.
>> And yeah, I think every time it makes a
mistake, it's not a reflection of the
tool because it is really good. It's a
reflection of how well you teach that to
somebody. So it's skills.
>> Yeah. So see it basically was able to
log it. It knows that it's it's under
this workout
and it's just basically a candidate.
>> Okay. So it can update logs. Can you do
me a favor and make as if you went for a
run at 4 p.m. I just want to see how it
populates.
>> Let's see.
Yeah. So, I also went for a run at 400
p.m. uh around the Golden Gate Park. Can
you help me log it?
And the cool thing about this as well is
you can have multiple terminals. Oh,
there we go. Perfect syntax, perfect
tags,
>> perfect everything. And we use this for
everything. So everything I am doing on
my daily note,
>> I don't type it anymore. And you can
also just do it from your phone as well.
And we'll talk a little bit later about
how we see the perfect knowledge
management system, what it is, like what
our criterias are for like the perfect
knowledge management system. But this is
definitely one of them where you don't
need to type anything anymore. So that's
pretty cool.
>> Yeah.
>> Nice. I mean, every one of these logs on
this daily page is like done through
that. I either I type it or I I speak to
it.
>> Uh like I had a dinner with a friend and
I basically just, you know, after the
dinner, I just basically said, "Hey,
like this is what happened. Here's what
we talked about. What did I eat?" And
then it just basically knows how to map
everything.
>> Yeah.
>> That's that's so cool. Okay. So this is
the daily note. So we've removed the
admin from the daily note. We now have a
personal assistant that can fill
everything in according to our structure
exactly how we want it. But I also know
that you've built a couple of other cool
things. So maybe we should go on a
little bit of a side adventure to since
you have a lot of meetings and you
process a lot of meetings. That is one
of the things that I found most helpful.
But you also have a very cool meeting
processing script. Do you mind showing
us that?
>> Yeah. So I'll give I'll use like an
example. This is like a real life
example. So I went to uh a lecture with
Michael Poland um wrote a new book about
consciousness. So it was a lecture at
Sydney Gen. And so what I did was I
recorded the session using my plot no I
have a plot pin. And so I recorded the
whole thing and so I have the
transcript. So what I do is I extract
the transcript, paste it into a note
with the meeting note template
and then what I will do then is
basically again talk to it, right? I
went to the Michael Poland lecture on
Wednesday and can you please process the
meeting note that I have? So I met up
with Ivonne to go to this session at
7:30 p.m. It was a very interesting
lecture. Really enjoyed it. Also was
very good to see Ivonne. She drove me
home after the lecture.
Okay. So then I hit enter. And this is
also cool because it's as if you have
again a personal assistant that you can
just speak to. So you don't need to say
in this format with this template in
give me these key takeaways like no it's
you set it up once and it knows which
skills which processes to use that's
what this meeting process so much
>> I think what's really cool is I didn't
even tell it which note right I just say
I went to the Michael Poland lecture on
Wednesday I want to process the meeting
note and it was able to find it's
basically let me find the existing
thing.
>> Yeah.
>> And then let's see, right? Let's see if
it's able to find this particular note
that I'm trying to.
>> I love this so much.
Cuz yeah, it knows even if you didn't
even say the day. Like if you just said
Michael Poland, it would go look for all
of the notes with those two words and it
would see oh on Wednesday because I know
your structure use a daily notes first
structure which everything will be put
in on your daily note. It knows where to
go find it.
Yeah, that's why I like this. I like
this so much. And with meeting
processing,
if it's a long script, and there's a
couple of times when I have meetings
that's 2 3 hours long, it's a long
script. The cool thing is you can just
let it run and you can go make coffee.
Like it's normally when I finished
meetings working as a banking
consultant.
I won't do that. After the meeting,
after that 2-hour meeting, you're too
lazy to go do anything. So then you do
nothing. And you say you'll you'll try
to convince yourself that tomorrow
morning I'm going to wake up extra early
to do it. And you never do it. That
meeting is never processed. Which means
that the insights it's 4 weeks later.
It's as if the meeting never happened.
Mhm.
>> This is just it it saves effort for you.
I think it's
>> So yeah, I see what it did, right? It's
a social because I'm meeting up with a
friend.
>> It's leisure. I mean, I see this as
leisure. I mean, really, this could also
be learning. Um, and then it maps it to
the events, right, that that I basically
created earlier. So what what it did is
it took the all the transcript and then
it summarized the a key takeaway
tool or resources mentioned. So like
anything that was discussed
>> it basically gives like a a list of a a
list of these.
Yeah, that's
>> and are tagging like all the different
areas
and I can basically say I don't I don't
agree with this. I I think I wanted this
in learning. So, can you please up this
to the learning area? It shouldn't be
leisure.
And then it just basically does the fix.
Yeah, I think my meeting processing, the
only thing that's different from yours
is I typically have to send follow-up
emails. So, I built into my meeting
processing that it should give me a
draft email to send out to the people as
well. And I think everything else is
pretty much the same. But the key
takeaways the key takeaways is if you
scroll down a little bit okay so it's
updated the up to learning
>> and then you can also just say like okay
well don't make this mistake again but
in this case it's very subjective but
the key takeaways this is something cool
that I found which is also with the
source processing which I think we'll
get to a little bit later as well which
these key takeaways turns into their own
notes so every time a meeting or process
a source
>> these key takeaways that the AI gift to
you on a silver platter. It's so easy to
turn that into notes. So consciousness
is a practice, not a puzzle. The second
last insight that you have number seven
>> that's like, oh yeah, I want to change
that or turn that into a note that I
want to reuse in the future.
>> So in the past when you go to a lecture
like this, you would be in the lecture
and you would try to take everything in.
You might write it in in a little
sketchbook or just a normal note-taking
book and two weeks later you'll probably
forgotten most of the insights, but now
you can actually take that insights and
put it into your own system of things
that you found interesting.
>> Yes. Yeah. I think that that's that's
why like I just love this so much,
right? Like say if in a month's time I'm
reading this book and I want to like you
know think through a c a few things I
can basically just go here and say
consciousness doesn't require brain I
can turn that into note as you as you're
saying right and then I can then
basically create this note
um use the ch the note template
and then
>> like basically it's like actually write
notes as I'm reading the book about this
particular point, right? And then it
will all be like deep linked. So
>> I just love
>> if you go back previous one,
>> the previous page
>> and you tell Claws like the third key
takeaway, can you turn that into a note?
I've been using that so much because
then it links that where this note came
from as well. So I'm curious to see
without you having done this if it
automatically links it back to the
original source
>> for the third key takeaway. Can you
create a child note out of this?
>> So that is normally my process of the
meetings as well if there's something
interesting that was said. So, in one of
our consulting calls, you mentioned
something related to a warm coffin, and
I like the imagery that it brought up,
and I knew that I want to use that
imagery in an article. So, I created a
note, the warm coffin. And when I was
writing the article, I remember like, oh
yeah, I had a conversation with Jean
about this concept. I want to bring this
into an article and I could just pull it
in because I already made the note about
it.
>> Yeah. It's like it created this as a
knowledge node with the event as its
parent.
>> Nice.
>> So cool. So it just knows how to do it.
>> Yeah. For this you can also like fill it
in with this. So normally you would have
to type it out.
But now you can just say okay so my
takeaway
from this note is this. Fill that in the
correct format into this note. So it
could still be your takeaways. It's not
just it's not just you telling AI to
okay go create that note and fill in
five pages of information about that not
like no why do you find it valuable
update the summary to this this is how I
want to use it in the future so it's you
creating new notes so the way that I see
the evolution of knowledge is we
obviously started out with oral
storytelling then we went to writing
then we went to the press well writing
We've oral storytelling, writing, and
now we are dictating again. We're
speaking again, but like back to text
with some filter in order to put it in
exactly how we wanted to do to to
visualize to see the data and it just it
makes the whole note-taking journey just
a little bit more fun because you don't
have when you are thinking about
something to like okay now I need to
type this and I need to find the right
way to say it. It's like no, you can
just word vomit into claude code and it
gets your meaning and it returns it on
the piece of paper that you can then
reuse in the future for any future
writing project that you're doing or you
just like the quotes or you just want to
remember this piece of information. It
makes all of that very easy. So, no,
thanks. Thanks for that meeting demo.
>> Yeah, don't don't really think my
meeting demo has anything to add on
this. So maybe we can go to
source processing.
And this is also a nice one because it's
visual. So we can see a lot of images
flying around which is always
>> I think this is like one of my I felt
most accomplished building this out. Um
so I watched your YouTube video on
source processing. I think that was a
very good kind of framework. the
workflow was so solid. I think you went
through and like maybe we can link this
the video here. Um you basically use the
Obsidian web clipper and there's two
types of source sources that goes
through this uh uh processing. So a
YouTube video or an article, you use a
web clipper. It basically captures it in
your Obsidian and then we use the
process source skill
>> to basically turn that note into a
source note. And so I set that up and it
really like you know it worked really
well for me. I think one of the problems
that I had is I doom scroll a lot,
right? I'm just constantly consuming a
lot of social social media like the
podcast, articles, right? Everything.
And a lot of times I'm just not really
like just mindlessly consuming it.
Sometimes I come across something that's
really interesting and I want to save
it, but I just like don't know where to
to do it, right? So I have like a read
later app that I use for a while. So I
was then thinking, well, this is a
painoint for me, right? I'm like, well,
with the source processing
skill, can I teach it to have it so that
I'll just give it a link and then it
will figure out what type of source it
is and then process it for me. All
right. And so I basically developed this
workflow that I kind of want to show you
here.
So developed this thing where let me
zoom in. So I need to ask this process
flow that you write it out yourself with
Canva or was it
>> No. So this is this is like the canvas
note in obsidian because I've trained
cloud code like all of these things
right and I basically said hey can I
have a visual way to like visualize this
workflow here are the pillars that I
want to walk through and so it just
created this for me.
So you you've gone through a couple of
sessions where you're building out this
new application essentially. It's like
you want to pull in sources and then you
want a better way to visually understand
it and then Claude can build this for
you in Canva. This is definitely a
gamecher for people who like visually
>> because setting this up just linking the
different notes in Canva with all of the
little arrows going to different things
>> that would probably have taken you like
10 to 15 minutes to like think about
where you should place it where
everything should go and now you can
just ask
>> your to do it for you. I mean I I
literally just just I I was like think I
sketched this out like what are the
different steps that that you know like
basically built into this workflow right
and then I just basically said hey like
I want to can this um I want to think
through this visually
>> these are the steps that I want to walk
through and then it basically then
created this. So it was really really
cool to see. I mean I still have to
review it but it's pretty much like 90%
accurate.
>> Yeah. But if you have something like
that for any project that you're busy
with and you have enough information
just by creating a project, having a
couple of work sessions on it and
pointing Claude to those work sessions,
it must feel so satisfying to just see
it produce something visually. It's
like, oh yes, this perfectly explains it
to me so I can explain it to somebody
else. Cuz if you were to explain this
whole process to me by just speaking,
I would understand it. But with this
visual component, it just makes
everything so much easier.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, that's that's very cool, Jean. I
like this.
>> All right. Should we walk through the
system,
>> please?
So, one of the things that I did was I
set up a Telegram workflow where because
the Obsidian app on mobile is not great.
>> And so, I was like, well, when I'm on
the go, I don't want to like deal with
it like a clunky app um and then, you
know, have to like deal with all of
that. So can I actually set up a
telegram connector so that I can send
messages to myself on telegram and then
it pops up on my scratch I call it
scratchpad.
So what I do with this whole workflow is
as I'm going through you know like doom
scrolling which I need to stop when I'm
coming across interesting content I
basically share it with my telegram and
then it will be like you know any of
these type right so it can be a YouTube
video tik tok video it can be video or
carousel Instagram reals or post uh
articles and blog post and then also
Twitter post so what it does is it sends
the URL to my scrap scratchpad, which is
a note within my Obsidian.
And then when I'm back on my computer, I
basically just go and I ask it to do
process scratchpad, which is a skill
that I have developed. And then what it
does is there's actually a few things
that I train it to do, but for URLs, if
it's a URL, it then routes it to a
process source.
>> Yeah. if it's like an activity or day
log because sometimes I'm out and about
like I want to log having lunch with
this person. I basically log it in the
telegram, right? And then it would know
how to basically process all of these
different types of activities.
>> That's clever. Okay, so you're using
your phone as basically the capture
engine for your obsidian when you open
up your obsinian data or if it's on
>> it can just process it. And now with um
claude code has that you can set
specific tasks for like every 30
minutes. So you can technically automate
that whole process now as well. As soon
as it goes through every 30 minutes it
goes and checks and then just processes.
>> Oh it's so my scratch pad is my dumping
ground, right? Like I'll show you what
it looks like. Yeah. So this is my
scratch pad. So it's like a mobile
capture inbox. So I have all these
basically this unprocessed item, right?
It's like you know the your video about
like building second brain with
obsidian. I want to do a reminder. Hey,
like I need to do this soon.
>> Reminder and then when I'm back here, I
just basically go process scratchpad. It
basically looks through all of this and
then it does fires off all of the the
steps and then it then deletes this. So
for the first one the process step it
would automatically detect that the
first one has a link therefore use the
process source
>> correct. So what it then does is the
process scratchpad basically reads all
of this if it's a URL it routes to this
is agent teaching the agent right agent
firing off an agent. So it fire off this
process source. So then it it then does
this. It detects the URL patent. So if
it's a YouTube, it knows that it's a
YouTube, Tik Tok, you know, different
types. And then what then it does is it
does a platform specific extraction.
So what I have taught it is not taught
it but I ask it to build is
>> if it's a sorry
>> what you've built you've done.
So, if it's a YouTube, it knows to grab
a transcript. So, that's an API that it
fires off
>> and then it does all of the the things
that I want it to. If it's a this this
part is really really cool, a Tik Tok
video or carousel thing, it knows that
if it's a Tik Tok video, it just
basically grabs the Tik Tok transcript.
>> Yeah.
>> And then does the summary. If it's a Tik
Tok carousel, it knows to basically like
use like an MCP to get the the images of
each of the carousel.
>> Do you have an example?
>> Yeah. So, let me quickly walk through
this. Essentially, there's like all of
these different types, right? And then
it then creates a source node. It has
like all of these different components
in the source node. So what I can show
you is for my source base, right? Um
yes. Yeah. So let me see an example of
the
>> essentially a table in your Obsidian
that shows all of the sources you've
ever pulled in from most recent to least
recent.
>> Yeah. So like say this one like I'm
learning UI design.
>> Um so it's an Instagram carousel. So
what it does is it grabs all the
different images.
>> And then it actually reads each of the
images to transcribe what's in there.
>> Yeah.
>> And then it then basically does a key
takeaway all of the different resources.
I basically said like if it's a website
that it's talked about, go and find me
the link. and then deep link it. And
yeah, so that's basically the workflow.
So that's a carousel. If it's a Tik Tok
video, it grabs the transcript
>> and then it just does like a key
summary, key takeaway.
>> Yeah. Kind of like the meeting
processing.
>> And then let's see there a YouTube clip.
>> So all of this is kind of advanced if
you think about it. It this is an
application that you're building. This
is a
>> Yeah,
>> it's an app within Obsidian.
>> this is an app within Obsidian. And like
it solved like one of the biggest pain
points that I've been thinking about.
I'm like, how do I how can I like I come
across so many interesting stuff that I
want to keep, right, that I want to
refer to in the future.
>> Yeah.
>> So, like I this is a YouTube one. It
embeds the YouTube video. Yeah. So, my
Wheatwise subscription just like ended
and I haven't I haven't um renewed it
because I I mean maybe I will renew it
for like the the reading thing, but I'm
now thinking maybe I don't need to
anymore
>> because you can build your own version
of it.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, this is kind of my own read,
right? like and then when I actually
have time to engage with it, I can then
again like what we talked about, I can
turn this into a knowledge database.
>> Yeah.
>> This is this is cool because you are
building the application which is a read
it later app that thinks exactly the way
that you want it to think. So it's not
you sending a feature request for a
application that you have signed up for.
It's like hey I really want this
feature. It's like no it's yours. It is
your application the processes that
process source that is basically the
back end of your app and you're using
Obsidian as your front end and together
they are a very unique source processing
application and
I've gone through a couple of these
skills that I've created and sources
that I created and if you haven't done
this before you might think well this is
so far out of my skill range.
And it is not it's tell me how long did
it take you to build this process.
>> Yeah. So I mean I would say right I do
not know code. I mean I learned HTML a
long time ago. Do not know do not know
any code. I don't understand Python.
>> This took me like probably over two days
of about one to two hour build per day.
>> Yeah. And it's just basically giving it
a like this is what I'm trying to do.
And then clical basically then plans out
the the whole thing. And then we start
off like by component. Right. The start
with the YouTube one and then the next
article and then we then tackle the Tik
Tok. The Tik Tok one actually took a
while to get right.
>> Right.
>> Or an Instagram because it's you can't
just download image from your carousel.
Right.
>> So it basically like do a bunch of
testing. Um yeah and now I basically
have a functioning read later app
>> and this whole process is
you talking to claude code it's trying
to pull in like let's say let's say
YouTube video it's trying to pull in a
YouTube video and that YouTube video is
not showing up on that specific note
that we see right in front of us right
now. You then go back to claude code
saying I'm not seeing this URL. Are
there any solutions of how we can pull
this in? And it goes through a couple of
iterations, it tries again, it fails
again. You say like, "It's still not
working. It's still not working until it
finally does." And it's like, "Yes,
that's the one. Update the skill." So
then you basically went through
different versions of your application
to find a one that a version that works
exactly how you want it to work. So it's
not you looking at code. It is not you
needing to understand how the code needs
to be structured. It is just you having
a conversation.
>> Yes. And it's it's almost like because
it's not perfect, right? Like the Tik
Tok carousel as I mentioned, right? It
took a long time.
>> I fixed them all now, but like what was
happening before was Let me see if I can
find
maybe the IG one.
Yeah. So, it was Yeah. See, like this
one.
Uh Yeah. So, this one I actually fixed
on on my main vault.
>> Yeah. But essentially this is not how I
wanted it, right? So what it did was it
basically did like a screen capture
>> like a screenshot into like each of the
slide whereas I didn't want that. I
wanted to show up like the the note
before where it's just all of the
carousel image coming up.
>> So for this I just basically said hey
like for this note this is not the
convention I wanted.
>> I want I don't want screenshot. I want
the image download. Right. And then it
then basically was like, okay, well, I
understand what you're saying. And then
it just basically try and do a few
different things. So it took a bit of
back and forth to to get it right. And
then once it's once it get it right and
then it just basically say, can you
please remember this in the conventions?
>> Yeah.
>> And then it updates the CLMD file, the
skills, and then a memory file to
basically like remember this convention.
>> Yeah. So for the people who aren't
familiar with Claude code yet, the
terminology is you have a claude end
file which is just a markdown file.
That's just a long instruction file on
how Claude should operate. So that's
basically it's memory essentially on how
to serve you for lack of better words.
And then we have these skills. So the
source processing skill that's basically
just another note that just instructs
Claude exactly that if the user pastes a
URL that means that we should go
activate the skill and then the skill
just have the step-by-step instructions
of what Claude should go do in order to
execute it. And then you have like a log
memory that just everything it does. I'm
guessing it just keeps track of
everything it's doing. Like it's like a
log, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> I've also implemented that in the past
week, especially working with another
tool, open claw, different use cases,
but
what is important with these AR tools is
they tend to hallucinate. So, they get
to a point where they don't understand
what you're saying anymore because it's
too far down in the conversation. What
obsidian does is it it confines it again
like it restricts it in the best way
possible that it doesn't lose the
context because you are operating within
your obsidian structure and again that's
why it's so beautiful. Um so yeah that
is the claude terminology. Something
else that I what you made me think of
null is I don't want to miss when
artists are coming to my area. So I'm
very bad at admin. That's why I like
Obsidian. It's one of those things that
I can offload unnecessary information
onto a page somewhere. And that's
basically why I first started using
tools like Obsidian is just to not have
to remember anything. And
one of the things that I always have to
be angry at myself for is one of my
favorite artists, they would come to
Amsterdam for instance, and I would just
miss it completely. I would find out a
week later that they came and there are
applications which can remind you of
these artists coming to Amsterdam and
>> gets the tickets pre-signup like
everything
but now you can bull it yourself. So
what I did last week is in Obsidian I
have a file which just lists all of my
favorite artists and now I have a job
that triggers every morning at 7 a.m.
that goes to all of the different
websites for these artists. It goes to
ticket master and
>> yeah,
>> it just gives me a summary every
morning. Say like, okay, there's no
updates. This person is coming on this
date. The pre-sale is going to open on
this date, on this date. We'll send you
a message on your daily note as well,
reminding you. We'll even put in a task
on your daily note for that day in the
future. Once I buy tickets, it
automatically knows to go book that time
in my Obsidian calendar. So that again
is an application which people pay for
which you can now build yourself and you
can customize it exactly how yes I mean
like I think that that point is about
building an application for yourself is
kind of the point right like your second
brain now is an it's a it's like a super
app
>> right there's like so many other things
that you can do just within your second
brain now and it is So so cool. That's
so cool.
>> I love that we are living in this time
period in history.
>> Okay. So should we do a couple of quick
fire rounds of other things? Us tasks is
one that I have not tackled sufficiently
yet, but because of your unique use case
and pressure testing, you kind of rely
on tasks. So I'm very curious to see
what you've set up because I haven't
seen this yet and I know I'm going to
take a lot of inspiration. So tasks
don't mind.
>> Yeah. So before I do task, I can also
talk through like a few other things
that I think that were really cool and
it was very fun to build. So one of the
things is I'm slightly dyslexic. So I
like colors help me read better.
>> Yeah. And so I basically said, hey, like
I wanted to differentiate if it's a log
versus an area. Yeah.
>> Because this is our convention, right?
Like there's there's always a log and
then there's an area that's mapped to
it. And then there's like either a
project or work session or whatever like
note that is related to that particular
log. So I said I want to like
differentiate the log and the area and
then also the the the note that is being
mapped to it. So I basically just gave
it this challenge. I'm like, "Hey, can
you help me figure this out?" And it's
like, "Sure." Like, this took like
literally five minutes. It created a CSS
snippet and then now like all my logs
and my areas are in different colors and
also the note type.
>> Yeah.
>> Different color conventions. I thought
that was cool.
>> Yeah. After I saw this, I think in our
third session, the final session of the
the three session build,
I was looking at my obsidian and I was a
little bit disappointed at how gray and
pale it looked in comparison. So the
next day I just decided like, okay, I'm
also going to do it. Like I know it's
not difficult. And 5 minutes, 5 minutes
and I had everything set up exactly how
I wanted. And I even wrote an article,
like a very short article explaining
exactly this. like it takes 5 minutes to
set this up and in 2 months when you get
bored of this color scheme you can just
say hey I don't like these colors
anymore change them and it can change it
according to a color palette so after I
saw your layout with these like color
tags I had a conversation with one of my
other business partners and he was
talking about
color theory and which colors go with
each other
>> get color palettes that if you have a
dark background, you should use specific
colors. So then I ask Claude like, "Give
me color schemes that I can use." And
now you can basically create an MD file
with a color scheme and you can just
tell Claude, "Okay, I'm in the mood for
that color scheme." And it would go to
that note and then of your notes
accordingly.
>> I like that.
>> That's so
>> I love that. Yeah, actually I think that
Yeah, that gives me inspiration, too. I
should I should probably do that
>> because you get you get bored of thing
like I feel
>> Yeah. I mean like I'm engaging with this
every day now. I want it to be visually
appealing.
>> Yeah. I liken it to fashions. Like you
get a new sweater and you love the
sweater and you wear it for a month all
day every day. After a month you're
going to be like, "Oh, I'm sick of the
sweater." And then you get something
else
>> and then you get something else for like
a couple of weeks or whatever. bad
example, but ultimately you'll come back
to the original sweat. It's like, "Oh, I
like this again." But now you can save
the presets and you can just switch how
you feel you want to work in your
Obsidian. So it's just like one snap and
everything is done.
>> Okay, that's what's next.
>> And the next thing is my mind palace
index. So I call my second brain a mind
palace. And so because I want
>> why Palace because that's Mine Palace is
the the guy who remembered where
everybody was sitting when a temple
collapsed back in ancient Greek or
something like that, right?
>> Yes. Because it's almost like it's
perfect recall, right? It's a demonic
device and to me like it's like this is
my mind palace. Like it's
>> it's my second mind pal second brain
mind palace.
Sorry, a a quick side
side note. This is your mind palace. You
know where everything is. And when I
first started to use claude code with
obsidian, there was a little bit of a
fear of am I going to lose my ability to
know the structure of my obsidian? But
there's this concept of extended
cognition that if you understand how
something works and you ask somebody
else to do it,
you asking that person fires off the
sequences of you manually doing it
yourself but somebody else is taking
care of it. So when you ask Claude to go
fill in something on your daily note,
just you asking
for that personal assistant to do that
fires off the same sequences which is as
if you are doing it but you don't have
to do it.
>> So it's it's not degrading the the note
takingaking process. It just speeds it
up with all of the connections still
remaining there which makes it an
extension. Like it's literally the
second brain. you think it, the
connection stays like, oh, okay, I want
this to go be be filled in on my daily
note because you think it, it's that
extension that goes from your brain to
the physical computer that you still
have that meat computer, technological
computer connection, but Claude is the
person that just does everything for
you. It's quite nice.
>> Yeah. Like I really like that that that
the way you're thinking about extended
connection. I actually have slightly
different take to build on top of that,
right? Yeah.
>> The way I think about it is our life is
finite.
>> We will never be good at doing
everything all at once.
>> There are things that we enjoy doing and
that there are things that we have
better strengths in. Right. Some people
are better in writing. Some people are
better in creativity. Right. We're never
going to be able to master every single
skills out there.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. And so for me, I often think,
okay, well, what is it that I enjoy
doing versus what is it that I have to
do,
>> right? And so for things that I have to
do that I don't really enjoy and there's
just a lot of like mental load that
comes with it, that is ripe for um AI.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Like I love like I love like you
know visually like explaining things but
I do not like coming up with the actual
artifact. Right. That's where AI comes
in. And so like that that's how I think
about like you know when to use AI
versus when to use my brain. And then
now that I have all of this right I'm
able to focus on so much more
interesting things right the the
connecting the reflection the creativity
right now that I have more time for that
stuff right all this administrative
stuff is now done automatically.
>> Yeah. So
for me as well like I feel there's way
more time to think to comfortable just
sitting and thinking about a concept. So
this extended cognition, single loop
learning, double loop learning, how the
work session and meeting aids in your
updating of mental models, like all of
these concepts is something that I'm
actively thinking about. But in the
past, I would need to go write
everything down, make sure that the
connections are right between the notes.
But that's the admin of it. It doesn't
allow me to just sit and think about how
I want to format and pull these things
to different places in order to write an
article about it or create a YouTube
video about it. The admin side of it is
handled which means I can say go create
this create these concepts and then I
can just sit back and think which is
nice. So the admin part is completely
just gone and it made the whole process
more fun again.
>> It becomes more fun.
>> Yeah. The fun thing the like the fun
thing is something that I keep on coming
back to. I'm just like really enjoy
doing this and it's like I'm solving
problems. I'm like really enjoying
engaging with it and it is a very fun
process.
>> Do you think
>> a quick question? Do you think
everybody else would find it as fun? Cuz
maybe we are just wired in a specific
way that we find this type of
organization fun and this type of
thinking fun in this specific capsule
which is Obsidian and Cloud Code. But
I've been wondering like maybe there's
just some people that won't find this
fun, but there's something in the back
of my head saying like no, if you have a
setup like this, there's no admin
associated with it, which means that it
takes the not fun parts out of it. So
I'm wondering what what you take. Do you
think other people would find this fun
as well?
>> Yeah, I that's a very good question
actually. Right. Like I mean I can't
don't know what everyone like how
everyone thinks but the way that I think
about it is it's fun because I have a
problem there is some friction
and then I came up with solution so and
then I'm solving it so it's very
satisfying right it's not the automation
that makes it fun because it's taking
away a lot of friction in my life it's
the problem solving that gives me the
satisfaction
>> right so if you're like using AI, you're
not having fun with it, I don't think
you're solving the right problem. That's
kind of like how I think about it,
right? It's the like because I have this
problem and I solve it and I figure out
a way to solve it, right? That is the
fun part. That is the sat.
It's like a dopamine hit that I'm
getting, you know?
>> Yeah, that's the answer that I was
looking for, but I didn't have the
words. So, thank you for for putting it
out there. So, what this tool allows you
is to solve your problems. And if you're
not enjoying it, it means that you're
not using it to solve your problems
because any problem that you have, if
you solve it, you're gonna have the
dopamine hit, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, that's nice.
>> Yeah. Because like I mean I I I I see a
lot of fear in AI. Like I I mean I work
in tech, right? Like this is like
everyone just talking about like the
fear of losing the jobs. So the fear of
not exercising your brain enough. It's
like that my point about like you can't
do everything at all times. You need to
prioritize. So prioritize what you enjoy
and don't let AI do that. If you love
writing, don't use AI to write.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Like if you hate writing, use AI
to help you write better.
>> Right. Like it's like that's that's
that's how like we need to you it's a
tool. We need to use it to advance
ourself on the areas that we want to
develop.
>> Yeah. And I think it's going to be more
important now than ever to
just follow your interests because
there's a lot of people saying that
we're all going to be out of jobs and
like the job market is going to shrink
like very doomsday scenario.
But with this, it it seems like the the
only way forward for the future of
specifically tech workers or finance
workers, a lot of these jobs, I don't
know if you saw, but Claude released an
article with this diagram that shows all
of the different areas, meaning like u
medical, engineering, mass, all of that.
And they had this cool diagram that
shows which areas they expect AI is
going to completely take over. And then
I have like all of these like okay cool.
So for transport not big takeover for
caring health services where it's
specifically caring for like elderly
that's not going to be taken over by AI
but then it's like math finance all of
those type of things. So now it's more
important than ever to use these tools
in order to upskill yourself in the
areas that you inherently find
interesting so that you can make
something out of that because that's the
only thing you have. you have the stuff
that you find inherently interesting and
stuff that you can potentially make
money off of of your interests and the
only way that you can do that is to
quickly upskill yourself and learn about
that and that's why you have tools like
obsidian now with claw code which is
also a tool that facilitates it solves a
problem what is the problem that you're
trying to solve well job uncertainty
okay what is the first step do I think
that I'm going to have a job in 2 years
time if I carry on working in this
industry maybe not so let's use these
tools in order to ideulate where I need
to change my direction into in order to
feel more stable in my career life and
it's so sad that we need to talk about
this
>> um
>> yes
>> it's
>> no so like I I I wrote a substack about
this right like I and like I was
reflecting on I I
like everyone right now every knowledge
worker right now there is this anxiety
that I mean for me I call it AI vertigo.
I feel like every every day every other
day there's like a new technology new
advancement in an LLM benchmark like
it's just non-stop right there's a new
tool that's coming up and I feel like
I'm falling behind. I'm reading a lot
about it. I'm falling behind. I don't
understand any of this and I've like
have this like sense of anxiety and
unease that's been kind of trilling me
like over the last year.
>> Yeah. And I would say like I I've only
been playing around with FCO for like
less than a month.
>> Yeah.
>> And now that I'm like playing around
with it, that anxiety actually turned
into excitement
>> because I'm actually using it learning
about it and then using it to learn
more. I'm solving problems and I now
understand what it is, right? And I
don't have a mirror ball. I can't say
like you know what job is going to
replace and whose like job what
profession is at risk but I think the
only way that we will actually address
our anxiety is by taking action by
playing with it by learning and trying
to understand it right that's for me
that's how I have helped address my my
anxiety and it's so satisfying it's so
so satisfying
>> yeah the only way that
you we basically get down to the point
of you need to learn how to use AI to
your advantage. So, you need to learn
how to wield it properly. And it's
scary, but it's also very we are very
lucky in
it's a double-edged sword or like it's a
it has cons, but it also has the pros.
The pros is whatever you want to learn,
you can now learn quicker, more
efficiently. So, these are tools for any
industry.
Basically the thing that you need to get
good at in the next what people say is 5
years you need to get good at learning
this is the perfect tool like this
combination is a very good tool for
learning anything quickly like you don't
have excuse that you oh I don't have
this experience I don't have this
knowledge like no you if you have the
setup it will make learning easier and
again more fun so
yeah if you're stressed just follow your
interests, get a a tool that assists
with learning and you are a for Wayne.
But we are we are digressing digressing.
We were talking about mind palace.
>> All right, I'll quickly show this and
then I'll go through the task manager.
>> So I basically want to again a visual
way to um basically remind myself of how
my second brain, my mind palace is being
structured. So I basically asked it to
go, hey, like based on everything that
we build, can you give me like a list of
all the log entry types that I've used,
right? Because I'm logging this
throughout my day, what emoji it uses
and when to use it. So it basically just
like sped out this table for me. And
then some rules that I need to remember
like it knows already through like the
skills that we developed, but then I I
myself need some reminders sometimes.
And so like it basically gives me some
of the rules keeping it very simplistic.
>> So you stopped it. So you said you need
to know it as well. Why?
>> I mean it's like I I don't want my my
second wing to be too bloated, right? I
want to make sure that I'm also keeping
to the conventions. So it's more sort of
like for me to remember like it's
>> like the the clock code takes off a lot
of that administrative things but
sometimes I'm like oh I need to remember
certain like you know certain
conventions that we did just so I can
prompt it well so like you know it's
it's for me right to understand my my
second brain
>> and then how Claude does the things what
it's doing so you still confined
you confine Claude and yourself to a
structure which makes the whole thing
runs run a little bit smoother and then
you also have basically your thumb on
the pulse of how everything is happening
which means that it won't just go create
its own rules without you understanding
what is happening because then you go
into the blackbox territory of oh this
thing is doing something but I don't
understand how so I think this is the
cool thing about
>> obsidian and cloud code is
>> you understand how the program works
because you built it
>> is just an application that you pay a
monthly subscription for. It is you
don't understand really how it works and
how it operates and you can't you you
you can't change anything
with that application immediately as
well. So I think this is a very
important point is these rules are as
important for you as it is for claude
code in order to restrain it in some way
and yourself in some way in order to not
let your system get bloated. So
>> yes.
>> Yeah, I also like it it helps with my
retrieval, right? Like if I want to look
up a certain note, I I mean I don't I
can use cloud to help me with that,
right? But sometimes I just want to like
find out certain things and because I
understand the structure, I'm able to
like very quickly retrieve.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And then so another thing I got to
do is basically my like all the
different areas of my life map out in a
chart. So basically like help me like
develop this so I understand how
everything sticks together. So my health
area all the different sub areas what
projects I'm working on.
>> So this was done
>> through CL through with how does it
visualize it also canva or is it
something else?
>> No this is a mermaid chart. So it's
basically like a a code
>> to the metadata by clicking down a
couple.
>> Yeah. So it's just it's a mermaid chart
that they basically like developed.
>> Okay. So that's cool. So Claude knows
that you have the Mermaid plug-in
installed. So it can use the mermaid
code in order to create that snippet
that we just saw that when you are in
reading or live preview mode in
Obsidian, it displays it in this way.
Which means that for every area, you can
ask Claude to go dissect your entire
system related to that area and give me
an eye overview of everything.
like the visualization which a lot of
people enjoy and they learn that way.
>> Yeah,
>> that's cool.
>> Yeah, I'm actually going to move this
into a canvas because I think a canvas
is a better way to to map this out. But
yeah, once I because I'm still
continuing to to build out this uh my
money palace. So once it's at a good
place and I want to like have a big
picture visualization, but this is my
first step. Yeah. All right. Are we
ready for the task manager?
>> Yes. Fun.
>> Okay. So, with the task manager, I
basically built like a task control
panel
where I uh I used the task plugin
>> within Obsidian. So, I downloaded the
task plugin and then I basically just
said, hey, like I want to uh structure
my task control panel with like these
six columns, right? because these are
the things that make make sense to me.
This is how I work. So I basically have
like a to-do panel. So what what I need
to focus on, what are the things that
are overdue, what are the things that I
need to do. So this is everything that I
need to do. And then underneath here I
have a discuss. So like during the week
like for with you right like I come
across certain things. I'm like hey I
want to like discuss this with you. I
want to show show it to him. So I
basically have like a discuss where I
tag you right in the note and then it
shows up here right and then followup is
like if I'm waiting on someone so I ask
someone to do something and then I need
to follow up with them then I basically
have it have it here and then inbox is
just my brain dump so like throughout
the day I'll just be like here's all the
things I need to do and so for anything
that is not in that is not mapped to the
the top five they're all showing up in
in in box. So, what I would generally do
is at the start of the day, I'll go
through all of these tasks and if I need
to say like, okay, well, this one I need
to do now,
>> I can just go in here and then I
schedule it for today and then it then
basically goes up to today. So, I know
that this is the the the things that I
need to focus on today.
>> That's cool.
>> Yeah. So, I'm like and then when I check
things off, right, I can just basically
come back and say, "Okay, well, what
else can I do today?" Right? you know,
it's just a control panel for me.
>> Yeah.
>> So, like I basically spent a bit of time
building this out and I cancelled my
to-do subscription cuz I don't need all
of the bells and whistle for to-doist,
right? I no longer need that. I can just
This is literally how I work.
>> Yeah.
>> This is how I want it to be.
>> And and then throughout throughout the
day, I would just like Okay, so for this
one, just like an example of the
workflow, right? Like I was doom
scrolling. You can see it's 12:00 a.m. I
came across this this Tik Tok and it's
about like these two teams that build a
a calorie tracking app and they
basically exited. My fitness pal bought
them for 40 million and my friend Ryan
is actually building something similar
and I was like, "Oh, I want to show it
to him at lunch." Right. So, I basically
just like did the whole I forwarded the
link to my Telegram and then I say
create a task to share this with Ryan.
Yeah. I'm going to have lunch and and
then when I come back here, I say
process scratch pad. It then basically
knows to process a note. Create the task
and then this task then pops out here,
right?
>> Uh well, here like Ryan
>> where did it come up?
Yeah, share. Yeah, this one. Share this
with Ryan tomorrow at lunch. So, yeah.
So, like it basically just like
I log it during my day and then it pops
up in my task manager. That is so cool.
You're giving me a lot of ideas to play
around with KBAN board as well cuz you
can very easily create something like
this if people prefer a physical note
task management system. So instead of
this which is the tasks plugin, you can
build something similar in KBAN with the
actual notes and also with the bases as
well. if you take the more of the note
rather than a single line for a task. So
this this because you can again optimize
it exactly how
>> yeah I I tried out a few kban plugin uh
but there's a bit of a learning curve
and I was like all right I and then I I
was basically conversing with claw and
I'm like can we try a kban like using a
common plugin it developed a few things
I didn't like the experience and so I
was like well why don't we just create
these columns right and then it
basically then did this but you're right
like you can just customize it in in any
way you want
>> and if you like it, you just change it.
So that's that's the the fun thing about
this. Something else that I want to say
now the
tasks. So for projects the way that I
think is when I want to work on
something I generally go to the project
and then from there I do the tasks. So
do you have a similar view on a project
page as well?
>> No, I haven't set that up yet, but I for
me it's more on a work session. So
within a work session, I may want to
like focus on certain tasks,
>> but I haven't actually built that out.
Like that's that's kind of like more
things that I can think of.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz what would be really cool is like
say like when I'm working on a work like
when I'm having a work session for a
particular project, I'm able to pull up
this and then basically just like select
the the related task. Let me see. Maybe
I have something.
No, actually I don't think I have
something built out yet.
>> But you've given me a lot of ideas.
>> Yeah, because it would be good to have
within your projects like a task list,
right? That is related to this.
>> I'm trying to see.
>> Oh, actually, let's see. cuz we have the
simplistic like oh tasks pulling in as
data view queries probably all the way
at the bottom.
>> Yeah, there we have the tasks. So we
have tasks, but it would also not be
that difficult to really like that log
color coding that pulls through like
this as well.
>> Cuz previously, sorry, sidetrack,
previously when I went to a project and
I would see all of these logs being
pulled through, it would be a little bit
confusing because it would just be a
wall of white text. And now with the
color coding, you can immediately see
like, oh, this is the next log. Oh, this
is what we did. Here's the work session.
Ah, it's so nice. Yeah, I think this
because this is what the most robust
project that I've had, right? Because
I'm building this and what's really cool
is with this log, it shows every it
keeps track of everything that I've done
related to second brain,
>> right? Like what I do is every time I
make an update to my second brain, I
create a work session and then I to like
capture all the things that were done.
So I have a trail of everything that
I've worked on and like it just
basically had this log that I that I can
just backtrack on like look at all this
like all the work sessions that I've
done. So, and this would have been a lot
of admin to maintain and there's a lot
of people that ask me
why do we need to create work sessions
or meetings? It just feels like admin
and like yes, but when I ask them
if you didn't have to do any admin
related to it, do you still have that
resistance? And some of the people say
yes, they like they don't see the point
in the work session. And for me, this is
the point. you have of how you completed
something from start to finish. Which
means that in the future
>> if you do something similar to this
project like let's say this is like
another type of project that has
similarities with a project you will do
in the future you now have every single
step you did in order to complete that
project which in itself is a higher
level of thinking. It is extracting the
processes that you have done throughout
that project that you can then reuse and
if you didn't have that you'll have
nothing you'll start from scratch again.
So this is
>> yeah this is something that maybe we can
talk about in like in in the future as
well like for me like I work session is
a game changer for me
>> right I I would have six seven projects
going on at the same time and it's I'm
context switching every every like every
day I'm context switching multiple time
right what I do is I create a work
session for me to actually scope down on
what I need to focus on right now so
like I have a two-hour talk. I need to
work on like this deliverable, right? I
create a work session and then I
basically pull in all the related
meetings, artifacts, content, whatever,
right? Like anything that I have into
the work session and then I use that
work session to say, okay, for this work
session, here's three things I need to
achieve. So, it's a to-do list, right?
And then I then spend the two hours like
really focus on just working on that one
thing.
>> Yeah. And because of work session
container, it really helps me focus on
what I need to focus on with all the
other contexts that that is related to
it. Super super helpful. And that's like
I mean like I need to protect my time,
right? Like it like I'm constantly
contact switching and this is the way
that I help that I found that it's been
really really helpful. I remember like I
was asking you in the first couple of
sessions like why do why are we doing
work sessions, right? But when it
clicked for me, I was like, "Wow, this
is this is really cool. It's amazing."
>> And that trail becomes so much more
powerful when you point an AI at it
because it doesn't have to go look
through all of your notes in your entire
system. It just needs to go through the
project and determine like, "Oh, here's
all the work sessions related to that
project." And then, oh, he's having the
next work session, so let's go and look
at the previous work session, which
would probably most relevant be most
relevant. and let's just be safe and go
look at a couple of other ones as well.
See if there's any tasks that we missed.
If there's any key steps that we had to
take and it pulls in everything with
links to the previous work sessions, it
automatically links everything by the
rationally. It's just beautiful. It's
really beautiful.
>> Yeah. Like if you look at like one of
these builds that I have, it basically
like it would take up the last session.
>> Yeah.
>> And basically just gives a work summary
all the things that we did.
Yeah,
>> that's nice. That's nice. Okay, so
that's the tasks
system. Thank you for showing that. Is
there anything else?
>> I can talk quickly talk through my
evening shutdown. Um, so
one of the things that I do is I have an
evening shutdown. Like this is basically
admin work, right? Like things that I
need to kind of file away. So what I do
at the end of the day is I just go in
here and I go evening shutdown. You can
see here evening shutdown and I when I
hit enter it does multiple steps. So the
first thing it will do is it will file
all my meeting notes basically like look
through like the trans square notes like
notes that I've taken in the meetings
and then it just basically files it in
the way that I want and then it runs
this evening shutdown thing where it
does three things. So I use Whoop for my
health tracking.
>> So it fires off an API to grab the um my
metrics and then it then basically logs
this into all these different fields
related to my data. It fires off another
API to my fitness pal and then it logs
these calories
>> the calories
and then I just basically
>> so I just want to say this quite cool
because you can now input a lot of
information from different applications
and again you might think that the API
call to these different things are
difficult you just ask claude like hey I
am thinking of pulling in this data from
this application walk me through it step
by step as if I'm a 5-year-old. And it
>> Yes, this is exactly what I did. I'm
like, I'm like completely new to this. I
don't know how to do this. And it just
basically gave me it built the code and
then it gave me the steps to set up how
to get my API. Uh what are like, you
know, basically like all the different
resources that's available. It was
incredible, really cool
>> as well is we are talking about claude
code in Obsidian, but you can also use
claude code just a little bit outside of
obsidian as well. It's not constrained
by Obsidian.
>> You can ask it
>> to build a health dashboard for yourself
outside of Obsidian. Basically, build a
completely new application and use my
daily data with all of these statistics
as the input and run that script once a
day and then you can see it outside of
Obsidian, the perfectly built health
tracking application exactly how you
want to see it. like that is the little
bit little bit more advanced use cases,
but I I don't want to say like oh it's
difficult because it's not. You just
have a conversation with Claude back and
forth until you see something.
>> So there's nothing that you can't do.
It's if you can think it, you can build
it. It's quite nice.
>> Yeah. And the next thing that I want to
do like when I do the weekly review
stuff is basically create like tracking
like visualize all of this data. Right.
So that's that's like the next step.
>> Cannot wait to see.
>> And then and then the final thing that
it does with the evening shutdown is it
reviews my entire day and then it gives
me a list of things to remember about my
day for me to review. So if it's a light
day, it pulls up about 10 entries. If
it's a heavy day, then it'll go up to
40.
>> And then I then basically go through I
at the end of the day, I will review
like all the things that happened just
to remember what what happened for me.
And then if it's something that I want
to remember, you know, for a longer
term, I basically bookmark it.
>> Yeah.
>> And then the the go the plan is to have
this sort of roll up in my weekly
review.
>> Uh CME Mini. So I recently bought a Mac
Mini for the open claw which is the
other AI personal assistant type thing
but claude code is getting quite good
that it can take over a lot of those
functionality.
So the value of a Mac mini is it's a
computer that's always on sitting on
your desk somewhere. You don't hear it
because it's so quiet but it's always
on. So your obsidian is going to run on
it. Your claw is going to run on it. And
then you'll essentially be communicating
to your knowledge management system
through your phone like WhatsApp or
Telegram. And because it's always on,
you have a direct communication channel
with your knowledge base. So if you
quickly want to ask a questions like,
hey, I remember a year ago that I
process this specific source which I
want to pull up now because I'm having
this conversation with a friend about
this specific topic. You tap it in in
WhatsApp to your Mac mini because it's
basically a server and then it would
respond directly. But you can do it now
already with the clawed code
>> because they claw code just released the
remote control, right? You can actually
remote remote into it. the the one thing
that I think open clock can do that
clock code still can't do is the
persistent because there's no cloud code
is you do one session and then you have
to kill like when you end it ends and
you have to restart a session right
whereas open claw is just persistent
it's just there and then it does this
heartbeat thing every I don't know how
many minutes
>> can do now as well since yesterday
>> oh yeah okay
>> they got new functionality So that's why
I'm saying we probably want to migrate
to Okay, this is like very geek talk,
but I'm going to keep this in cuz I like
to talk about this. AI is developing
very quickly. So you would have to have
some type of computer that's always
online. It's either a cloud-based
computer that you purchase or it's a Mac
Mini that is just always on in order to
keep your Obsidian open, your open floor
open, your Claude code open. So that's
just always there. So what Claude code
has gifted us yesterday was basically
the same functionality as openclaw but
the only restrictions is you need to use
anthropics model. So then you're
basically locked into one system which I
don't want to do. With open claw you can
choose which models you want to use. So
there's like still like a nice trade-off
but they're getting close and closer and
close to the same thing which is
>> the perfect personal assistant.
So
>> yeah,
>> Mac Mini Mac Mini is the way to go if
you want like an always on server
somewhere with your Obsidian on it that
you can communicate through your phone.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So I mean that's basically my
evening shutdown workflow that I've kind
of automated and yeah that's it.
>> Nice dude. Thank you for the showcases.
This is beautiful.
Maybe
yeah, let me share my screen and then I
can do an example of the weekly
processing.
>> Yes. Yes. I want to see because I
haven't actually built that out. I
that's like the next thing I want to do.
I I'm taking a bottoms up approach to
start off with daily logging. Next is
like, you know, the weekly roll up,
monthly, and then yearly roll up, which
I know like you have a really really
nice system.
>> Yeah, I'm still optimizing it, but I
think I have something that works well
enough right now. Okay, so we are in my
Obsidian now. Let me just open up my
clawed code
and our Claude code is running. So my
typical week, it looks very similar to
yours, especially now with the color
coding as well. So I just created a
dummy week for this example. So we have
three pictures. For me, it's just three
pictures of the day. They say pictures
are worth a thousand words. And it's
nice at the end of your year that you
can just see all of your pictures, all
365 days, just in one base table. To me,
it's just a nice way to relive your
here. So, I fill in three pictures of
whatever was interesting to me in the
day. With daily pages, I have these
different things. I'm not going to open
this cuz there's some personal
information, but my tasks, my very
simplistic task management system that
I'm definitely going to update after
this session notes created this day,
daily pages. This is just like previous
years.
Oh, cute. I went to I went to go play
with puppies on this there. That was a
good there.
But then we get to log pages. Well, I
have focus area to just to orientate my
day. And then I think our systems look
very similar. It's just logs. And this
is just I tell Claude to go full in. At
7:00 a.m. I went to the gym. At 9:00 I
was doing week planning. At 2:00 p.m. I
was working on this project. And then
this is also similar to your end of day
review. I have a similar end of day
review that just goes through everything
as well. and it just gives me this
little breakdown.
So, we do this for every single day of
the week. And this is where all your
work happens. That's why I preach the
daily notes first because if you fill in
every single day with all of this
information, you don't really need to do
much. Like that is the only admin is you
need to orchestrate your daily note. You
need to make sure that it's filled in.
You need to make sure that the metadata
at the top, the sleep hour, sleep
rating, healthy eating, you need to make
sure that's filled in. Whether it's
manual, and for me, I'm still doing this
manual, even though I also have a whoop,
which I also need to steal your process.
So, we need to have a discussion about
that as well. It's your responsibility
to make sure that the daily note is
filled in. And then you get to the end
of your week and that's where you want
to do your week processing.
So maybe a step back is typically on a
Monday. So if we go back to the Monday,
uh
which is the 4th, I would have a week
planning note. So for me this would be
the week planning and this would be
empty and I would just have my skill
activated which is week planning and
then it goes through the different life
areas and it checks what I did last week
and what is top of mind based off what
it knows about me and it would go fill
it in itself and then I have a week
schedule as well which it basically
breaks down every day what I need to do
if I have any consulting calls if I have
any meetings, if I have any social
engagements. And to me, this is almost
like a north star for a specific week.
Okay. So, weing,
>> you definitely want to do something like
that, too. Like like a look ahead of the
week, right? That's really nice.
>> Yeah. I only started to do this about a
month ago. And I always have it open on
the side panel.
>> Yeah. Like this is my personal week
planning, which I'm not going to open up
now, but I always have it open. And it's
so nice to when I'm sitting in front of
my computer and I'm not sure what I need
to do next, I know that this is always
going to be updated because I have my
Claude connected to my email and my
Google calendar as well, which means
that my Google calendar and my Obsidian
is basically talking to each other as
well. So if something pops up there,
>> I have skills that automatically pulls
in that information and automatically
adds it to my weekly note as well and to
my daily note. So whenever I open up
Obsidian, I know everything is in one
container, which I think a lot of
people,
me included, included up until last
year, we still have a lot of different
applications that we had to like, okay,
now I need to go to my emails. Now I
need to go to this website, now I need
to go to Google in order to search
something. Now I need to copy paste that
to ChatBT. And it's like all of this,
but now it's just your Obsidian
dashboard. Everything is inside of it.
It is beautiful.
Okay. So,
>> yeah, you can also have like a daily
reminder of things, right? Like every
day on a daily note, like what do you
need what do you need to focus on today?
>> Yeah, it's very nicely done. Yeah. I
tell you something cool that I saw from
a
tweet yesterday was a guy that have this
tweet using this heartbeats that Claude
have now that can do something every 30
minutes and
he had this thing of keep me on track
with my tasks for the day and remind me
every 30 minutes of my daily tasks. So
here on the fourth we have the focus
areas. So what he did is he basically
have like his focus areas for the day
and then every 30 minutes he gets Claude
to send a message saying why are you not
doing the most important thing? Why are
you wasting time? And I thought like
that is so cool. So what I built is I
built this guide which is Claude code
chron job recipes which is I have this
one the cron momentum mori focus check
and what this does is every 30 minutes
it looks at my daily note and asks me
what I'm doing right now it says to it
knows my number one priority and it
looks and it asks me if I'm working on
that and then it gives me a momentomory
quote which just reminds me of death
which just reminds me to not squander my
time.
>> Yeah. I mean, I used to have an app that
does this. Like I used to like set up
like this like ping I get a notification
on my mobile phone like I mean didn't
end up using it but you're like
literally building this within your
second grade which is so cool.
No. Yeah. Exactly. It's another
subscription that you don't need to pay.
And I I used this for the first time
last night. And it was so much fun.
There's a couple of times where I was
playing around with like a color coding.
And it detects that I'm doing color
coding because I have the the same type
of log that you have, which is okay. At
1400 I did this, at 1420 I did this. So
it has its own log of what it is doing
and I'm doing. And
with that, it knows that I'm wasting my
time on something that I should not be
doing, even though it like seems
productive.
>> Yeah,
>> let's use the
Oh, what are you doing right now? And
it's like gene dummy data working on
number one priority building dummy week
data for your YouTube something else.
>> Asking you to validate are you focus on
the most important? So dummy data this
week that we're going through null that
was my number one priority and let's
just say let's just say I'm working on
the dummy data
so normally it doesn't ask but then it
gives us something like this good you
are on your number one priority state
people are frugal in guarding their
personal property but as soon as
something comes to squandering time they
are most wasteful of the one thing in
which it is right to be stingy the clock
is running. Next check is in 30 minutes.
>> So cool.
>> I love that.
>> It's so nice just to get those
reminders. So I've been thinking on on
how I can make this a little bit better.
And my thought is
to at the beginning of the day just say
what I want to get done but then also
identify the tasks that is difficult for
me that is admin intensive that I can
feel that I'm almost hiding away from to
go look at those tasks and then to go do
research about the tasks in order to
give me like some type of like a easier
way to start with the task myself so
that I feel like oh I'm not starting
with it is starting with that that would
make it easier for me to go back to it.
>> So,
>> yeah, what you're talking about is I
mean it's it's human psychology, right?
Like it's actually very hard to take the
first step.
>> Yeah.
>> Once you take the first step, the
momentum then builds, right? And having
like a accountability partner like this
is really really powerful.
>> Yeah. I I was I'm always joking with my
friends that once I get filthy rich, I
am going to have somebody that lives
with me 24/7. That that person's task is
to wake me up at a specific time that I
want to wake up. That person's task is
to make sure that I'm in bed at 9:30 in
the evenings. That person task is to
like hit any junk food out of my hands
if it sees like the full accountability
partner. So, we're getting a little bit
closer with these tools that can assist
us a little bit more, but I'm
>> This is reminding me of Game of Thrones,
you know, like shame.
>> That is not a bad idea. I'm going to
build
like shame.
>> I'm I'm literally going to build that
technology into this like 30 minute
recap. If you see me doing something
else, just shame me because I learn with
I think I'm good with negative
reinforcements. Like, shame me. Other
people want positive reinforcements.
>> I'm all about the positive
reinforcement.
>> It's like the angel, the the little
demon at the bottom,
>> but you can tell it how you want it to
interact with you. So it's not like a,
oh, here's the program and like this
works for me. So I have a a squares
sized hole in my chest. So I'm going to
give this square that fits me to you
that have like a hole like a round hole
in your chest. Like it's not going to
work. But you can optimize it. You can
change it exactly how you want it to be
used, which is the fun part. Okay. So,
>> shall we go back to the week? Think
we're getting off track, but it's it's
fun. It's fun use cases we're talking
about. Okay. So, we spoke about the
week prep. We've gone through the entire
week. We filled in the pictures. We
filled in everything. Now, we get to the
end of the week. And this is what we met
with. We met with your weekly note and
no information is filled in. So
typically before well till end of last
year I would have to come to my weekly
review and say okay what was my week
rating I have to scroll down. Luckily we
have basis which made this a little bit
easier which pulls in all of these daily
data automatically. So we can see it's
starts Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday,
Thursday. It pulls in all of the
pictures. It pulls in the summary. It
pulls in the day rating. And then here
we can see the average. But then
typically I need to then go back to the
top and say the week rating was 0.86. So
this is not subjective. This should come
from our daily notes averaged by the
number seven and then lo health. These
are all kind of subjective but you can
teach claude how you think about this.
So for health if it sees that I did not
exercise, I did not eat properly, then
it's can give me its own score out of
10. And it's the same thing for wealth,
career, social, personal development,
leisure, environment. And then a summary
can also just be a summary of all of
your daily notes. Like there's no real
reason to do the admin of reflecting
yourself because you already done the
work on the daily note. So if we scroll
down, we can see our week planning note
and we have this chart that is not
filled in yet. That is just based off of
those metadata scores that we gave at
the top. Health, wealth, career, social,
personal development, leisure,
environment. So what we want to do at
the end of the week, we want to fill in
this information. We want to give a
summary and we also want a place where
we can reflect which is here. We want to
just write about what I like to do is I
like to go to my different areas. So I
like to make a heading for health,
wealth, career and just write out what I
did in that week. So if we go to
Claude and we say we pull up a skill
which is week review, we pull it in. And
for this one, because it's not the
current week, I just need to specify
which week am I talking about.
Otherwise, it's going to think I'm
thinking about the current week, not the
dummy week. So I put that in and it
starts to run.
So with this, it's
taught to go full in all of this data.
And another thing that I wanted to do is
to go look at the pictures and choose
the three
pictures that best represent my week.
And I do this the same for the month,
for the quarter, for the year, where I
try to distill like these are the three
main pictures for the week, for the
month, for the quarter. So that when I
get to my yearly note, I can look at
basically three different views or four
different views. The one is a big long
base with just all of my days like this,
but just 365 entries. Or I can open up
my monthly base, which is just 12
entries with the three textures that I
chose or the weekly base or the
quarterly base. And there's different
views to look at your year at the end of
the year.
>> Okay,
>> I love this. I mean like when I think
when I ca first came across your videos,
this was one of the things that really
like drew me to your your methodology
because
like we spend so much time just living
life and just letting life like time
just pass by, right?
>> This is basically having a system to
live your life, capture it, review your
life.
>> Now the capture thing back to the
administrative overhead, right? That was
just really, really hard to do. And so
now like you have the capturing the
administrative part is completely taken
away. Yeah.
>> So like the possibility of this like
you're living your life it cl the AI
captures it for you.
>> You then do your reflection and your
review and your creation like your
creativity. I think that is so powerful.
I love this.
It's It makes me think of an article
that I wrote at the beginning of the
year where we're talking about Yeti
reviews and why most people
won't complete their yearly review. And
>> the premise of this was basically it's
too much admin because the original way
of reflecting on a year is going through
your phone, your calendar, your images
of the entire year and then you're
trying to at one point in time try to
make sense of 365 days where a lot of
things happened. You're not going to
remember everything. You're going to get
like glimpses. But with a system like
this is it basically does the
remembering for you. So nothing slips
through the cracks. you can see the year
as it truly was. You have the actual
data about like what was this week's
rating
and
>> that's so cool. It just filled it all in
for you, right?
>> Can you talk about how it evaluates
those scoring?
>> This is a a lot of back and forth. So,
if we can see what it did,
let me update the weekly note with
everything. So
there's a a month ago when I started
with this process,
>> it would give certain ratings which I
would not agree with and then we'd have
a back and forth conversation about like
no I think this should rather be a six
instead of a nine. Here's the reasoning
for it and over time it comes really
close to what I would give it. So I
would still review the log week rating,
the log week wealth, the log week
career, and I would see if I agree with
this, but it's basically coming from, if
we just go down
the week summary,
this is basically the summary that it
gave for each of those areas. And based
off of this, based off of how I
instructed it to rate it, based off of
what I did, probably compared to
previous weeks as well, it would give
certain ratings. So for health, two
solid gym sessions. Sauna and ice bath
recovery day felt like a full body
reset. So it sounds like I did like
three things. So log week health is like
seven. Yeah, that's that's about right.
Wealth, no direct financial activity,
but workshop pricing locked at I didn't
really do much. So wealth is a three. So
if we scroll down to the charts, we can
see that these are the scores that it
gave it. And this chart is just based
off of the metadata all the way at the
top.
>> Yeah, I love this that wheel of life
thing. Yeah, cuz previously you have to
manually go in and change the numbers,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> So, the the most exciting part of this
whole weekly review for me is this graph
because it's just nice to look at and
it's also just nice because this is very
subjective. This is you choosing how you
felt with all of these life areas. But
if you continuously having a wealth that
is 2 3 2 3 1 zero, it means that you
should probably pay more attention to
it. If you are
>> for social like if it's only a one, you
know, like okay, maybe I should spend
more time there. So
>> also nice to have that
>> you not really choosing the initial
numbers. it looking at your daily notes
and deciding how it thinks your week has
gone.
>> Yeah, I actually like I I was talking
about how like in the beginning of this
year I was like I just have to do
something about this. I did an annual
review for myself and I basically did
this scoring and like my work is like 10
and then social is like probably about
five. M
>> my personal time and learning is very
very low and that was like I need to do
something about that's that's that's
what pushed me to contact you actually
>> that you had that frustration um
>> yeah but when you see it it's eye
opening right and then the whole concept
of momentum like life is short like if
you don't do something about it like
like I kind what what I had was I kept
on feeling like I thought that things
will change but I wasn't making any
actions to change it.
>> That's like literally the definition of
insanity, right? Expecting a different
outcome by doing the same thing. And so
I'm like, I have to do something about
this.
>> Yeah.
>> Makes me think of this heat map diagram,
which also just gives you an indication
of how you feel your days are doing. So
we I use the minus2 to two scale rating.
So minus two being the worst day
possible and two being the best day
possible. And to have something with the
data that you put into your daily notes
to have it visualized like this is very
pleasing to me. And
>> at the end of the year when you do your
yearly review when you have something
like this you have the base table which
if we go back to the weekly note
the base table is something that you can
sort by your day rating. So for all of
your days, 365 entries, you can sort
that your worst days pop up at the top
and you can go and analyze why were
those days bad and you can use that data
for something like this as well where
you have like okay I want to go look at
why this day was bad and I remember that
this day was the day that I thought I
had a very serious jiu-jitsu injury that
I tore my LCL and you can see the next
day is also just like me being a little
bit sad. And then the next day was the
day before flying back to Amsterdam
where I got my crutches and I was in a
wheelchair at the airport. And it's just
>> and this so powerful like just like I
mean I'm just thinking about all the
time I didn't do this
>> and all the memories that I could have
actually captured. Right.
>> Yeah. And there's something
it's the memories that you capture in
this way.
There's value. Well, there's the way
that I see it. There's two types of
value that comes from it. It's the one
is reminiscing and the others is
reflecting. So reminising.
>> Yeah. And growing from that reflection.
I think that's Yeah. I I 100% agree.
It's so so cool.
>> And then we go back to double loop
learning. So you have the information in
order to not make the same mistakes
again to improve your life a little bit
going forward. But what I use this for
as well, if we go back to the weekly
note in one of the days, when I open up
a daily note like this one, I can then
go to my daily pages and see previous
years on this day. And there would
typically be a photo with a friend or
family member. And immediately what I
would do is I would just take a
screenshot and send it via WhatsApp
saying, "Hey, this was a year ago." And
that's an automated way of connecting
with people again, people that's
important to you, people that you might
not have spoken to in a long time. The
other thing that I wanted to show you
was on the weekly note. This is cool.
So, it pulled in four photos
automatically.
And here it told us which photos
it chose. Four Legos, Chef Cooking, Run
Club, dogs, business office. And you
might wonder, how does it know which
photos to choose?
And typically what I would do, what I
would do at the end of the week is I
would have to go into that note, copy
that photo, come back here, and choose
it. And these like every day have three
different photos. Like this is just for
an example. So that's 7 * 3 21 photos
that you need to go okay these three are
important. But now I told Claude my
thinking process of how to choose these
photos. And my thinking process is
social engagements, photos with other
people in it, uh successes or highlights
and any new or novel experience. So when
I implemented this a month ago, I was so
surprised at it choosing exactly what
photos I would choose. I would literally
while it's processing, I would tell
myself I would choose the family get
together. I would choose the dogs. I
would choose the running event and maybe
uh an office win. And it would get it
right 99% of the time. So it's just
automating everything but in the way
that you would do it because you are
teaching it to think like you do.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's nice. It's fun. So I think
those are our use cases.
So this has been a 2hour chat
>> and I think we got through a lot of
information and I do think other people
watching this would find this quite
valuable in the sense of what can I use
these tools for cuz normally I have a
very dedicated video going deep on one
specific subject but I don't think I've
ever done one that's just wide reaching
and talking to somebody that has
recently gone through the process cuz
for me I've helped a lot of people to
set up the obsidian side and also to
integrate cla code and I feel I've been
using this for so long that I might miss
out on the the experience of somebody
new coming into this and the cool things
that they finding out along the way
which I found a long time ago which I
don't have that novelty associated with
anymore. I think it's nice to have these
conversations to talk about that initial
phases where you discover something. So
I just want to say thank you. This was a
really fun chat for me.
>> Yeah. No, thank you. Like this is this
has been really really fun for me too. I
think I mean I keep on thinking about
like why am I doing all of this, right?
Like why am I doing all this? Um I mean
just like the more I'm using it, the
more I'm finding it it's enriching my
life,
>> right? Like what's the saying like an an
unexamined life is not worth living?
Like that that hits pretty hard for me,
right? Like I
>> I just want to be like a a major player
in my own life.
>> Uh and this I just like just
implementing this over the last month
and really using it every day. I've
saved a lot of time, right? I I think
I've kind of become like before that was
I'm an administrator of like my second
brain. Now I'm actually an orchestrator
of my second break. So I'm like
basically orchestrating things make it
happen, right? And just and and then the
most important thing is it's a lot of
fun.
>> Like once this clicks, it's a lot of
fun. It's very gratifying. And so
yeah, it's been a really good
experience. I I'm like starting on this
journey. I am going to keep going. You
know, I'm hoping that, you know, we can
partner on some things together and this
is really really fun. Yeah. I think I
don't think this will be the last
conversation that we're having.
>> So, a quick note and this is probably
what we're going to end on is it's
cultivating. My claude code is thinking
and I think it's been 30 minutes since
the last momentum.
So, what are you doing right now? And
I'm going to say I am recording the
session and then we'll end with a
momento quote.
There's a version of you that dies
having never published this video. That
version also has a really clean script
with a great callback map. Nobody
watched it. So, it's just like it's
almost insulting me saying like this is
the person that I could have been if I'm
not doing what I'm doing or should be
doing right now.
So, Jean, thank you so much. Uh, I think
we'll definitely have a couple of other
similar videos because I find it very
useful and I think other people would
find it useful as well. So, yeah, see
you in the next one. Thanks, June.
Thank you.