Yet again, Enthropic just dropped
another feature that I think a lot of
people have been waiting for. Now, Cloud
Code, it can now control your actual
computer, your mouse, your keyboard,
your screen. It will take screenshots.
It'll figure out what is on your
display, and it'll just click around and
actually do things for you. Now, this
will work in both Cloud Code and Cloud
Co-Work, and it's available right now
for any Pro and Max users on Mac. But
here's where it actually gets
interesting is that you can pair this
with another feature called dispatch,
which this will let you text Claude from
your phone and it will do the work on
your computer while you're away. So,
let's say you're sitting down for lunch,
you realize you forgot to export that
report, you text Claude, it opens up the
app, grabs the file, sends it off. So
today I'm going to be showing you guys
how to actually set this up, walk you
through some real demos, talk about what
it's actually good at, what it can't do
yet, and a few use cases that I think
are going to be really practical for
anyone running a business or just doing
any sort of knowledge work. So let's get
into it. Here's the official blog post
from Anthropic. They're calling this
computer use, and it just went live
yesterday as a research preview. Now,
what's actually happening under the
hood? It's pretty straightforward. So
when you tell Claw to do something on
your computer, it will follow a specific
order. So first, it'll check if there's
a direct integration. Like if you ask it
to check your calendar, it'll just use
Google calendar connector because that
is faster and it's more reliable. Second
is if the task needs a browser, it'll
just use the quad in Chrome extension.
And third, when neither of those can
actually handle the job, does it fall
back to actually controlling your
screen. So taking screenshots, moving
the mouse, clicking buttons, typing, all
that stuff. So it's not just using
screen control for everything because
that would be a little bit more
expensive. So it's actually being
optimal. So that's just a design choice.
screen control. It would be the backup
option for things like any native apps,
internal tools, or anything that just
does not have a native API integration.
So, to actually turn this on, you just
need to simply go into your cloud
settings. So, I'm on the cloud app
currently. So, we'll just navigate over
to our settings. And from here, we'll
just scroll down to the desktop app
section. You can go to general, and you
scroll down, you should see computer
use. You just have to enable this. So,
it's going to give you a few
disclaimers, all that sorts of stuff.
And we'll just enable this. What I also
want to do is going to keep our computer
awake. This is going to allow us to make
sure that, you know, our computer isn't
going to go idle or anything. So, we can
actually use our cloud code instance on
the go and it's not going to go to sleep
or anything like that. Now, if you're
not seeing computer use, all you want to
do just close out your application. So,
again, I am using this inside of the
desktop app. And what you want to do,
just log back out, log back in, make
sure you're updated on the latest
instance, and you should be good to go.
You'll be able to see it. All right, let
me show you what this actually looks
like. So, I have this PDF. This is just
sitting in my downloads folder on my
computer. And I want Claude to actually
be able to send it as a DM to somebody
on Slack. Also be able to email it off
to somebody. Now, I don't have either of
those applications open right now. So,
I'm just going to go back to Claude. I'm
going to say use computer use to find
the client proposal PDF on my computer
and send it as an email to this guy and
DM it to Kave in Slack of a summary. So,
we'll run this off. Now it is worth
noting if you are running this for the
first time using computer use for the
first time it is going to require and
request a few different permissions. So
if you're you know asking it to access
your downloads access your local
computer you will have to first provide
it with those permissions. So if you're
asking it to go ahead go on Slack or
record your screen anything like that
you have to enable those system
settings. So you only have to do that
once. So right now it's asking to just
read for this. So I'm going to give it
permission. And next up, should be able
to be able to actually read the entire
proposal and then start sending the
summaries, connects to Gmail, and also
connects to Slack. All right, I've read
the proposal. It's a 73,000 10E AI
workflow automation engagement. Before I
send anything, here's what I'll do. I'll
email this guy and then I'll send the DM
over to Slack. Can I proceed? I will say
proceed. Let me create the Gmail draft
and then send the DM to Khave in
parallel. So right now it is just using
the connector. So it's not even using
computer use. So right now it is
recognizing that it already has a
connector. So it's going to be a bit
more efficient, bit more practical
because it's going to cost less tokens
to actually interact and use computer
use. Whereas the connector, it's much
easier and there's a better procedure to
actually be going about this. So let's
go ahead and check that. All right. So
you guys can see right here we have the
draft. Please find the client proposal
for Acme Corps operations team attached.
This covers the full 10E engagement. Let
me know if any revisions are needed. Not
check slack. Cool. So we can see right
here, hey Kjav, here's a quick summary
of the Acme Corp client proposal I just
sent over. So it's pretty much the same
thing as the Gmail draft.
Hypothetically, if Slack was not a
connector, same with Gmail, then that is
where it would be able to use computer
use and actually interact. Let me show
you where it's actually going to be
using computer use. And before we do
that, I have to introduce Dispatch. So
dispatch, this is going to allow you to
actually utilize Claude from your phone
while your computer is elsewhere. So if
you have not set up dispatch yet, just
go ahead, navigate to dispatch. It's
extremely simple. You'll just have to
scan a QR code or just log into Claude
on your phone and it'll be paired. It is
as simple as that. It takes maybe 30
seconds to set up. So, go to that now if
you have not already. So, what I'm going
to do is I'm just going to start a new
message and I'm going to paste in use
computer use to actually open up my
notes app on my computer and create a
new note summarizing today's meetings
for my Google calendar. So, let's send
that off. You can see I actually ran
that earlier, but we should see on our
computer that we will have this new
request. So, it's going to log that,
recognize the input. You know,
everything's going to be hands off. So,
you can see that I'm not actually
controlling my computer in just a second
where it will actually open up my notes
here. This is where my notes app is now
open. It says Claude is using your
computer. And in a second, it should
input everything, you know, the summary
from my Google calendar, which there it
was using a Google connector. So, that's
just something that's natively set up
inside of Claude. So, right now, it's
just inputting everything in here. So
here I have my morning routine from 8:00
to 8:30. This is recurring. I have my
team sync at 1:00 p.m. and then we have
a call later in the day. So awesome.
That is how we are actually utilizing
the computer use. Hypothetically if we
wanted to use it from our phone. So if
we're away from our desk or anything
else. So beyond what I just showed you,
I mean there's a thousand different use
cases that you can use this for. Lead
generation, lead research, lead
enrichment, whatever it may be. It
doesn't have to be regarding to leads,
but you can use this across departments
for so many different use cases. So,
just to expand and give you guys some
ideas, first one, client deliverable
prep. So, let's say you're just building
out an automation or a project workflow
for a client and you've got the proposal
doc inside of Google Docs. You've got
the scope spreadsheet in Excel and the
contract PDF in your downloads folder.
Now, normally you would have to spend
about 10 minutes just jumping between
apps, copying all that information,
reformatting whatever it may be. But
with computer use, you can just tell
Claude to pull the key numbers from the
spreadsheet, open the proposal, update
the figures, and then attach everything
to a single email draft. It will handle
all the app switching automatically for
you. Second is any overnight code
reviews with scheduled tasks. So clawed
code, it already has a scheduling
feature you guys may already know about
where you can just set prompts to run on
a chrome. Now combine that with computer
use. You can just set a task that runs
at midnight, pulls up your staging
environment in the iOS simulator and
then clicks through the core user flows,
screenshot anything that looks off and
commits a bug report to your repo before
you even wake up. Now third, and this
one is very specific to agency owners. A
lot of your clients, they're going to be
running proprietary softwares that has
zero API access. So you can think about
like old clinic like dental practice
management systems where they have local
accounting tools or any niche industry
platforms that were just built 15 years
ago. They're legacy systems. There's no
Zapier connector. There's no web hook.
There's no API documentation. There's
nothing. But those apps, they do have a
GUI. And now Claude can interact with
that GUI. So you can actually build
automations around software that was
previously impossible to integrate with
and that opens up a whole new category
of clients that you can now serve.
Fourth is competitor research on
autopilot. So you can schedule Claude to
open a local note-taking app every
single morning. Pull up three or four
competitor websites using the Chrome
extension. Screenshot their pricing
pages. Compile a weekly comparison dock.
And if you're running an agency and
tracking how competitors are actually
positioning, that is a task that a VA
may have well taken like 30 minutes to
perform. Now, it runs itself. And last
but not least, and again, like these are
not limited to just these use cases.
There's so many more that you can be
using this for. So, this is the one that
I actually keep coming back to and what
I have been using this over the past day
is let's say you're on a sales call. The
prospect is asking for a case study that
you know is saved somewhere on your
machine. So, maybe it's just a Google
Slides saved on your computer. So
instead of saying like, "Okay, let me
find this after the call." You can pull
it up right on the call. You can use
dispatch saying, "Hey, I need you to
find me this file." And then you can
present it, show it on the call because
you're going to have it in seconds. You
don't have to be digging and finding it.
Meanwhile, Claude, it will do all that
for you. Now, to talk about some
limitations of what you should know
before you actually get too excited
because there is some important
disclaimers. So, first thing, this is a
research preview. It works, but it is
not bulletproof by any means. Like
sometimes claude it will click the right
button from what I have found. Sometimes
it misreads the screenshot. It is early
enthropic. They are saying that upfront
and that is what I respect and
appreciate about them. Second, it is Mac
only right now. So it will come I'm sure
for Windows pretty soon but for right
now it's just Mac. And third, this is a
big one. Browsers are very limited. You
can't use Google Chrome. Claude can't
click around, type in Safari, Chrome, or
any browser through screen control. That
is a deliberate security decision. So
like web pages, they can contain hidden
instructions that could trick an AI
agent into doing something that you did
not ask for. So for any browser tasks,
you would have to use the claude in
Chrome extension instead, which is a
separate tool, or you could just
download a different browser. So I don't
know all the other ones available, but
it will not be Chrome, it will not be
Safari, all the big ones. You'll have to
look for a different third party
application, a different browser that
you will have to use. Fourth is the
financial apps and crypto wallets. These
are blocked by default. So you can just
add your own apps to the block list. And
I mean this makes sense. Like you do not
want an AI agent to be accidentally
clicking around your training platform
or your wallet. Fifth is computer use.
It runs outside the normal sandbox. So
usually when Claude works on files in
co-work
isolated virtual machine, but computer
use, it actually breaks out of that
where it's interacting with your actual
desktop. So you should think of it like
giving somebody remote desktop access.
So you have to be intentional about what
you actually let it touch. And this is
where it's a little bit more similar to
OpenClaw and where you might want to
have a different computer specifically
for this. So it's not going to mess up
all your files or anything like that.
And finally, this is only available on
Pro and Max plans right now. So it's not
on Teams or Enterprise. And the reason
is that activity from computer use, it
isn't captured in audit logs, which is
something that enterprise customers
would need for compliance. Now look, I
mentioned this is still early, but what
Enthropic just shipped here, it is
pretty clear signal of where things are
actually headed to. Like we're moving
past the stage where AI just writes text
in a chat. This is actually doing work
on your computer while you can go live
your life. You can pair that with
dispatch from your phone and actually
schedule tasks that run overnight and
you basically have a digital employee
that is always on for you. And for
anyone running a service business or
just an AI agency, like this is the
stuff that should be on your radar. the
use cases, they're only going to get
better as this moves out of the research
preview. Now, if you guys do want to
stay up to date on how to actually use
these tools in your business and
practical AI strategies to starting and
growing your business, then check out
our free AI newsletter. We upload weekly
sending you strategies on how to start
and actually grow your business and our
experience in the space. And before you
guys go, we are hosting a live free
workshop next Tuesday, breaking down how
we use AI inside of our three companies,
automating about 60 to 70% of our tasks
currently and how we've been
implementing AI, Claude Code, OpenClaw
for all of our clients and the results
that they have seen and how you can
actually do that for yourself, your
team, upskill your team, and install
Claude inside of your guys'
environments. So, if you are a business
owner and you're looking to either drive
leverage or increase your bottom line,
then make sure to check out and sign up
for that webinar next Tuesday. We'll be
covering all of that. You guys do not
want to miss it. But with that being
said, thank you guys for watching.