The newest AI models are the smartest
that we've ever had. They're also the
worst at telling you when they're wrong.
For those of you that are new here, hi,
I'm Dylan. I run an AI consultancy and I
use Claude, Chatbt, and Gemini every
single day across all my client work.
And the smarter these models get, the
more confidently they guess instead of
admitting that they don't know. Now,
this video gives you three prompt rules
that fix that. I'll walk you through
each one and give you the exact prompt
that stops the guessing completely. So,
let's get into it. So, this is the
challenge we're all facing. As new model
generations are released, its
intelligence increases, which is a
benefit. But the negative here is that
the more intelligent AI becomes, the
less likely it the less likely it is to
admit that it's wrong. So, its honesty
stays the same, its intelligence
increases, which causes the honesty gap.
And this is known by many researchers.
Open AI just published a research paper
on this exact topic. And that's just one
of two problems. So with this first
problem, we know as the intelligence
increases, the AI wants to please us and
it wants to give us an answer instead of
just saying it doesn't know. That's the
first problem. And the second problem is
actually you and me. That's what we call
automation bias. So what's happening
here is as the AI sounds more confident,
as its intelligence increases, we start
to trust it more, which means we check
its output less, which in turn causes
errors that compound over time. And this
loop feeds back into itself as the
intelligence gets smarter and smarter
and smarter. So if we don't add any
checks and balances here, there's a high
probability that we're missing stuff
that's critical for us not to miss. And
this challenge is something that all of
us will face. Here are just a few use
cases that I've seen this manifest when
working with clients. But it's important
to note this is just a small sampling.
This can happen and likely does happen
in hundreds of cases. The most common
category of task where AI guesses is
when you're asking the AI to pull
something directly from a source. So if
you've given it a report, an Excel
sheet, a contract, an email, whatever
else, you wanted to extract that
information and do something with it. In
the process of extracting that
information and giving you the answer,
it may infer things from its own
knowledge base, the internet or
elsewhere, and that might go against
what you actually wanted to do. Some
clear examples of this is say you have
the AI reviewing contracts for you.
Well, we're reviewing those contracts.
There could be two clauses in there that
talk about payment terms, but the AI
just picks one and gives you an answer
from that and ignores a second. Another
one could be a simple thing with meeting
notes. So, say you have a transcript and
you have the AI extracting action items
from that and it sees in the transcript
that somebody said, "Let's circle back
next week." From this, the AI may infer
that it's going to just choose a
specific date as well as give that task
to a specific owner. And sometimes the
AI inferring from the context is useful,
but most times you at least want to
check it. And there are many other use
cases that I've seen. So, extracting
information from invoices and receipts,
checking legal documents for insurance
and leases, scoring different vendors
against each other, building out CRM,
all types of things. Quick pause in your
regular programming. This video is
brought to you by me as always. So, two
quick things. First off, Blow is a
30-day AI insight series, completely
free. You'll get 30 insights in your
inbox so I can apply AI to your business
and your work. The second thing is if
you'd like to work with me, blow a
series of offerings to see if there's a
good fit from the two of us. Now, let's
get back in the video. So, we know the
challenge and we know where this
potentially could pop up. Now, let's
actually walk through the rules of how
we can mitigate this. So, the first rule
is forcing the AI to give us blank
answers when it doesn't know the answer.
And a common thing people mess up here
is instead of asking the AI to give them
nothing, they ask them to give me
something but give me a confidence score
associated to that answer. With this
approach, we're giving the AI another
out to lie to us. It could give us an
eight confidence score, but really it's
probably a zero. So, we don't want to
leave that up to AI. We want to remove
that responsibility from them and have
them just give us evidence. And the way
we're going to do that is we're going to
ask the AI to give us a blank value when
it's uncertain or doesn't know. In
addition to the blank value, it has to
tell us why it's uncertain. So, it has
to give us an explanation of why it
doesn't know the answer. This helps us
in two big ways. One is we can quickly
skim all the values, seeing the ones
that are blank, and those that are blank
we can check quickly. In addition to
that, by forcing the AI to explain why
it doesn't know, it gives us an easier
way to identify exactly where the error
is and fix it ourselves quickly. So
let's see what this looks like in
action. So on the left hand side we have
no rule. So this is using it without the
rule. And here we can see we're
extracting data from a contract. We have
payment terms, renewal date, liability
cap, etc. All the values been have been
populated by the AI. Now we have the
rule turned on with the prompt. And
instead of having all the values filled
in, we have a few different blanks here.
And these blanks have reasons as to why
they're blank. So for the payment terms,
we can see that the AI stated on pages 8
and 14, there are two different payment
terms, net 30 and net 45. That's why I
left it blank. So we as the user, we can
look at this and say, okay, we want
net30 or we want net 45. But we don't
have to have the AI decide that for us.
And the prompt here is simple to
actually enable this specific rule. It's
only a few lines. So at the very top,
we're stating that I want you to extract
the following fields from this document
into the table. So we're giving it a
purpose. Below that are the rules and
this is the important part. So the first
rule is stating that we can only extract
values that are explicitly stated in the
document. So this here is a concept
called grounding. So we're grounding the
AI in the source document ensuring that
it only gets information from here and
nowhere else. And after that we're
giving the AI an out. So we're saying
it's okay to give us no answer. So if
the value is ambiguous, missing or
unclear, I want you to leave that field
blank. In addition to leaving the field
blank, you also need to add a column
called reason. And next to those blank
fields, I want you to give a one-s
sentence explanation as to why you left
it blank. And then we add a last
reassurance at the bottom, reaffirming
that the AI should base every value on
what the document actually says, and it
should quote and reference specific
sections that it pulled from for that
blank section. So this is our first rule
in first prompt, where we're forcing the
AI to give us blank answers when it
doesn't know and explaining why it's
blank. The second rule is actually
changing the incentive mechanism because
currently the way the AI sees these
answers is it equates a wrong answer to
the same value as a blank answer. And we
want to change that. We don't want the
AI to think that these are the same
because if it does, it's likely going to
default to the wrong answer because it
wants to give you something. So to
change that, we're just going to add a
single line prompt that alters the
incentive in the AI's head. So instead
of saying this, we're going to say that
a wrong answer is three times worse than
a blank answer. And imagine if you have
a new employee and you hire them and
they want to please you and they want to
give you answers. Well, if you tell them
that if you give me a wrong answer, it
costs the company 3x more than a blank
answer. They're likely going to give you
a lot more blank answers than wrong
answers. The same thing applies here.
And this is the prompt. Like I said,
it's very basic. All we're saying is a
wrong answer is 3x more than a blank
answer. When in doubt, leave it blank.
That's it. That's rule two, changing the
incentives. The final rule is forcing
the AI to show the source. And we're
doing this because again we're fighting
a battle that the AI is constantly being
pulled into. So say we've given our
instructions here and the instructions
explicitly state that we want the AI to
extract only information from the
document and nothing else. Well, over
time as the AI is working on a complex
task, it will continually want to infer.
So it keeps getting pulled away from the
system instruction that we gave it and
it's wanting to go back to its old ways.
So when this occurs for rule three, we
want to have a safety net that catches
it. And that's what this third rule is
all about. Even when the AI wants to
avoid what we're asking it to do, we're
still going to have a safety net to
catch it. And here's the prompt for
that. So in this prompt, we're saying
that for each field, I want you to add
another column. So every field that you
extract, and that column is going to be
the source column. In the source column,
you're going to add one of two answers.
Either you're going to say the value is
extracted because you got it word for
word from the document like I asked you,
or you're going to say inferred, and
that's when the AI derived the answer
from the surrounding context, it
calculated something or interpreted
something itself. and for the inferred
column. So when you add this value, if
you do add this value, I also want you
to have an evidence column right next to
that that tells me exactly in one
sentence explaining what you inferred
from where. Now remember the reason we
have to do this, even though we've asked
the AI to only extract stuff and not
infer stuff and give us blank answers,
it will over time on complex tasks start
to infer. And when it does, we want to
have an out or a safety net to ensure
that when it does, it gives us an answer
as to why. And this is what it looks
like through an example. So say we're
still extracting information from the
contract. We have the field names that
we're extracting. We have the values and
then right next to that we have the
source. So the source is the information
I mentioned previously. So we have the
extracted, the extracted and inferred.
For the extracted, it has the evidence
column telling me exactly where it got
it from. For the inferred section, it's
telling me exactly what it inferred and
from where. So again, this makes it easy
for me to skim and validate the AI's
output. So instead of looking at
everything, I'm just looking at the
inferred fields. And that's our third
rule. But we're adding a safety net when
the AI decides to infer on more complex
tasks. And this is what it looks like
altogether. And as a reminder, the
reason we're doing this and we're adding
this to every single prompt that our AI
extracts information with is we're
reducing the burden on ourselves and
increasing our trust with AI because we
don't have to check everything it gives
us. Instead, all we have to do is check
the blanks as well as the areas where it
inferred. We can skim and approve the
rest. And I'll share this presentation
with you below in the description so you
can get access to this prompt and all
the subprompts. So you can copy and
paste this anywhere you like. Now, as a
quick recap of the three rules. So the
first one is we're forcing the AI to
give us blank information as well as
explain why it's blank instead of
allowing it just to fill in the gaps and
give us wrong answers. After that, we're
penalizing the AI and trying to change
the incentives. So we're telling it that
if you give us a wrong answer, that's
three times worse than just giving us a
blank answer of saying I don't know. And
finally, in rule three, we're asking the
AI to show the source. Because even
though we've stated we only want the AI
to extract information on complex tasks,
it will likely still infer. When it
does, we want it to show the evidence as
to why it did. So, it can quickly skim,
find the area that's been inferred,
check the evidence, and see if it's
right or wrong. And that's it. So, as a
quick reminder, two things. First off,
Blow is a 30-day AI insight series,
completely free. You'll get 30 insights
in your inbox so I can apply AI to your
business and your work. And the second
thing is, if you'd like to work with me,
Blow a series of offerings to see if
there's a good fit between the two of
us. So, these prompts handle accuracy,
but accuracy is just one piece of using
AI well. I mapped out four levels that
every AI user moves through. Most people
skip to the end, and that's exactly why
they stall out. I'll show you where you
are and what to focus on next in this
video right here. So, go ahead, click
that video, internet. Click it. I'll see
you next time.