So, if you've been using claw code for a
while, you'll remember the old problem.
The output was never good enough. You
had to babysit everything, and you'd end
up telling it to fix its own mistakes.
But now, that's completely changed. Now,
the agents are actually good. They can
run full tasks. They can handle real
workflows and get surprisingly close to
what you want. And that's created a new
problem. You've got multiple agents
running at once, five terminal tabs
open, and you're clicking between them
trying to remember what each one is
doing. So every time you switch, you're
losing context. And it's not claw code
that's slowing you down anymore. It's
the way that you're using it. So I've
spent the last 3 or 4 months building
full business systems inside claw code,
running multiple agents in parallel,
managing my business using it. And this
is the bottleneck that nobody's talking
about. So I went out looking for a
better way. And I tried everything.
T-Mox, the desktop app, Vibe Camban,
Paperclip, and they all have the same
issue. They're all built for developers
managing code, not for business owners
managing goals. So, I decided to build
something different. And in this video,
I'll show you what's out there, why it
doesn't work, why it breaks down, and
the command center that I built that
actually fixes it. So, let's get
straight into it. And first, let me
paint a picture of what's actually
happening. So, you're going to start a
Claw Code session. You're working on
something, whether it's a content
system, a lead genen workflow, whatever
it is. Claude is running, doing its
thing for, let's say, 5 to 10 minutes.
and your mind starts wondering. So, you
decide to start another task. So, you
open up another terminal tab and then
another one for the next task. And
before you know it, you've got five
terminals open because that's the max
you can handle. And you're clicking
through them all going, "Which one was
building my landing page? Which one was
doing my research?" And this is the
thing that gets me. Claude Code has
honestly gotten so good at doing the
work autonomously. The agents are
faster. They're smarter. They can handle
more complex tasks without you having to
watch them. We can run them on auto mode
most of the time. But our interface for
actually managing those agents has not
changed at all. We're still flicking
between these terminal windows. And you
guessed it, every time you switch
between the terminals, you have to
reread what's happening. You have to
figure out where things are at. And all
of that mental overhead does genuinely
add up and it slows you down massively
and stops you from doing other tasks,
which let's be honest is why you wanted
to actually use claw code in the first
place. So the problem isn't claw code.
The problem is that we need to abstract
one layer higher. So we need to start
managing goals and tasks not managing
terminals. So naturally I went looking
for solutions online and there are
actually quite a few options out there.
So let me walk you through what I found
and these can be pulled into kind of
five main approaches. So option one is
T-Max. The first thing that most techled
clawed code users or developers try is
T-Max. And if you don't know what that
is, it lets you split your terminals
into multiple panes. So you can see
several claw code sessions running at
the same time. You can see multiple
agents working side by side and have a
chat to those individual agents in one
window. But it still has one major
limitation. You are still in that
terminal. You can't see the big picture
and you can't drag tasks around. You
can't see progress at a glance. You're
still just having a chat interface
conversation back and forth. And then
when you start to think about passing
this to a client, imagine passing that
to your non-technical client and asking
them to manage the agents that you've
implemented for them. So then on the
other end of the spectrum, we have
Anthropic's own desktop app. And
honestly, the UI is really nice for this
and it's improving all the time. It's
clean and it gives you a proper chat
interface instead of that terminal. But
there are two problems with it. First,
setting up things like environment
variables and MCP servers is harder in
the desktop app than it is files in your
terminal. In the terminal, we literally
just add av file with our keys or a
settings.json file. And second, this is
the big one, you're still managing one
conversation at a time. You've got a
nicer window, but it's still one window
and you're flicking back and forth
between your conversation topics to
actually get those individual tasks
done. You don't have that abstracted
higher level view. Now, this is where it
gets really interesting. Vibe canban is
a canban board designed specifically for
managing coding agents. So, you can
create issues, drag them into in
progress, and it automatically spins up
separate claw code sessions. And the UI
is genuinely very nice. But this is the
key thing. It's designed for developers
who are managing code. So it talks about
GitHub commits, pull requests, branches,
diffs, and if you're a software engineer
orchestrating coding agents, that's
brilliant. But if you're a business
owner who just wants to say get this
goal done, it's too much for your use
case. And then if you want to abstract
one level higher, we've got paperclipip.
So paperclip is an open-source
framework, and you can think of this as
an operating system for running an
autonomous company. So, it's set out
like a traditional company. You create
org charts, assign roles like CEO, CTO,
and set budgets for specific roles. And
conceptually, I get where this is going,
but in practice, it's way too much for
most of us. You don't need an org chart
to write a LinkedIn post and build a
landing page. You just need to get jobs
done faster. So, Paperclip, although it
looks brilliant, is solving a problem
that most of us don't even have yet
because we still want to manage those
outputs. And then there are tools like
claude code board claude code task
viewer open clause mission control and a
bunch of others and some of them are
really polished but again they're all
oriented around coding sessions code
review developer workflows technical
users only. So every tool out there is
solving the same problem. How do I
manage multiple coding sessions? But
that's not actually the problem for
business users. Their question is how do
I manage multiple business goals? let
Claude code figure out the rest for me,
but still have a handle on and maintain
and supervise the outputs. And this is
the gap that none of these tools fill.
So, let me explain what it's actually
missing. Every tool I just showed
started from the bottom up. So, they
start with the session in the terminal.
They start with the code and then they
try to add a project management layer on
top of it. But what we actually need is
the opposite. We need to start from the
top and work our way downwards. So we
need to start with the goal like I want
to build a lead generation system and
then let the system figure out what
sessions to spin up, how in-depth the
planning should be, how many agents are
needed, what skills to use and how to
get it done, i.e. all the technical
overhead. And it's much like hiring a
competent employee. You give that
employee a goal. You say, "Here's the
deadline. Go and figure it out and
update me when you've made some
progress." That's the level of
abstraction as business owners that we
need. And there's also one more thing
that none of these tools handle at the
moment. None of them have the operating
system in the back end that stores your
business context, your brand voice, your
client details, your content strategy,
your target audience. None of these
camban tools show anything about your
business. They're just managing coding
sessions in a complete vacuum. So, what
we need is a tool that thinks in goals,
not sessions. It knows your business
context and lets you manage everything
from one place with minimal interaction
with the terminal. So, that's exactly
what I built. So, let me show you the
command center. So, it sits on top of
the Aentic OS that we've built out in
previous videos. So, quick recap if
you're new here. The Aentic OS is your
entire business brain living inside
Cloud Code that you can spin up in just
10 minutes using our plug-and-play
templates. So, it contains your brand
voice, your content strategy, all your
ICP details, and it's all connected
through skills that actually work
together with memories of what you've
previously worked on. Now, the core idea
of the command center on top of the
Aentic OS is really simple. Instead of
managing terminal interfaces, we're
going to be managing our business goals.
So you can think of this as a sort of
canban board for your business. But if
we have a look at traditional canban,
you'll see why it's different when we're
considering not human workforce but a
genic workforce. So say we have the
traditional canban board here. We have
not started and we want to actually
create a content repurposing system for
our business. So we would then push the
task to Claude. Claude would then start
the task, do a bunch of research, spin
out some subtasks. They'd appear in this
view here. Claude would then take on the
subtask. We might at some point get to a
point where we have to review the
outputs. So it pass it to the review
stage. This is very sequential at this
point, but actually the way that we
operate with agents and claw code is not
sequential. It's actually iterative. So
the next stage would be I give feedback.
Claude goes back into progress. Claude
does some more work. It then gives me
back for review, back to Claude, back to
me. You see how it's so iterative like
this? So what we've done is just
extracted the iterative nature of the
clawed conversation and actually built
it out into our own canban board. And on
the left hand side we've got our turn
which is all the stuff that we need to
review. And you can see we're stacking
different tasks, different goals on the
your turn here. And on the right hand
side we have Claude's turn. Now you'll
notice here it's not a coding canban
board. You've got your goals, your
active task, what's in progress, and
what's done or been achieved. Down here
we've got the scheduled task. We've got
the recent outputs and the history and
we can separate it per client. But none
of this talks about GitHub commits, pull
requests, or anything technical. This is
all about managing business goals. But
we're doing that through effectively
different tasks which spin up different
agents in your terminal. And all we need
to do is describe our goal. So we can
use some of the plug-and-play commands
here as part of the agent OS or we can
come in and say build me a content
repurposing system for my YouTube
channel. We can decide what permissions
to give it. The default permissions that
we've already assigned in settings.j or
JSON or the fully automatic i.e.
dangerously skip permissions. And then
we can give it a level of task. So is
this a quick task? Is it a campaign with
multiple deliverables where it has to
break out subtasks or is this a deep
build where it needs to go into way more
detail with the planning? We're going to
hit quick task for this. Send it to
Claude. And you can see it's now in
Claude's queue. So this is spinning up
an instance inside Claude that we can
actually click inside and see the
activity as it built out with Claude. So
we can see the full logs of exactly what
Claude is doing inside this conversation
history of the goal that we're trying to
achieve. So Claude's going to work out
exactly what planning level is needed
for that given task. It's going to come
back to us seeking feedback where
required and it's going to use the
skills that we've got built into the
system which we'll come to. and it's
come back to me because it's reflected
on all of the memory that it has inside
the history of the repository and said
before I scope this out further are you
looking to expand beyond newsletters or
is this about refining or fixing the
newsletter system from yesterday so it
understands that yesterday we input
exactly the same task to build out this
content repurposing system and is
starting to build on that memory
yesterday we can see the full
conversation history or just actually
reply at a glance without needing to see
and scroll through all the conversation
history for demonstration I'm going to
mark this one as done and it will pop
into the achieved or I can drag it down
here and we basically move that into
already completed to close that terminal
session. Now if we look at an example I
created earlier when we click into a
task we've got a full view of the last
two messages between us which are the
most important messages cuz it's what
information did I give Claude? What
information did it give back? So this is
about a LinkedIn post on claw code and
codeex. And what I want to point out
here is not only can we reply and
actually use our built-in commands like
we can in claw code add our attachments
but we can actually see all of the
outputs in one place that it's produced.
So if I wanted to see this LinkedIn post
I could effectively look at this preview
and actually scroll down and see this in
a markdown preview and then take that
either download it directly here or take
that directly to LinkedIn. But what
we're not doing is actually going
through and just having a standard
conversation with Claude. What we're
doing is managing six plus tasks at a
glance from this dashboard and able to
actually get that summary view inside by
clicking on each task. You can see the
deeper builds have full phases that
we're able to execute with many many
files that link to those phases. If
we're working across multiple clients,
then we might want to see just the tasks
or the files in that client and what's
been achieved. or we just want to see
across all of our projects what tasks
are we looking to manage and at a glance
we can see all scheduled tasks that
we've built i.e. we have a monthly
learnings health check so it checks all
of the learnings and all the feedback
that we've given it and consolidates
that every month we have a weekly
activity digest and a skill update check
that runs at 9:00 a.m. every single day
to make sure that our docs are up to
date with all the skills that we've
installed. And then down here we have
all of our recent output. So, at a
glance, we can see without having to go
into the individual tasks, all of these
MD files and actually click into, let's
use the LinkedIn post as an example.
Click into and see the preview of the
markdown down here as well. So, you're
able to totally abstract away from the
terminal here and manage a series of
tasks that flick between your turn and
Claude's turn in this canban style. Now,
this is definitely still under
construction, by the way. It's not
perfect yet, but it's becoming better by
the day, and we're going to launch it
for all members in the community in the
next week or so once we've ironed out
the bugs. And we've already alluded to
this, but not only do we have this feed,
which gives us an overview, but we've
also got scheduled tasks. So, in Claw
Code, we can actually interact with your
Mac or your Windows machine and run
things on a schedule. So, you can set up
tasks that fire every single morning,
every week, every month, whatever period
you want. Say for example our skill
update check. We can see at last round
one day ago there was a success message
and we've got a link to the output file
here which gives us a log of exactly
what happened. Now we can test run
these. We can activate and deactivate or
we can actually delete them directly
from here and that will affect the
underlying files in our VS Code at the
base. Now next up we've got skills
management. And this is something I'm
really excited about because you can see
all of your skills in one place. So not
buried in different file folders
somewhere. They're right here. So you
can search through the skills. You can
see we've got 21 skills installed. You
can search through the skills by
category and see exactly what those
skills are and actually modify them from
the interface. So if we go into our
copywriting skill, we've got the
skill.md file, but also we can see all
of the reference files in there. And
what we can do is actually go in
directly and edit this markdown inside
here. And that will affect the
underlying file. And every time now the
skill runs, those changes take effect.
But you can see how this directly
compares to actually looking at this
exact skill inside the VS code terminal.
So we go into doclude skills the
skill.md file and then we have this
markdown that's quite hard to visually
understand and read versus the markdown
that's actually rendered on the site. We
can make a change and it will update it
directly. And just to prove that I'm
going to save this to test markdown
copywriting test. And you can see that
that's immediately rendered in here.
Marketing copywriting test. and we'll go
back to all skills. Now, the important
thing here is we've got a meta skill
creator built in that builds on
anthropics skill creator and adapts
skills to fit this agentic OS. So, what
we can actually do is use that in the
add a skill and we can either put like a
GitHub reference to a specific skill we
want to emulate or just give it a
description or upload the skill directly
and what that will do is use the skill
creator to create that new skill inside
here. And then let's not also forget
about the documentation. So when you're
writing out your claude.mmd, your
readme.md, all your brand context where
we store things like your community
links, your personal links, your YouTube
handles, stuff you use again and again
are all saved into this system. And
we've built this out in a similar way to
OpenClaw where we've got things like the
sold MD which feeds into how the agent
works every single day with your tasks.
And again, all super easy to edit and
manage from this dashboard. And this is
all done on a per client basis. So if I
go back to the feed and filter by client
one that has no brand context set up,
then the docs are going to be relevant
for client one only. So you can see
there's very few docs available for
client one, but they still have access
to all the skills which are installed at
the root level. We can switch back to
root and see all of the tasks that are
remaining. So that is the command
center. You can think of this as one
dashboard where you manage your goals
instead of terminals. And like we said,
we've got the business context built in.
We've got scheduled tasks being built,
all your skills management, your docs,
multi-client support, and it's basically
a way to work at a higher level and get
more done faster without ever needing
you to flick between multiple terminals
as a business owner. So, let me wrap
this up. The terminal was actually fine
when we were running one claw code
session at a time. But agents have
actually got so good and they can handle
so much more that now we need to
abstract one layer higher to be able to
actually leverage the productivity
gains. And whether you use one of the
tools I showed you like Vibe Camban or
Pulsia or whether you build something
custom like the command center for
yourself, the point is still the same.
We need to stop managing terminals and
start managing goals to improve our
outputs. So if you want to see how the
Aentic OS works under the hood for
powering this command center, then watch
this next video or grab the whole system
including the command center in the
academy link in the description. The
command center first version is
launching next