Anthropic is testing a new always claude
agent called Conway that can stay
active, react to triggers, and run in
its own environment. Z.ai just launched
a screenaware vision coding model built
for openclaw and clawed code workflows.
And Alibaba dropped Quinn 3.6 plus with
1 million token context aimed at serious
agentic coding and full real world
deployment. All right, let's start with
Anthropic. They're testing Conway, which
looks like a completely separate
environment built around Claude, almost
like its own operating system for AI
agents. Instead of opening a normal
chat, Conway shows up as its own sidebar
option. And when you click it, it
launches what their internal code calls
a Conway instance. That wording alone
already tells you this isn't a session,
it's something persistent. Inside that
environment, you're not just chatting,
you're dealing with a full agent
workspace. It has its own interface with
sections like search, chat, and system.
Chat works like you'd expect. Search
seems tied to experimental hotkeys. And
system is where things get interesting
because in there you can actually manage
the entire Conway instance. There's an
extension section where you can install
custom tools, add new UI tabs, and even
define context handlers. And the format
they're preparing for this is something
called CNW ZIP files. That basically
looks like Anthropic building its own
extension ecosystem similar to an app
store where developers can package tools
specifically for this environment. And
that changes the game because now Claude
isn't just a model you talk to. It
becomes a platform that other tools plug
into. Then you've got connectors and
tools. The system shows connected
clients and what tools they expose,
which means Conway can integrate
directly with external systems. There's
even a toggle that lets Claude running
in Chrome connect straight into Conway.
So now your browser becomes part of the
agent loop. And this is where it gets
serious. There's a full web hook system
built into Conway. It gives you public
URLs that external services can call and
when that happens, it wakes up the
agent. That means Conway isn't waiting
for you to open it. It can sit there in
the background, get triggered by events
and start working. That's basically an
always on agent model. This lines up
perfectly with what Anthropic has been
doing with clawed code and agent
workflows, especially with that epitaxi
interface that was spotted earlier.
There are references to epitexi inside
Conway, and it looks like that might be
the control layer for managing these
agents. So, you can start to see the
direction Claude is essentially turning
into an always running operator that
lives in its own environment. And that
puts it directly in competition with
things like OpenClaw, except Anthropic
is building it natively with deeper
integration into their own models. At
the same time, they're improving the
developer experience on the ground
level, too. Claude Code just introduced
no flicker mode. And this actually fixes
a problem that's been annoying people
for a long time. If you've ever used
terminal based AI tools, you've probably
seen the flickering, the jumping
content, and the way performance starts
degrading during long sessions. This new
mode replaces the traditional rendering
approach with a full screen buffer.
Similar to how tools like Vim or HTOP
work. Instead of constantly rerendering
everything, it only updates what's
visible. That removes flicker completely
and stabilizes CPU and memory usage,
even during long conversations or
multi-agent workflows. And they added
something unexpected on top of that.
Full mouse support. You can click to
position your cursor instead of using
arrow keys. You can expand tool outputs
by clicking. URLs open directly when you
click them. File paths open in your
editor. You can drag to select text and
it automatically copies to your
clipboard. The scroll wheel works
smoothly for navigating long histories.
Even selection behavior got upgraded.
Doubleclick selects words. Triple click
selects entire lines. And in terminals
that support advanced protocols like
Kitty or Weserm, control + C copies
instead of cancelling selection. So now
the terminal starts behaving more like a
graphical interface which lowers the
barrier for developers who don't want to
deal with pure command line friction.
You enable it with a single environment
variable cloud code no flicker equals 1.
Or you just add it to your shell config.
It came in version 2.1.88
still experimental though most internal
users already prefer it. There are some
trade-offs. Native search shortcuts like
command plus F might not work the same
way and some behaviors need adjustment.
Though overall this is a clear move
toward making AI coding tools feel
smoother and more stable during real
world usage. Now while Anthropic is
pushing deeper into agents and developer
tools, ZAI is coming at this from a
different angle. They just launched GLM
5V Turbo and basically it's an AI model
built to look at what's on a screen and
understand it well enough to help do
real work with it. That's the key idea.
A lot of AI models can look at images. A
lot can write code. The hard part is
getting one model to do both well at the
same time. Usually, one side improves
and the other gets weaker. A model might
be good at describing what it sees,
though struggle to turn that into useful
code or actual actions. Z.AI AI says
this model is built to handle both
together. So instead of looking at a
screenshot, turning it into a rough text
description and then reasoning from
that, GLM 5V Turbo is supposed to
understand visual input more directly.
That includes images, videos, UI
layouts, design mockups, and dense
documents. And that matters because real
work usually does not arrive as clean
text. It shows up as a broken screen, a
messy PDF, a weird layout, a bug
screenshot, or a recording of what went
wrong. Under the hood, yes, there's real
tech here. Zai says it uses the Cogvit
Vision Encoder to preserve fine visual
detail and layout structure. And it also
uses MTP or multi-token prediction to
improve speed and handle longer outputs
better. In simple terms, it's built to
see clearly, think faster, and stay
useful when the task gets bigger. and
the tasks can get big. The model
supports a 200,000 context window, so it
can handle huge amounts of information
at once, including long documents, large
code bases, and extended visual or
video-based workflows. ZAI also says it
trained the model across 30 plus tasks
at the same time. That includes STEM
reasoning, visual grounding, video
analysis, and tool use. The practical
point is pretty simple. They're trying
to make it good at the whole chain, not
just one piece of it. So instead of an
AI that only recognizes what's on a
screen or only writes code in isolation,
they want one that can look at
something, understand it, figure out
what needs to happen next, and help
carry that out. That's why it's being
pushed for agent workflows. It's
optimized for OpenClaw, so it can work
through real visual environments, help
with setup, analyze what's on screen,
and move through tasks that look a lot
more like what people actually do on
computers. It also works with cloud
code, which means a developer can show
it a screenshot of a bug, a broken UI,
or a rough feature mockup, and the model
can suggest code based on what it sees.
That's a much more natural workflow
because that's how people actually work.
Sometimes they do not write a perfect
technical explanation. They just point
at the screen and say, "This part is
wrong." Z.AI is also pointing to
benchmarks like CCbench, V2, Zclaw
Bench, and Claw Eval. Those are tests
for multimmodal coding, agent tasks, and
multi-step execution. And according to
the company, GLM 5V Turbo is hitting
state-of-the-art on the tasks where the
AI has to both understand visuals and do
something useful with them. So, this is
part of a much bigger shift. AI is being
trained to deal with screens, layouts,
apps, and messy workflows, then turn
that into action. And right as that
trend is speeding up, Alibaba just
dropped Quen 3.6 Plus. And this one is
really about turning all this agent talk
into something businesses can actually
use. Alibaba says it's built around a
full capability loop. Meaning the model
is designed to perceive, reason, and act
inside one connected workflow. So
instead of just answering and stopping,
it can break down a task, work through
the steps, test things, refine things,
and keep moving toward a usable result.
That becomes especially important in
coding. Alibaba says Quen 3.6 Plus is
built for repository level engineering,
which basically means it can work across
an entire project, not just one code
snippet at a time. So, it's meant for
bigger, more complete tasks across a
full codebase. And then there's the
biggest number in this launch. Quen 3.6
Plus comes with a 1 million token
context window by default. That is
massive. In plain language, it means the
model can keep far more information in
view at once. You can feed it huge
documents, giant code projects, multiple
files, and long instruction chains
without it losing the thread nearly as
fast. That matters a lot for agents
because agents need memory. They need
room to track what happened earlier,
what files matter, what tools were used,
and what still needs to be done. Alibaba
also made this more aggressive by
putting a preview version on open router
and at least for now giving people free
access with that full 1 million context.
That opens the door for a lot more
developers to actually try it. Under the
hood, Alibaba says the model uses an
improved hybrid architecture that boosts
efficiency, reduces energy consumption,
and improves scalability. It also says
reasoning and agent behavior reliability
are stronger than in the 3.5 series. And
this is clearly aimed at real
deployment, not just flashy demos. Quen
3.6 plus is going into Alibaba's own
ecosystem, including Wukong, which is
its enterprise platform for automating
business tasks with multiple AI agents.
It also works with OpenClaw, Claude
Code, and Klein. So, it fits into the
agent workflows people are already
building. On the multimodal side,
Alibaba says the model can handle dense
document parsing, real world visual
analysis, and long video reasoning. It
can also look at interface screenshots,
handdrawn wireframes, and product
mock-ups, then turn those into working
front-end code. So again, you can see
the pattern. The whole industry is
moving away from AI as just a chatbot
and more toward AI that can stay inside
a task, react to what it sees, and keep
working. Anyway, I'm curious. Are AI
agents really going to replace apps or
is this being overblown? Thanks for
watching and I'll catch you in the next
one.