By the end of this video, AI Claude Code
specifically will be able to do things
inside your GoHighle account. Claude
Code is going to pull contacts, read
your conversations, move pipelines and
deals, and post social media content
along with some blogs all from a single
sentence that I'm going to type. No
Zapier, no API calls, no thirdparty
middleware, just cloud code talking
directly to your GoHighle account
through something called an MCP. We're
going to set up this in four steps.
First, we're going to create a secure
token inside of Go Highle. Then, we'll
grab your location ID. Then, we'll drop
one config block into COD code, and it
takes about 30 seconds in general. And
then, we're going to be able to test it
live so you could see it actually
working. If you use GoHigh Level and
you've been building in Claude and been
using agents inside of Claude Code, this
is going to be the setup you've been
waiting for. So, come along and build
along with us.
This means your AI can manage your CRM
while you sleep. No manual data entry
and no app switching. So now let's go
into model context protocol. These are
the official goh highle documents that
you see and inside these documents
you're going to see the highle MCP
server. Now all the instructions are
actually here to connect and believe it
or not it's going to make it fairly
easy. Now all I have to do technically
is give our AI these instructions and it
should be able to figure it out. The
second thing I want you to know is all
the different things it can do. All
these different things are called
endpoints and they're basically things
that are allowed right now through the
MCP server through the official Highle
MCP server that will allow you to do all
these things. Now, believe it or not, if
you want to do more inside of Highle,
you can make your own MCP, host it
somewhere, and have instead of the 39
that are available here, have close to
the 200 and something 90 that are
available out there. But that's not
going to be covered here today. What's
going to be covered is already using
what they have existing, which is pretty
good. you can do a good amount and at
least have your AI executive assistant
help you do these things. Right? So,
first thing that we're going to do is
we're just kind of understand where it
is. This is marketplace.goyle.com
docs/ othermcp in the index. And it
literally gives you exactly the steps
that you need to follow, but I'm going
to walk you through them anyway. So,
first thing you got to do though is you
got to give permission inside of your
account. Now, I'm going to go into my
account. This is my test account. And
inside of here, you're going to go to
settings. And inside of settings, you're
going to go to private integrations.
Inside private integrations, you're
going to hit create a new integration
and you're going to type in cloud code.
Okay, MCP. Grab that. Ctrl + C. Come
back over here. Cloud code MCP. And now
in the tool that we gave you, the SOP,
you're going to have a whole bunch of
things that need to be in here. And I
can tell you that one of the most
important ones is to view locations. And
it's listed on here. So, make sure
you're following the SOP of all the
things you want to basically turn on.
But let's just do it together, right?
So, I don't want it to edit the
business, but I definitely want it to
view it. I'm going to edit calendars.
And by the way, do not give it all
because if you give it all, it can
delete users, add users, and it can
create a bunch of problems if you give
it the wrong kind of availability. Now,
this thing can even write AI, voice
bots, and chat bots for you. And I'll
show you where that is. But again, just
be very careful what you're giving it
because if you don't know what you're
doing, it could delete a user for you
and everything else. So, try to avoid
the ones that are going to have some
pretty bad impact, right? But that's 65.
That's pretty good. I'm going to go
ahead and create. Now, the second I
create, it's going to expose my key, but
I know for a fact I'm going to rotate
it. So, it's also going to be blurred,
but I'm going to take this key. It's
very important. I'm going to copy it
because once you have it, you're not
going to see it again. And what I'm
going to do is I'm just going to paste
it somewhere safe. Once I paste it and I
have it somewhere good, it's awesome.
And by the way, again, I'll just rotate
it or delete it entirely. This is also
my test account. Has no payments. Has no
real information in there. But either
way, I'm being super safe. Then I go to
my business profile. And in your
business location, you're going to grab
this ID right here. You're going to copy
that and also put that in a safe
location because you're going to need
that later on. Right. So, now that you
have the account you want it to go into,
you are set to go. So, the first thing
that we're going to do is one, we're
going to pull up VS Code. And in VS
Code, I'm going to pull up a terminal.
So, I'm going to get rid of these two
terminals. And inside the terminal, I'm
going to have what we call the
PowerShell. This is bash, but we're
actually going to change it to
PowerShell. So, you're going to click on
this little down arrow, and you're going
to go to PowerShell. Now, if you haven't
installed Claude on your terminal, I
suggest you watch my previous video on
installation of Claude in order to get
that. I don't want to waste a lot of
time here on that one because again,
that video is pretty jam-packed with
that. So, what I recommend you doing is
exactly this. And anytime you get a code
from anybody anywhere on the internet,
what I usually do is I go to my cloud
code chat. I come in here, I create a
new chat. And in this new chat, I'm
going to say, I just received a code
that will help install a go highle MCP
on my claude code in my terminal. Please
make sure that this code is not
malicious or it's going to harm and that
it's right for my PC. And if you scroll
down in the SOP and if you follow all
the steps like we have been, what I'm
going to do is I'm going to come in here
and I'm going to copy this whole thing.
Crl + C, Crl + V. and I'm going to just
make sure it verifies that I'm doing
everything right. Now, a couple things
that you need to understand. First and
foremost, you have to have cloud code
installed on your terminal. You have to
have git bash and you also have to have
Node.js installed if you're using a PC.
Apple has a set of different
instructions. I've included that in
there, but again, you would put that
plan in here or that code to ensure that
it's really good. Now, code review, it's
safe to run, blah blah blah, and it goes
through the whole entire thing. So, now
you're good to go here. So, what we're
going to do is we're going to take that
code that I gave you. We're going to
open up a text document. We're going to
put that code in there. And let's just
do it together. Going to go to that
code. Windows is going to be up here.
Mac is going to be down there. What
you're going to do is you're going to
come over here and you're just going to
copy this yellow part right here. Ctrl +
C. Go into this file and you're going to
notice that it's going to say
authorization bearer your PIT token
here. Highlight where it says your PIT
token. Grab the PIT token that you got
from high level and only the PIT token.
And what we're going to do is we're
going to paste it. All right. So that is
pasted and it should say bearer space
pit and then whatever the code is. Then
you're going to have your location ID.
You're going to highlight this right in
between the quotations. Very important
that you keep the quotations or leave
the file unchanged. So, right in between
the quotations of this one, like you did
with the token area there, you're going
to grab the location ID, copy it, and
paste it right in here. Okay. All right.
Now, I'm going to go into my VS Code.
I'm going to open up a terminal window.
I'm going to select the down arrow right
here. I'm going to go into what's called
the PowerShell. Inside the PowerShell,
I'm in my AI executive assistant folder.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to
paste that command that I told you all
to copy. So, I copy that command. And
I'm going to come in here. I'm going to
paste it. I'm going to hit enter. And if
I did this right, I got done. GHLmcp
added. And now what I'm going to do is
I'm going to call and I'm going to type
in MCP. And if I did it right, I'll see.
Yep, there it is right here. ghl MCP
connected. Cool. Now that we actually
have the GHL connected, like you can see
here, we're now going to do the second
part of this is where we're going to
create our first person of our AI agent
team. Right. So, what I'm going to do is
I'm going to come over here and we're
going to talk a little bit about file
structure just so you have it. Now, I
have a folder that I call dev. If you go
I have it in my D drive or whatever else
and I have dev where I have all my
projects. I'm going to rightclick and
I'm going to create a new folder. All
right. So, we're going to come in here
and we're going to do new folder and
we're going to do AI agent team. And the
second gift I'm going to have for you is
if you click and you grab all the
folders and everything else. Just go
ahead sign up for our newsletter so you
can be able to learn more about this
stuff as we constantly go through. If
you go in here, I have given you a file
that you can download that is on top of
the SOPs an agent that you can put in.
Now again, this is my version of the
agent. Yours will be a little bit
differently. So obviously do the agent
the way you wanted to, but it's going to
give you the structure of everything you
need to run your first AI agent inside
of here. Now you see I have dev AI agent
team and what I'm going to do inside
this folder I'm going to install another
folder which is my GHL agent that is
going to do things in GHL for me. So
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
open up my another version of my file
manager or wherever you store documents
or wherever you download and I'll have a
zip file. I'm going to click on the zip
file and in here usually in a PC you
have extract all and a Mac it might be a
little bit differently but extract the
file and then browse to that dev folder
agent team and you're going to literally
select that folder and extract the
folder right in there right and now what
you're going to see is is in that folder
we are going to have all the necessary
files to launch our agent so I'm going
to go to file I'm going to go to open
folder and inside of this open folder
I'm going to go to my dev I'm going to
go to my AI agent team and lo and behold
I have my agents here right so my AI
agent team is Donna which is my main
agent content agent and these are all
other ones you can build GHL agent and
everything else but the GHL agent is the
one that we're going to work on right
but very specially about this AI agent
is going to be the cloud MD file so the
cloudmd file is always going to be the
actual directions for the bot so in here
it tells everything that we have to do
these are just some set of rules that we
have and more importantly it tells you
where the MCP server it tells you that
the PIT token is stored in the root and
the location ID is stored in the
environment variable now the environment
variable and we're going to go where
that is right there is this environment
example right here and notice that it
already states your GHL pit token and
your GHL location ID is in here and it
needs to have those two things added the
reason is is even though you added it to
the MCP server However, when you start
working with GHL when you're working
inside the skill and inside this agent,
it's always going to need to ensure
that's going to the right location ID
and the token. Now, this is just kind of
a requirement. So, what we're going to
do is we're going to come in here and
we're going to fill those in. Obviously,
I'm not going to share mine, but you
would just fill in the tokens you have
in here. So, we go back to the file that
we had first the location ID here, and
you're going to paste it. And then the
token base you're going to come in here
and you're going to put in once you have
that I'm going to leave it and I'm going
to go back to just closing this out and
it's automatically going to save. And
for you because again this was an
example for you what you're going to do
is once you've gone in here and you
fixed that environmental file and
because you have your right tokens in
here you're going to just rename it and
you're going to remove the example with
a dot and that becomes your env file
which is you're going to need. Now I'm
back in my GHL agents. What's really
cool now is so I can come in here and if
I follow my SOP that I have in here,
there are some examples here how Donna
works, blah blah blah. And you can
create additional Donna and just add it
to what I wanted to give you a little
placeholder. Delete the agents if you
don't want it. But this is just to give
you a really good idea how to do all
this. Okay, so now we can be in Donna
because that's the main folder or the
main team. And I can come in here and
just paste this. Hit enter. Ask GHL to
run its first discovery. Connect GHL.
pull all pipelines, tags, and custom
fields and save everything. So now what
it's going to do is it's going to save a
lot of this into the memory and my Donna
is already kind of doing a lot of the
things. So now I'm basically building my
own AI team as we're doing this. But
what I have to do is preload everything
into the GHL agent. So the GHL, you
know, it's knows the location. It's
going to the MCPS now. It's going to ask
for a bunch of permissions. All right,
success true means it's connected. All
these are true. So, it's connecting to
each of the end points to grab the
information that it needs. So, then it
could do its job and do whatever it
needs. So, as long as I keep getting
those 200 twos back, that means that the
token and the action location ID is
right. Now, later on, if I'm running
multiple accounts and she might need
access to it, this will be GHL agent for
the specific location and then another
GHL agent for another location and then
you would use different MCPS to connect
and you would just connect them
appropriately. Now there is a way to
connect to your entire agency but again
you got to use that sporadically. This
way you can communicate directly with
the client. Now it looked at the 19 you
know pipelines discovered 15 tags custom
fields and everything else. Now one
thing that we are correcting in the MD
file or in the memory file is we don't
want to store all the context
conversations and anything else that
might be too a little too crazy. But
this at least will get you an idea to do
that. So it knows what it's working with
and how to tag and everything else. So
here I can say who is in the lead
management pipeline and how many
contacts are in the new lead section and
it might not be any because like again
this is a test account but at least we
can go in there and we can figure it
out. And now what you can do is you can
come in here and you can add an
individual to a lead just by speaking
it. If this is communicating with other
agents, you can then now say okay give
this to the lead magnet agent and make
sure to put this person into a contact.
And remember you're also going to have
calendar abilities. So you could say
what calendars do I have available and
so forth and so on. And then it will do
the same exact thing. So new lead, one
contact. Boom. And it gives, you know,
the contact name of everything that's in
there, which is amazing. And now if we
want to, let's just clear this
conversation. I can say what calendars
do I have available for me inside of
GHL. And it's going to pull the
calendars to see which calendars are
available. And then again, remember what
we're doing here is we're printing raw
information. But at the end of the day,
like if this is connected to other apps
or you're speaking it, you could just
say make an appointment for such and
such. use GHL to put a calendar on this
particular calendar and then it will go
do its thing to make sure that it's able
to go in and do the entire process which
is amazing right okay so it's saying get
calendar events benches the specific and
it needs a calendar ID so it's saying
that it has a location ID but
unfortunately GHL tools don't include a
list calendars endpoint and it could
have been me that I maybe didn't have it
so we would just go to the calendar ID
or user group so if I'm back in GHL I
would just have all my calendar IDs
listed in here. So I go to GHL, go to my
cloud MD file and I would tell here's
the available skills but then I would
also say here are my common calendar ids
and you would get all the calendar ids
from GHL and so forth and so on. There
is some nice ideas of checking the
pipelines of things that you can do in
here. But again now you can come in here
and you can integrate and you can
communicate with your actual GHL
account. And just remember this is now
part one of like your agent team. You
now can come in here and you can do
whatever you want and add more agents
and make a full AI agent team that can
communicate with each other and get
everything done for you. So hopefully
this helps and we'll see you in the next
one.
>> [music]