Boris Cherny, the guy from Anthropic who
started Claude Code, recently posted on
X a thread of what he thinks are the
most underrated features of Claude Code.
It's a pretty interesting list, but one
of them really jumped out at me. It's an
option to start Claude Code as a
specific agent. Your entire session
becomes that agent. And my first
reaction was, "Oh, that's kind of cool."
And my immediate second reaction was,
"Wait, if I've got a brainstorming
agent, how is it different to start
Claude Code as the brainstorming agent
versus just going into Claude Code and
saying, "Hey, use the brainstorming
agent." Shouldn't that be the same
thing? So, I tested it. The difference
was night and day. It was not at all
what I expected. This is my
brainstorming agent. Ask questions,
identify the most valuable features. You
don't write code. You're not a yes
machine. And then when you're done, save
the summary to a file if the user wants
to hand it off to another agent. All of
those things are contained in that agent
file. It just tells the system how to
behave and what its purpose is. So, most
of the time an agent gets called from
inside of Claude Code. Either the user
can explicitly say, "Hey, use the
brainstorming agent. I want to
brainstorm ideas for this app." Or if
the description is clear enough, then
Claude Code knows when to use the agent
for a specific purpose. But, according
to this post from Boris, there is
another way to call it with that agent
flag. So, usually if I'm starting up
Claude Code, I just type Claude and I
hit enter and it starts up a session of
Claude Code. But, if you use the agent
flag and then give it the name of your
agent, it'll start it up with that agent
as the session. I'm now going directly
back and forth with the agent rather
than asking Claude Code to use the
agent, having Claude interpret what I'm
saying, hand it off to that agent,
getting some interaction with the agent,
having the agent hand it back to Claude
Code, and then coming finally back to
me. So, my question was, is this going
to be something that I can feel? Is that
difference going to be tangible? So, I
took the same prompt and I asked both
versions of the agent to do the same
thing. Basically, I want to build a
website for my YouTube channel. I don't
really have any specific ideas. I don't
want to close any doors. I just want to
make sure that I'm not building myself
into a corner somehow. And it came back
with a lot of great questions and it
felt like a conversation. It needed to
get oriented because it didn't really
have memories of me or what I do. Who
are you? What's your channel about? When
you say professional website, do you
mean professional or do you just mean
you want a little personal website where
you can put ideas up. I gave it a bunch
of information about me and sort of some
thoughts about where I might or might
not want to take this website. In
general, it tried to take in as much
information as it could and then gave me
some advice. "Oh, I think you might want
two or three pages max. Let's keep
things separated a little bit nicely.
Have one page for the homepage, another
page for these apps that you might want
to feature, and then we can add a third
page in the future as needed." It listed
the things that it thought were the most
valuable. It had a list of things that
we could add later and none of them
would be negated by anything we were
going to put into this plan today. And
it gave me a full product spec at the
end. It did have a list of open
questions, so I went back to some of
those and addressed them. Overall, I
felt like this did a really nice idea.
It had a full picture of who the website
would be for, who I was, what I was
looking for in the website, and what we
might want it to be in the future if we
ever got that far. And almost as
importantly,
what were the decisions we came to and
why did we come to those conclusions.
The whole thing felt like a conversation
the whole time. And one of the really
nice things, I never felt that pressure
of, you know, sometimes when you're
using Claude Code and it asks you a few
questions and says, "Okay, are we ready
to get to work?" And you're like, "No,
no, no, hold on." I didn't get that
pressure to just get going and start
coding. It just felt like it was there
to hang out with me, ask questions or
answer questions as long as I needed to.
And and that's important. The reason it
stayed focused is because that's all it
knows how to do. That constraint is
actually its best feature. So, next up I
opened another project. I opened Claude
Code like I usually do and I asked it to
use the brainstorming agent to help me
plan. I gave it the exact same prompt
that I had given the previous one. That
brainstorming agent then went on to ask
me a handful of questions that I
answered as close as possible as I could
to the previous session. But, the
interesting thing is once that was done,
that agent marked itself as finished and
handed everything back to Claude Code.
So, you can even see here where the
handoff happened. The brainstorm doc is
saved in this markdown file, which is
what I asked for, but I didn't get that
I didn't get that summary from the
agent. This is Claude Code talking
again. It's interpreting that file that
was handed back and giving me the
headlines. It basically recommended
everything to me. It didn't ask how many
pages I wanted. It didn't ask me what
kind of layout I wanted. It actually
didn't even ask me what I wanted the
webpage to look like. It just made a
bunch of those decisions for me. Again,
there were several open questions in
that agent's documentation that Claude
Code had to then come back and ask me
about about your my channel and my
brand. And the funny thing was it asked
me what newsletter tool I had in mind
even though I had already told it I
maybe in the future might want a
newsletter, but I didn't have anything
currently. It sort of lost that
information somewhere in the translation
from Claude Code to agent, agent to
Claude Code to me. So, there was
definitely sort of a gap in the
information flow. But, Claude Code went
on to ask me a couple of other questions
because it was reinterpreting that data
from the agent. And I will say a couple
of them were really interesting. Because
Claude Code is more of a generalist
rather than a specialist, it had a
bigger overview of of really of what I
was trying to do. And it actually
highlighted a couple of really
interesting things. It picked up on
something I was talking about my
background and said, "Oh, that's a
really great storyline. We should really
highlight that on the webpage. That's
not just background information. That
could be kind of featured." And so, it
had a bigger vision picture than the
brainstorming agent did. And that's when
I really started to understand the
difference. Starting the agent with the
agent flag is like going into a doctor's
office. You're sitting there with a
specialist. You're having a
conversation. You're having back and
forth. And the person that has that
specific knowledge that you need is
sitting there having a conversation with
you. Going into Claude Code and then
asking it to use an agent felt more like
when you go into a doctor's office and
they sit with you for 5 minutes and then
they make a big note and they hand it
off to their assistant and they say,
"Thanks. I'll see you later." And then
the assistant says, "Okay, I'm going to
read over the doctor's notes and I'll
have a few more questions for you. You
can ask me anything you like." It felt
like I got just a few minutes with the
specialist and then I was sort of handed
off to this assistant, to this
generalist. Now, just like in real life,
the assistant can be really helpful and
sometimes knows things that the
specialist doesn't. So, it's not that
one is better or worse, it's just that
they are really different experiences.
So, next came the part that I didn't
expect. I had built out an architect
agent and I wanted to run that same
experiment with the architect agent. So,
I came in and started Claude with the
architect agent. And I told it, "You've
got notes in the docs directory on a
website we want to start building." So,
it started out great. It found the
documentation. It asked a couple of
technical questions and asked if I had
photos or logos that I wanted to put on
the website. Once I had all that in
place, I gave it the go ahead and it
started building. And that's when it
started running into problems. It gave
me a long list of things that I needed
to do. It was really hampered because it
was only allowed to do the things in
that very tightly scripted agent
specification file. It couldn't reach
around and do a lot of the things that
you would normally expect Claude Code to
be able to do. So, basically, I had a
lot of back and forth of creating
directories that I wasn't used to
creating, renaming files, and just
having a whole bunch of general errors.
In the end, it didn't look great and I
tried to work with it to get it to look
at least halfway decent, but it just
couldn't figure out what I was even
asking it to do or why I might need
those changes. So, conversely, back in
the project where I was just running
regular Claude Code and I said, "I think
we're ready to build. Let's use the
architect agent to do that." It was off
and running with no problems. The agent
did ask me again a couple of technology
specification questions and then it just
took off and started working. And
because this was the agent running
inside of Claude Code, once the
architect was done architecting, Claude
Code took over and was able to create
all of the directories that it needed.
It started the server. It checked to
make sure everything was running and
that it all looked okay. This was really
the flawless Claude Code experience that
we've all come to know and love. And so
that's when it kind of clicked for me.
Starting an agent with the agent flag is
really really powerful when the
specialist that you're creating is
really different from Claude Code. So
this might be a brainstormer or a
researcher or an interviewer or an
adversary. Any area where you want
Claude to not be a coding specialist for
a little while. So here was my takeaway
from all of this. And Boris has actually
talked about this in other interviews.
He mentioned that he thinks of coding as
a series of phases. The specification,
the development, the refinement, the
testing. Each phase is different and
benefits from a different mind, a
different specialist. You can put all
the specialists together and get a much
better result than you would from just
giving everything to a generalist. And
obviously he's thought a lot about this,
way more than I have, but it definitely
lined up with what I found. It felt like
starting with a specialist and having it
do very specific pieces of the process
worked really well. But then handing
those pieces back to the generalist,
Claude Code, and letting it take a
second pass at the broader picture,
things that might have been missed,
really it fills in the gaps that the
specialist might have missed. There is
one more thing that's worth mentioning
really quickly. When you are specifying
the agent up there in that top matter,
you can actually specify what model it's
constrained to use. So for some things
you might really not need the Opus
model, you might be able to use the
Haiku model if you're just doing generic
research or quick web lookups. So if
you're one of those people that has been
running into rate limits recently on
Claude Code, that might really help you
out. That way you don't have to remember
to keep switching back forth between
models when you go into Claude Code
every time. All right, and so that's the
agent flag. It wasn't trying to be
everything for me. It was just really
good at the one thing that I asked it to
do. So if you're using Claude Code and
you haven't tried this before, give it a
shot. Create an agent that's good at
something other than coding, put it in
the .claude/agents
directory, and let it go to work. And
then you can just start up Claude Code
as that agent. You don't need to explain
to it what you're trying to do. You can
just start that conversation because it
already knows what you're there for. All
right, thanks to Boris Cherney for
posting that original thread on X. I
will put a link in the description below
because there really were a lot of good
tips in there. I will probably be
digging into a few of them in future
videos. All right, that's it for today.
Thanks for watching. I'll see you next
time.