There is a new generation of AI agents
emerging and most of them they forget
everything they learn. Hermes agent, it
does not. It's built by news research.
It's open source and it is the only
agent framework with a built-in learning
system that actually improves over time.
Now, in this video, we're going to go
deep on how it works, why it's different
from any other agent out there, and
whether it's the right choice for you.
Now, the AI agent space right now, it's
essentially like the web wars in 1995.
Everyone's building them. That's Chrome,
Firefox, Safari, except for agents.
There's no consensus yet on what
actually matters. [music] Now, most
agent frameworks, they treat the agent
as stateless. So, you ask it something,
it answers, and if you ask the same
question next week, it starts from zero.
Hermes, it does not work [music] that
way. It's built on a core assumption
that an AI agent learns from its
interactions and becomes more valuable
over time. And that's not just a
marketing spin. Like, it's a completely
different architecture and it changes
what you can actually build with it. So,
let's break down what that actually
means. And really quick, if you're new
to the [music] channel, my name is Nick.
I've spent the last 2 years helping
companies implement AI, driving over $5
million in bottomline revenue across
clients, helping hundreds of
entrepreneurs build AI businesses. In
today's video, it is directly relevant
because if you're building anything with
AI agents, you need to understand the
actual architectural choices that
separate a tool that stagnates from one
that improves. Now, Hermes agent, it
represents a fundamentally different bet
on how agents should be working. So,
what actually is this framework? Well,
Hermes agent, this is just an
open-source self-improving AI agent
framework. It's built by News Research,
so it's version 0.6.0.
It is production ready. There's also a
very strong adoption. They have about
19,000 GitHub stars, solid community,
and about 200 plus contributors. It's
also MIT licensed. It's fully commercial
friendly. Here's the thing. Hermes, it
does three different things. It is a
fullfeatured agent that can use over 40
different tools like web search,
terminal, file system, browser
automation, code execution, image
generation, text to speech, and even
vision. It's also got a messaging
gateway so you can talk to it from your
terminal. You can connect it to
Telegram, Discord, Slack, WhatsApp,
Signal, even email all from one process.
And it has a built-in [clears throat]
learning system. So that is the part
that is actually different. It doesn't
just run tests, it learns from them.
It's also built on Python. So that's
about 92% of the codebase. 92.5%
actually, which actually matters because
most AI infrastructures, it lives inside
of Python. So any LLM APIs, any
transformers, any training frameworks
and you can integrate it, you can debug
it and you can extend it if necessary.
So with that being said, the
installation it takes about 60 seconds.
It's just one batch command and it
handles Python, NodeJS, everything. All
right, here's where Hermes gets very
interesting and why all these tools and
platforms actually matter. Now most
agents, these are effectively just
tools. So you are using a tool, it helps
you, you move on. Simple as that. Now,
Hermes, it treats itself like a product
that is just going to get better and
better. So, think about how this
actually can work in practice. Hermes,
it is going to store everything. So, you
have this folder right here. So, this is
going to be every conversation inside of
it. You have every task. You have every
question. This is starting to look like
a face, but but anyways, it is going to
be able to search its own past using
full text search. And when it finds
something that's going to be relevant,
it's then going to summarize that from
there. So 6 months from now you can ask
something as simple as like haven't we
solved something like this in the past
and it should be able to find that it'll
know it will actually be able to
remember. Now with this it's able to
actually create some skills from here
with that. So this comes about week
four. This is all hypothetical by the
way. So let's say you ask it to just
like analyze my monthly revenue, pull
data from Stripe and also HubSpot and
then send me just a weekly summary with
three insights every single Tuesday.
Now, Hermes, it'll do it for you. So,
the first time it'll be maybe 20
different steps. It'll be multiple API
calls. It'll do the research for you.
And with that, like what happens is it
creates a skill from that interaction.
So, it packages the logic as a reusable
function. It tests it. It also stores
it. So, next time you ask for something
similar, it doesn't just start over. It
would actually run the skill. It'll
refine [music] it and it will make it
faster as well. Now beyond this, Hermes
is going to actually track some patterns
that are going to be very specific
towards you. So this can consist of any
of your preferences, maybe your working
style and what actually is going to
matter to you. So when you ask something
very vague, it's not going to guess like
it would actually understand your
context and over time it would
eventually be able to nudge itself. So
it notices patterns across your
conversations. It can suggest like you
probably want a skill that's going to do
X instead of Y. So you can improve it,
you can reject it and week after week,
month after month, this is going to be
compounding for you because it's getting
better. It's going to get more tailored
towards you and your preferences. And
this is fundamentally different from
Chat GBT or Claude or OpenClaw. They
reset every time. Hermes, it is designed
to be getting better. It gets smarter
the longer that it actually works with
you. Now, if you're going to actually
deploy an agent that learns just like
this, where it runs matters just as much
as what it can actually do. So, let's
discuss that. Now, most agent
frameworks, they're just built for
notebooks or local machines, right? So,
you can run them on your laptop. If your
laptop turns off, just like clawed code,
for instance, the agent will stop
working. But you can actually run Hermes
in about six different places. So, you
can install it on your local terminal if
you're developing. You can run it on
Docker for any containerization. You can
SSH if you want it on a VPS which is how
I actually utilize it myself and
Singularity if you have even any
research cluster access or Daytona for
any persistent cloud development and
then there's also going to be modal
where you can just pay for any compute
seconds. So when your agent it is idle
and waiting for message you're not
paying anything at all. It is zero modal
it hibernates all automatically. It
wakes when you have a message coming in
in your agent. It runs 247 for about5 to
$10 a month instead of a permanent VPS
where it's going to be a little bit more
expensive, but still the costs are going
to be relatively minimal. Now, this
matters because you have different
projects needing different types of
infrastructure. So I would imagine where
you have a personal assistant on your
laptop like maybe that can be local a
production system it needs to SSH or you
can use Docker for or a research project
using GPU it needs some HPC clusters or
a startup decoding like can we actually
afford this like that needs serverless
and Hermes it does not lock you in like
you can use any of these you just pick
the back end that's going to be most
applicable and actually make sense for
you and the reason that I actually put
this on that VPS guess is because I
needs to be able to utilize a lot of the
stuff and have it do jobs while I am
away. I do not want to keep my computer
around. I don't want to buy a separate
computer or anything like that just yet.
I just want to keep it simple and see if
I like this first through a VPS. We'll
test it and we'll go from there. But
now, let's just break down what this
actually looks like and how it operates
under the hood. So, when I say that
Hermes is learning, I want to actually
show you what that means mechanically
because it's not magic. It's just an
architectural decision. So it all is
going to start here with this user
request up at the top. Now within this,
you give Hermes a real task. So it can't
be something as simple as like what's
the weather or anything that generic. It
should be something like pull my revenue
from Stripe and then I want you to cross
reference it with my HubSpot pipeline
and then analyze it in Python and then
write me a one-page summary with three
different insights and send it to the
leadership Slack channel. So like that
is a real workflow like that is a
generic or non-generic and uh pretty
complex process I should say. You have
multiple systems you also have multiple
steps associated with it. Now within
step number two right here. So Hermes it
has over 40 tools as I have mentioned.
So it changed them together. It's
hitting Stripe APIs. It's pulling from
HubSpot. It's running Python to actually
crunch the numbers. So it's generating a
chart. It's formatting and sending Slack
a message. So if it's the first time
running this through, that's about 15 20
different steps. It will take a few
minutes or up to 5 minutes, whatever it
may be. And that's fine. like every
agent it takes a while especially the
first time and that's not the
interesting part. This is the
interesting part within step three. So
right here what's actually going on is
it is going to well after it finishes
Hermes will record everything that it
had just done. So every API call, every
decision, every tool it used in what
order that's going to be recorded and
that full recorded is what they call a
trajectory. So most agent frameworks,
they just throw that away completely.
Like the task is done, the memor is
gone, Hermes keeps it instead. And then
from there, we're going to get into step
four. Step four, this is just going to
analyze that trajectory. And it's going
to ask itself like, can I package this
into something that's going to be
reusable? And if the answer is yes,
well, it writes a skill. It packages the
whole workflow as a reusable function.
It tests it. It then stores it right in
your local file system at Hermes
back/skills. and you can go look at it.
It's just going to be code sitting on
your machine. Simple as that. Just like
if you use cloud code or anything
remotely similar. Moving on to step
number five, the reuse and refinement.
So this is effectively the whole point
right here like this one. So next time
you actually are asking for something
similar like maybe it's the a Monday
report, maybe it's a variation. Hermes
it will not be starting from scratch. It
will run the skill. It'll be faster.
will be cleaner because it has a
standard operating procedure to be
following and if something changed like
you added a data source or if you want
the format different it will refine the
skill it will update it will get better
and better so this entire loop right
here like this is effectively the entire
value proposition of Hermes so like
these are not pre-recorded macros like
these skills they are very alive and
inside of your code they're able to
learn from each execution and you can
also share them through any maybe it's
like agentskills.io IO. I know it's a
very common one which is basically just
npm packages for agents where Hermes it
ships with over 40 bundled skills
already but the real power is the custom
ones that you can actually build
specifically for how you are working and
again over time like your Hermes it
becomes a completely different tool than
somebody else's Hermes like it's shaped
by your workflows your preferences your
patterns and that is what self-improving
actually means in practice. Now, of
course, as you would expect, like this
matters a lot in practice. So, let me
show you what real deployment actually
is going to look like. All right, let's
discuss a little bit about the
limitations because there definitely is
some. First up, Windows does not work. I
don't mean that it's not optimized for
Windows. I genuinely mean like if you
are on Windows, you are completely out
of the equation. So, you need WSL2 like
full stop. That sounds like a small
thing until you're actually talking to
any enterprise teams and half your
engineers are on Window machines. Now
they are working on experimental Windows
support but there are PRs landing for
path handling and PTI support but as of
right now the readme says they are not
supported. Plan accordingly. Now the
learning loop here's the thing that not
many people are going to tell you like
it is very beautiful in theory but in
practice like it only creates skills for
very complex tasks. So if you give it
something simple it is not going to be
learning and the skill that it creates
it is LLM generated. So it's not
actually going to be guaranteed to work
properly for you. So you get a skill,
you run it, it fails, you're like,
"Okay, so I thought that this would save
me time and actually just wasted it." So
maybe it was a nuisance, it was
detrimental where the the learning it is
real, but it's not magic. So you have to
set your expectations accordingly and
just know that you are going to have to
adjust things quite frequently. Now
there's also a security thing that
bothered me a bit. So if you're running
on the local back end like not docker
not modal you're running this locally
your agent it can call the terminal
which runs as you on your machine. So if
the LLM decides to do something weird or
edgy it definitely can like there are
dangerous command checks built in and
there's actually a PR right now to
tighten this even further but the docs
they themselves for production use
docker or modal as your backend because
the container it is the security
boundary. So if you're security
conscious and you're running locally,
like this is something you genuinely
need to be thinking about. Now the
agent, it also gets stuck sometimes. So
if you message it, it can ignore you and
it'll so often just get into a loop and
just keep going while you are just going
to be sitting there. So they have
shipped some fixes for this in past
releases like the VO. 4.0 change log. It
has multiple fixed stuck agent loop
entries, but it's one of those things
that just keeps coming back in different
forms. So it's getting better, but is
not completely solved. And then there's
also the speed. So if you need raw
execution speed on multi-top workflows,
Hermes it is not exactly optimized for
that. Where frameworks like Crew AI and
Langraph, they're purpose-built for fast
orchestration. In Hermes, it is trading
speed for learning and that's the bet
that they are essentially making. So if
your use case is run this pipeline as
fast as possible, like those frameworks,
there are going to be better tools. And
if your use case is to just build an
agent that gets smarter the longer I use
it, that's where Hermes is going to
actually be much much better for you.
Now look, these are not deal breakers if
you're a Mac or Linux shop building
internal tools and you're okay running
Docker for isolation. But if you need
native Windows or if you need lockdown
security environment with no containers
or speedritical pipelines, then Hermes
is not going to be your tool. it's
optimizing for something completely
differently. Now, that brings me to the
comparison. So, if learning is what
Hermes is betting on, there's another
framework taking a completely different
bet. So, if Hermes has all these
trade-offs, and it definitely does, the
obvious question is like, okay, well,
what about OpenClaw? Because every time
that I mention Hermes in my community,
somebody says like just use OpenClaw.
Like, so let me just break this down
because I think most of the comparisons
out there are actually getting this
completely wrong. So, first, if you do
not know what OpenClaw is, you need to.
Peter Steinberger, he built it as a
weekend side project back in 2025. So,
it went from zero to about 300,000 plus
GitHub stars in about 4 months. It beat
React's all-time record and the record
that React took 10 years to set. It took
this 60 days for Open Claw. Now, Jensen
Wang, he called it probably the most
important release of software ever.
Dyner, he then joined OpenAI in
February. The project moved to an
independent foundation and the
development pace somehow got even
faster. You know, there are releases
landing every few hours. There about
13,000 community skills on Claw Hub. 2
million monthly active users and this is
not a small project that you have not
heard of. Like this is the biggest thing
happening in open-source AI right now.
And here's like where most creators just
get this wrong about the comparison is
like they frame it as like which one is
better and that's the wrong question.
Like these tools, they're making
fundamentally different architectural
bets. So, OpenC Claw, it is a messaging
gateway. It is built in Typescript. It's
designed to be the single control plane
that routes your AI across every
platform that your life is touching. So,
24 platforms including WhatsApp,
Telegram, iMessage through Blue Bubbles,
Teams, Discord, Slack, Signal, Google
Chat, Line Matrix, IRC, WeChat. There's
even more. Now, you text it from your
phone. It works on your machine and the
community ecosystem. It is gigantic.
There's 13,000 skills on Claw Hub.
There's tutorials everywhere. There's a
whole startup ecosystem just building on
top of it. And if you need an agent that
shows up across five business channels
from day one with a huge community
behind it, like OpenClaw is
purpose-built specifically for that. But
here's what OpenClaw does not do for
you. It does not learn. So the skills in
OpenClaw, they are maintained by humans
where you install them, you configure
them, you update them. And with that, if
the agent does something clever today,
it's not going to remember how to do it
even faster tomorrow. So there's no
trajectory capture. There's no RL
training pipeline and open clause memory
system. It is going to work through
plugins. So any filebacked memory, you
have lance DB for vector search. You
have lossless claw for full conversation
persistence. So it is solid, but you
install it and configure each of those
parts separately. And it's just a lot to
configure and constantly have to
optimize. Hermes, it is the opposite
bet. It is built in Python by Noose
Research. It's an actual AI lab, not a
solo developer project. And these are
the people behind Hermes model family.
So they know how models learn because
they train them for legitimately a
living. And that shows in the
architecture because the learning loop
it is fundamentally baked into the core
where you have autonomous skill creation
after complex tasks and skills that
self-improve during use and memory that
can nudge itself and a trajectory
capture that exports to share GPT for
any fine-tuning your own models. Now the
last part is the RL training pipeline.
So if you're building AI models or doing
any kind of research like this is the
infrastructure that openclaw
fundamentally does not have. So on
platforms Hermes it now covers 12. It
has Telegram, Discord, Slack, WhatsApp,
Signal, Email, Home Assistant, Dingtalk,
Mattermost, Matrix, Fau, and Wecom.
That's still less than open clause 24,
but the gap it is narrower than most
people actually realize. And the
crossplatform conversation continuity in
Hermes. It is something that multiple
reviewers, they have called out. So,
start on the CLI, get notified on
Telegram, resume on Discord, and then
there's not going to be any context
lost. On the infrastructure, Hermes has
six different backends where you have
the local, you have Docker, SSH,
Singularity, Daytona, and modal
serviceless. So, you can run it on just
a simple $5 VPS that costs nothing when
it's idle. And OpenClaw, it's primarily
just a node.js process or most commonly
docker. Both work, but if you want
serverless or any HPC cluster
developments, Hermes is the one that's
going to be supporting that. And one
thing that I haven't seen on any other
video thus far is that Hermes, it has a
built-in openclaw migration tool. So if
you actually run this command,
Hermesclaw migrate, it is going to pull
your soul. MD, it can pull your
memories. It can pull your skills, your
API keys, and your messaging config. So
literally everything. It's one command.
So if you're already running OpenClaw
and you're curious about the learning
side, you don't start from scratch. Like
that's a very deliberate strategic move
from noose because they're not asking
you to choose. They're just saying like
keep open cloth if it works for you and
try Hermes alongside it. So look, if you
are running a business and you need an
agent that operates across multiple
channels, handles customerf facing
tasks, has a massive community
ecosystem, and you want something where
you can find a tutorial for literally
anything at 2 a.m. That's OpenClaw. It's
the operations and platform play. And if
you want an agent that compounds what it
knows over time, gets faster the more
you use it, it can export training data
for your own models, and you're
comfortable running it on a server,
that's going to be Hermes. It's the
personal agent and the research play if
that is what you need. So they're just
completely different games. Pick the one
that actually matches what you're going
to be building. So if you're leaning
towards Hermes, let me show you how
simple it actually is to get started.
Let's do that now. Now, one thing that I
really like about Hermes is how simple
this is to actually set up. So it's
legitimately a few minute task. All
right, so here's what we're going to do.
We're just going to copy this read me
that is from GitHub. I'll have
everything linked inside of my school
community, so it is super simple for you
to actually install. But we're just
going to type in this curl and then the
GitHub install link. So from this, it's
going to run the Hermes agent installer.
You can see it's an open source AI agent
by news research. That's how you know it
is the right one. It's going to install
everything else. So all the Python,
going to install the NodeJS, all the
current updates, checking RIP Grip. So
we'll go from there. Now it's installing
all the other dependencies. And with
this, it's just checking your system.
So, Linux, iuntu, wherever you're
actually on, and it detects what you
have and it installs what you don't. So,
Python, Node, Rip, Grap, uh, FFmpeg, as
you guys can see up here. Like, you
don't have to touch any of that. So, the
installer, it handles everything. It is
super simple to get up and running. And
I mean, this is about 60% of the work
right here. So, there's no prerequisites
except for just using Git. So, now we
have the setup wizard. everything from
here we can just press insert to begin
now it's going to ask me for my provider
now if you are using any of your plans
if you're using chat GPT if you are
using your enthropic or cloud
subscription you can continue using this
it's not like openclaw where you are
restricted from something like that so
you just have to input your oath where
run you through it real quick if you do
want to go with enthropic I have some
existing credentials but what you would
do is you would click reauthenticate it
to actually say something different, but
you're going to select your oath, in
which case it'll provide you with a link
where you just log into your cloud
account and you get a code and then you
just have to input it back into here.
But I'm going to cancel this for the
time being. And we're just going to move
on to the next piece. So this is the
TTS. So we are able to use something
like 11 Labs to actually talk back and
forth with to this agent. So I'm just
going to keep the current one. And now
this is the terminal backend. So if he
wants to put this on docker local modal
SSH. So I will run this locally for the
time being. Let's continue this and
we're just going to enable pseudo
support and everything else. We're just
going to run with that. Full progress
display. Press enter again. Context
compression. We'll keep that in activity
mode. So I'm going to go with whatever
is actually being recommended. Now we
have a session reset policy. I'm going
to skip this. You guys can spend a
little bit more time on this and
customize this to your particular
settings, but I'm just going to uh go
with most of the defaults. I'm going to
ignore it to set up any of these. So,
WhatsApp web hooks. Now, if you guys do
want to enable any of those specific
things, it's very straightforward. So,
for example, with uh with Telegram, if
we actually pull that up right now,
we'll be able to see that it's as simple
as just creating a new bot inside of
here. So you just type out / newbot and
you'll be able to just take your API
access token and you can throw that
inside of your terminal. Anyways, moving
on. We now have all these different
skills. We have web searching and
scraping. We have the browser
automation, terminal processes. I'm
choosing to set this up later. I'm just
going to leave everything blank, but I
actually will enable some of these so I
can press space to check mark them. And
let's go ahead and just skip. You guys
can provide any of your API keys now. So
if you want to set that up, you can use
browser use, local browser, browser
base, camo fox. They give you a lot of
different options. So the smart home,
I'm going to leave that blank. Not worry
about that. Foul image generation. I
don't want that now. Arl training. So
everything I'm just going to skip for
the time being. I don't want to set any
of this up now. Next up, it's just
asking me to reload my show to use the
Hermes command. So I'm going to type
this out. It's going to reload
everything. Now, to actually get started
using this, I'm just going to simply
type out Hermes and it's going to start
setting everything up for me. So, just
like that, we are now inside of our
environment. We are now able to fully
utilize Hermes agent. So, you guys can
see all the available tools and you can
change the colors of everything because
it is a little bit hard to see. So, you
can change your terminal and the
background of everything because, you
know, can't really tell what anything is
being listed out as. Now just like cloud
code we now have access to the full
terminal interface where if we just type
slash you can see all the different
commands. So we can try new reset
background where um we can go even
further. We can have the provider the
prompt you guys can provide it with a
backup API key. So if you want to use
something like open router instead of
just using you know your quad
subscription because sometimes I want to
use us 4.6 6, but I also want to be able
to use chat GPT, use codeex, so I'm not
going to be spending an arm and a leg
doing simple tasks and overkilling it by
just using Opus 4.6. So, the list goes
on and on of all the different commands.
So, I'm not going to run through all of
these. It is very in-depth, but you guys
will be able to explore them for
yourself. So, we even have some native
Obsidian connections and uh we have
Claude code, we have codeex, we have
Hermes agent. I mean, the list goes on
and on. You can use open code. You can
use dog food, which I actually have no
idea what that is even for. It looks
like it's some QA testing. You have nano
PDF where you can even edit PDFs with
natural language instructions. You have
linear, you have notion, um, PowerPoint,
Google Workspace. So, I'm not exactly
sure if these are CLIs or just MCP
connections, but anyways. Now, I do want
to mention that if you want to run this
from your phone, which is kind of the
whole point of running this on a server,
is you need to actually start the
gateway. So, what that actually looks
like is you just need to simply type
out, let's back up, Hermes gateway. So,
with my current setting, you can't
really see what I'm typing out, but
there you go. So, we just type out
Hermes Gateway, and this is going to
allow us to actually start this. So, the
gateway would go up. You have your
Telegram adapter connected, and then
you'll be able to utilize Telegram on
your phone. Find the bot you just
created. Hit start, send it a message,
you'll be good to go. It'll start
responding. It'll be the same exact
agent that is inside of here. same
memory, same skills, just accessible
from your phone and really wherever you
want to be. So that's the setup. It's
just one install command, one setup
wizard, one Hermes to be running it. And
if you guys do want to be setting this
up on a VPS where you don't have to
worry about keeping your computer on at
all times, and you know, you can just
focus on locking it down from there,
making sure that everything is secure,
similar to what you would do with
OpenClaw, then you can do something like
Katner, you can use Hostinger. I mean,
there's so many different options out
there, but it is very simple. You just
have to start off with the console
inside of your platform, whichever
you're using and then you're going to
have to SSH into it through your machine
first, but you can SSH in through any
computer you're using. But anyways,
you'll be able to utilizing it on your
phone once you first set it up and get
your foundation set up. So, if you guys
want a full video on how to set this up
through a VPS, I'm happy to do so
because it is a little bit more complex
than just setting it up locally. But
anyways, I hope you guys are realizing
that the question isn't anymore like
should we use agents or what kind of
agents like should we actually be
building where Hermes it represents one
answer agents that learn and that feels
almost obvious now. So of course agents
should improve over time but
architecturally like it's surprisingly
hard and most agent frameworks it
couldn't do this if you ask them. And
the fact that news research built this
from the ground up, it tells you
something that they really believe the
future of agents, it is in adaptation
and learning and depth, not in the
breadth and the generality. So whether
they are right, time will tell. But if
you are building AI infrastructure and
understanding that this choice learning
versus breath, it is essential. And if
you're learning how to evaluate and
deploy AI infrastructure like this, you
need to go ahead and join our free
school community. That is where we are
having the real conversations about what
actually works. It's not hype. It's not
theory. We have over 18,000 members, all
founders and operators building AI into
their businesses. Now, we deep dive on
architecture and decision infrastructure
and choices and real implementation
challenges every week. So, link is in
the description. But thank you guys for
watching. If this was helpful, make sure
to like and subscribe for more on AI
infrastructure and agent frameworks. But
I'll see you guys in the next video. And
if you're looking for more on AI tools
and weekly strategies to growing and
starting your business, that's
subscribed to our free AI newsletter as