Everybody knows that Claude has been
shipping like absolute madmen. I swear
they have like Opus 20 under the hood or
something. This is everything the Claw
team has shipped in the last two months.
Almost every single day has a new
feature. But that's not what I'm talking
about today. There are actually a ton of
hidden features that the Claude team
hasn't talked about yet. A lot of these
exist because of the new million context
window for Opus 4.6 and they completely
change what Claude Code can do. Today,
I'm going to walk you through a couple
of the hidden settings that I use inside
of my Cloud Code setup. And by the end,
you'll be able to implement these for
your own Claude project. Your Claude
will work harder, remember longer, and
most importantly, stay out of your way.
Let's hop into the video. The first one,
and this is probably the easiest change
you're going to make today, and you'll
notice throughout the video that we're
working in one specific file, and all
these changes will be relatively easy
for you to make. We're going to hop into
ourcloud folder up here. We're going to
open it up and scroll down to this
settings.json. and I'm not going to
click on it yet, but that's what we're
going to mostly be working with. By
default, Cloud Code only keeps your
conversations for the past 30 days.
After that, they're gone, and that
matters a lot more than you think. I'll
run a command here that we're all
familiar with called /res when you want
to continue a past conversation or just
go look at the context of that
conversation. We'll run that, and you'll
see that I have 50 total sessions. And
then if we go all the way down through
our 50 sessions, we can see that our
last session was saved from 4 days ago.
The same thing if you were to run
something like SLI Insights, which
generates a report analyzing all of your
Cloud Code sessions, the default is set
to 30 days. And as you're about to see,
if you've been using Cloud Code like I
have, 30 days really is nothing. If
you've ever ran that /insights report,
you'll see here that we get Cloud Code
insights from March 11th to the 26th. We
have 156 sessions, 193 total hours, and
that's only in the past 15 days, right?
So, we want to be able to get it to the
past year. So, that's exactly what we're
going to change in our settings.json
file. How we're going to do that is
very, very simple. You're going to hop
over into your settings.json, and yours
probably doesn't look how mine looks
right now, but it's a super easy fix.
We're looking at this line right here at
the top, which is our cleanup period
days. We set it to 365. Natively, it's
at 30 days. So, we're going to want to
go ahead and change that. Now, if you
don't know JSON and you don't want to
type this in yourself, we can do it in
natural language. In our settings.json
file, please set the cleanup period to
365 days. You could say something simple
as that and then send it off. Now,
Claude will go into your settings.json.
mind come back and say it's already set
to that which is totally fine but that's
how you guys would do it in your own
thing. So right here it says it's
already set to 365 days on line two. If
we hop in here you'll see on line two
our cleanup period days is there. If
that's not there for you it'll allow you
to enter that in. You can resume old
sessions run insights over months of
work and none of it disappears on you.
And that actually ties directly into
Opus' new 1 million context window.
Claude is now able to actually use all
of that old context. So why would you
let Claude throw it out after 30 days?
When Claude runs something like a bash
command, the output sometimes can be
absolutely massive. And Claude actually
has a cap on how much output can
actually be read back. That default is
30,000 characters. That means if you run
something that has a ton of output like
build logs, test results, npm tests,
Claude will only see the first 30,000
characters and then truncate everything
after that. Meaning that everything
after those 30,000 characters is gone
and Claude doesn't have that context
anymore. And in order to quickly fix
that, we're going to hop into our
settings.json, JSON zoom in here on the
bash max output length which is default
set to 30,000 as I mentioned because the
default context window used to be
200,000 for opus 4.6 six. Now it's a
million. So went up 5x. So that's
exactly what we're going to do into our
output length. We're going to put it up
to 150,000. Now if you get a massive
output that's over 30,000 tokens and
less than 150, Cloud will see all that
context and have a lot more to work
with. Obviously capping it at 30,000
when the context window was 200,000 made
sense because we couldn't afford to load
anymore. But now you've got a million
tokens of context. So make sure you're
using it. So, unfortunately, by default,
when Claude reads a file, it only reads
a max of 25,000 tokens. And that's
because of the old 200,000 context
window. The problem is since Opus 46 now
has a million context window, we're not
allowing Claude to use its full
potential when reading files. Once
again, you can fix this by hopping over
to your settings.json, opening it up,
and then you'll see this line here. It's
set to 25K tokens. We're going to go
ahead and change that to 125,000. Then,
we're going to go ahead down here and
make sure we press save. But there's a
second problem. Even when we update that
setting, Claude will only read 2,000
lines at a time. Enthropic unfortunately
hard-coded that. You can't change that
in the JSON settings. But fortunately,
there is a workaround, and we're going
to hop into our claw.md file. You'll add
this instruction inside of your claw.md
that says, "Anytime you input a file,
make sure to read it, do a line count,
and if the file is over 2,000 words,
we're going to use offset and limit
parameters to break this thing down into
chunks and read it properly so we don't
miss anything." As far as adding that to
make it simple for you guys, you could
just do it in natural language. In my
settings.json, JSON set the file read
max output tokens to 125,000. Also add a
rule to my claw.md that tells you to
always check the line count on a file
before reading it. If it's over 2,000
lines, use offset and limit to read it
in chunks instead of trying to read the
whole thing at once. We would then send
it off that prompt. Since I've already
done it, we're not going to just test it
again. But don't worry, I'll have this
in a resource guide for all of you. The
link will be in the description for all
the hidden settings that I'm showing you
guys today and how to install them for
yourselves. This next one has been
covered a ton already, but it's agent
teams. A lot of people still don't know
that you can enable this in your
settings.json, and it's an experimental
feature that's not automatically
enabled. Agent teams lets you coordinate
multiple cla code instances working
together. One session acts as a team
lead coordinating work, assigning tasks,
and synthesizing results. Teammates work
independently, each in its own context
window, and communicate directly with
each other. Now, let me show you how to
enable it. Once again, we're going to
hop into our settings.json. We're then
going to see a line here that says
claude code experimental agent teams. We
have it set to one. If it's set to zero
or doesn't exist, that means it's not
enabled. The easiest way to enable agent
team is to either add that line or say
it in natural language. I need you to
enable the agent teams experimental
feature in our settings.json. I'll go
ahead and send that off. And it's
probably going to come back telling me
that it's already installed in our
project. And then, as you can see, it
says it's already enabled. And if we hop
back into our settings.json, we'll see
that cloud code experimental agent teams
is now set to one. Now, I know most of
you probably know about sub agents.
Claude can spin up other instances of
Claude to do different kinds of work.
You can change the model and you can
have it all report back to your main
cloud instance. But these sub agents
have a big limitation that agent teams
does not. They actually cannot
communicate with each other. Agent teams
is exactly that. It's a team. It's got a
team leader and then you got team
members who can all communicate with
each other before going back to the main
team agent. They can share information
like this agent can share information
with this agent. this agent can hand
things off to this agent and then they
all collaborate together before going
back to the team leader. Okay, so let's
put this into practice. So, I actually
chose a pretty specific prompt because
it does get finicky if you're not very
specific on spawning an agent team. If
you don't say that, Claude will probably
spawn a team of sub agents, which if you
see over here in the top left, I'll go
through an example of what that kind of
output looks like. But we're going to go
ahead run this prompt through spawn a
team of agents and we'll see the results
and then we'll compare them between
agent teams and sub agents. hop into
bypass permissions mode and send this
off. Okay, so the team of agents just
finished and we're going to go through
everything that they just did. So, the
video that they ended up deciding with
was the newest uh control your computer
feature, which I've seen a ton of great
content about already. It gives us the
reason why this one wins because it's
hot probably. It launched two days ago.
Follows the exact playbook that drove
your breakout video. Be the first to
applaud feature, although I'm definitely
not going to be the first one. We have a
feature walkthrough plus live demo,
which is the format of the video. It
gave us a built-in short, three
thumbnail options, and then it asked me
if it wants me to move it through my
script pipeline. All that being said,
these are all the tasks that it
completed. It created a video planning
team. It spawned a trend research
teammate, spawned performance analyst
teammate, and spawned a concept writer.
And then it coordinated the team and
delivered final video concept. You can
see here that these agents are sending
messages to each other. So these send
message functions. So send message to
concept writers, both research files
ready to go, right? Our performance
analyst agent sent a message to our
concept writer saying that it was
finished. And this right here just
breaks down our video planning team. It
then saved all three deliverables into a
video planning folder and then went
ahead and shut down the team cleanly. So
this is the result that we get from
using agent teams. But what about sub
aents? To hammer down that these prompts
need to be pretty specific. I thought
that this would work in spawning an
agent team. I said I need a team to help
me plan out my next YouTube video. Have
one member research what's trending in
AI automation this week. And then gave
another couple of tasks. I then gave it
the models and what the main agent
should use. It then just spawned a team
of sub agents to where we just went
through how we would typically go
through if you wanted to use multiple
agents. And then it gave us this result,
two video options, kind of older content
like why small businesses are ditching
Zapier for Naden. It gave us some key
insights, some performance flags and and
overall I wouldn't say the output is
horrible. Like there's probably some
good information here, but I definitely
like this agent teams example much
better. It gives me one clear video of
the most recent things that are coming
out. Just the biggest distinction here
is that these agents are actually
talking to each other whereas the sub
agents are all just performing tasks.
They have no idea what each person is
doing. So they're just they might be
duplicating information or just wasting
tokens. This next hidden feature is
called autodream. It's a secret
unreleased feature that Claude released
at some point and I only found out about
it from this expost from our friend
Anthony. Claude already has something
called automemory which allows it to
remember things in between sessions. But
over time those memory files tend to get
very bloated. overlapping notes,
outdated projects, and some things that
just don't really matter anymore. And
how Claude works, it's loading that
bloated information into every new chat
that you're starting. This new secret
autodream feature completely fixes that,
which is wild because sleep is exactly
how humans do the same thing. When
you're sleeping, your brain consolidates
memories, keeps what matters, and then
throws out the thoughts that don't. At
least I think. I'm not a sleep expert,
but that's exactly what this autodream
feature does. In order to enable this
autodream feature, you're going to have
to hop into your Claude Code terminal.
You're going to type in /memory. This
will open up your memory settings. And
then you'll see here at the top that
there's an autodream feature as well as
automemory. Automemory is on by default.
Autodream is not. You have to go turn it
on. You'll also be able to see when you
last ran it. And then it'll tell you to
do /dream to run. However, if you run
/dream, it's going to say unknown skill
dream. So the only other way that I
found out to run this is to just tell
Claude to run your autodream. So now
it's going to go ahead and start running
the autodream. Now you can see it says
got it. Running a dream cycle memory
consolidation on your memory files. Let
me go through all the four phases. It
has four different phases that it goes
through and then it'll come back to me
with all my consolidated files. Then it
ran phase two which gathered the signal
and then it identified some issues
inside of our current project. Now it's
executing phase three which is
consolidation. Our dream cycle finished
up here and here's everything that it
did. Consolidated some files, updated
some files, pruned a couple of files and
then kept any unchanged ones and then
flagged some opportunities for me. That
took about 3 minutes and 15 seconds. And
this autodream feature is like giving
Claude a brain defrag. And the more you
use it, the better it gets over time.
Knowing what context actually matters to
you. This next one is all about privacy
and control. Claude actually sends a lot
of your data over to something called
statig. Statsig essentially tracks usage
patterns and operational data like
latency and reliability. This data is
really used to test new features and
drive analytics. Bot also sends data to
Sentry for error logging, which allows
Anthropic to diagnose crashes and bugs
that are in production. Now, if you're
like me and you want control over all
your data, you're going to hop into your
settings.json JSON once again and then
you're going to add these three lines
right here. Disable telemetry, disable
error reporting, and cloud code disable
feedback survey. All of them should have
a number one next to it and you're good
to go. Now, this one's completely
optional, but if you want to keep some
of your data private, then you can
definitely flip these on. Now, these
last two are incredibly simple, but I
promise you once you use them, you'll
never go back. The first one is called a
hook, which essentially plays a sound
every time Claude is finished with a
task. You can set this up in natural
language by saying something like, "I
need you to set up a hook every single
time you finish a task. I want you to
play some sort of dinging noise
notifying me that you've finished." So
Claude created our hook. It created it
in a settings.json. I would just have
that moved into my settings.json. But if
we go ahead and open up a new tab and
hop into it, if I type something in
like, "Hi," you should hear a message
come back with a little bit of a ding.
Any minute now, we should hear a little
bit of a ding. There you go. And that'll
carry on through sessions because now
it's in our settings. local.json. And
then quickly for the last one, you can
actually name your tabs in cloud code. I
for how much I use it. The fact that I
just found this out is pretty cool. But
for example, I put in two new tabs. This
one I wanted to create an app. So I
could just change it to app creation.
And in this one, I asked it to tell me
about myself and I could just name it
bio. So now I look in my tabs and I have
bio and app creation. Super simple, but
sometimes those are the best. Okay, so
that covers all the hidden skills that I
wanted to show you guys in this video. I
also wanted to show you guys my final
settings.json JSON setup which will be
in the free resource guide. All you need
to do is join my free school community
and you'll have access to this document.
Just for transparency, I'll scroll
through this for you guys. We have all
the settings that we set up. We have our
hooks in here and then we have some
permissions down at the bottom.
Hopefully at this point you've seen
something that popped out to you and is
really going to help you maximize your
cloud code setup. As always, if you've
gotten any value from this video, drop a
like, hit that subscribe button. It
definitely helps me out a ton. Leave a
comment down below on which of these
hidden settings you're going to
implement first. I drop videos every
Tuesday and Friday. And if you've made
it this far in the video, thank you so
much. And I'll see you in the next one.
God bless, guys. Hey, if you're still
there, something I like to do at the end
of all my videos, is pray for you guys,
my audience. I do this because I
genuinely care about each and every one
of you. I really thank you for taking
time out of your days to watch my
videos, and I just love you guys. I know
that this is a little bit weird. Trust
me, the first time someone prayed over
me, I was uh was a little weirded out.
So, I totally understand. If uh if
you're uncomfortable at all, please feel
free to click off the video and I'll see
you guys next week. I'm going to stop
talking and go ahead and pray for you
guys.
Heavenly Father, thank you so much for
this day. Thank you so much for your
sovereignty in our lives. Thank you,
Lord, just for all the opportunities
that you've laid out at our feet and
have given us the opportunity to just
chase. Lord, I just want to pray for my
audience. I want to send them off with a
blessing, Lord, that they just live a
life of peace, live a life of wisdom,
live a life of just happiness, Lord. And
I just pray that in all of this time of
of where this world is at with all these
wars, all this uncertainty, AI taking
over, uh Lord, I just pray that you
bless us with this peace, with this
peace that understanding that one day
you're going to return and none of this
stuff is going to matter. Uh Lord, I
just continuously thank you for
everything that you do in my life and
everything that you do in my viewers'
lives. Lord, just continue to keep us
near to you. Continue to hold us strong
in our faith. Continue to bless us with
strength, Lord, so we can continue to
glorify you in everything that we do
because that is the ultimate goal.
Glorify you and serve others. Lord, I
just one thing for myself. I just want
to pray for the wisdom to do the thing
that you put me on this earth to do in a
way that pleases you and serves the
people you put me here to serve. Lord,
give my viewers wisdom to continue
serving their customers, their families,
anyone in their lives that have meaning
to them. And Lord, let them just be let
them just have a serving attitude. I
pray all this in the name of Jesus
Christ. Amen. Go have a blessed day,
guys. And I'll see you next week.