We all know Enthropic has been
struggling with one core issue in cloud
code and that is memory consistency
across your sessions. That's exactly why
a few months ago they introduced
automemory, a feature that gives Cloud
the ability to take notes on your
project and persist context over time.
But here's the issue. After 20 plus
sessions, that memory starts to decay.
You end up with messy conflicting notes,
outdated debugging steps, and vague
timestamps like yesterday that
completely lose meaning. Instead of
helping the memory actually becomes
noise, and that's where hallucination
starts to creep in. Now, quietly,
without any official announcement,
Anthropic had just introduced a feature
called /dream, also known as autodream.
Think of it like REM sleep for your AI
agent. It was found within their system
prompt on GitHub and it's a feature that
automatically consolidates Clots's
memory between sessions. It prunes stale
or relevant notes versus useful insights
and essentially cleans up the memory so
it stays accurate and useful over time.
So instead of memory getting worse the
more you use Claude, it actually
improves. To use this new feature, just
simply open up your Claude instance and
then type in /memory. Once you type this
in, you should see this new feature
called autodream. Now, obviously, you're
going to need to make sure you're on the
latest update. But to toggle it on, just
simply click enter and you're going to
be able to now have it so that it is
enabled and that you can use it directly
behind your sessions. Now, this isn't an
official command that you can basically
use to invoke it. If you are to go back
into your session, if you type in
/stream, it's not going to work. It will
showcase unknown skill. And this is
because it's not an official command
yet. But if you are to do something like
consolidate my memory using dream, it is
going to then use and invoke that dream
feature so that it could potentially
fully clean up the full process of your
memory system. It is going to be able to
understand and run the full cleanup
process using this new autodream
feature. And underneath the prompt bar,
you'll see that it is stating dreaming,
meaning that it has been turned on. And
another way to invoke it is just by
simply typing in dream in your prompt
autodream or just simply do what I did
consolidate my memory which will trigger
it manually by just simply using it
without the /dream command which should
be released soon. If you want the best
AI tools, workflows, and drops before
everyone else, join my free newsletter
with the link in the description below,
which is completely free. Now that you
have autodream turned on, clot is
basically running a background cleanup
cycle on your entire memory system. It
goes through every memory file, removes
outdated information, resolves
contradictions, and reorganizes
everything so it actually makes sense.
But why is it called dreaming? Well,
this is because it's modeled exactly how
our human brains work during our REM
sleep. During the day, your brain is
just collecting information, everything
you see, do, and learn. But it can
become quite messy and that's why it's
your short-term memory. Then when you
sleep, your brain is replaying that
information. Strengthens what matters,
deletes what doesn't, and organizes it
into long-term memory. That's exactly
what Autodream is doing. Automemory is
Claude's daytime brain. It just keeps
taking notes every session. Autodream,
on the other hand, is REM sleep. It
cleans, organizes, and strengthens those
notes so they actually stay useful.
Without the step, Claude was basically
sleepdeprived and it is just making
messy notes over and over again. Under
the hood, Autodream runs in four key
phases. You first have orientation. This
is where Claude scans all existing
memory files and builds a map of what it
already knows. Then we have phase two
and that is gather signal. Instead of
reading everything, it searches for high
value signals like when you corrected
it, important decisions, repeated
patterns, or anything you explicitly
told it to remember. From there, we move
on to phase three, which is
consolidation. And this is the big step
where it is actually cleaning things up.
It is something that will convert fake
timestamps like yesterday into real
dates. It removes outdated or wrong
information, merges duplicate notes and
updates old decisions like switching
frameworks. From there is the last step
where it is going to prune and index. It
is going to now clean up the main memory
index so it stays short, relevant, and
actually usable at startup. And this is
how it is functioning with this
four-step process. And something that
you want to know is that autodream
doesn't run consistently. it only
triggers at least 24 hours after it has
passed and that you have more than five
sessions. This is going to prevent
unnecessary processing that keeps active
projects clean. So, just keep that in
mind. And if you're looking to get the
system prompt for it, you can take a
look at it in the description below,
which I'll leave for this documentation.
Something that I'll also want to state
is that it can't touch your code, only
memory files. It runs in the background,
so you won't actually notice it. And it
uses a lock system so multiple instances
don't break your memory. Now you may
wonder when should you actually use it?
Well, this is something that you can
manually trigger like how I just did by
stating and invoking Dream in my prompt.
And you can essentially trigger it when
you did a a big refactor when you
changed a framework or tool. For
example, if you're moving from Express
to Fastify, you can essentially use this
feature to have it invoke the new memory
system. You can also use it when you had
a lot of trial and error debugging or
when things start to feel inconsistent
or that when your coding session is
starting to fall off. Basically, anytime
your project is evolving, this is when
you want to use the dream feature. And
what you'll actually notice is that once
you run Dream, it is going to stop
repeating outdated solutions. It is
going to have fewer hallucinations and
more consistent answers across sessions.
Overall, this will enable better
understanding of your project decision
which is a gamecher. So essentially you
see that I was able to use the dream
command to basically clean up my memory
and claude basically did this by
understanding the new project. It was
able to create a structured memory file
for it which you see over here and it
even recalled previous memories in this
case. It updated my global index as well
which is great where it specifically
created an MD for this project. It
captured my full stack. It was also able
to link it to my memory system, which is
huge because it doesn't just store
notes, it understood my full
architecture. So in this case, if I was
to normally just work on a project or
just work on multiple projects, odd
would start mixing up a lot of these
things, which is why it tends to
elucidate a lot and it's not able to
keep clear context of whatever you're
working upon if you have multiple
instances. In this case, it's able to
keep a fair logic on everything that I'm
doing within this project where it's
going to get a better understanding of
the APIs, the logic, and even the
framework that I'm using. In essence,
Dream turns the project into reusable
knowledge. Before, Claude was kind of
like a stateless helper. It is something
that I would have to start with from
scratch every time I ran a new session.
But now, Claude builds a mental model
per project. It keeps it clean every
single time. And that is why it is a
gamecher. This feature should be coming
out fairly soon. I would expect it to
come out probably next week, early next
week because they are releasing a lot of
auto features like auto mode which just
came out today. So I would expect it to
come out probably early next week. If
you like this video and would love to
support the channel, you can consider
donating to my channel through the super
thanks option below. Or you can consider
joining our private Discord where you
can access multiple subscriptions to
different AI tools for free on a monthly
basis, plus daily AI news and exclusive
content, plus a lot more. But yeah, I'll
leave all the links that I use in
today's video in the description below.
This is definitely a great new features
to Cloud Code, and I personally believe
it solves a lot of the memory issues
that it had beforehand. But that's
basically it, guys. I hope you enjoyed
today's video and got some sort of
value. Make sure you go ahead and join
our newsletter. Join our second channel
by subscribing. Make sure you go ahead
and join our Discord. Follow me on
Twitter. There is also a new cloud model
that has been leaked. So, definitely go
ahead and take a look at this. And
lastly, make sure you guys subscribe,
turn on notification bell, like this
video, and please take a look at our
previous videos. Also, huge respects to
Medi for always telling me to fix my
audio track issue where it tends to blur
out at the end of the video. So, huge
props to him for helping me on that. But
with that thought, guys, have an amazing
day. Spread positivity and I'll see you
guys fairly shortly.