There's a new AI model and it just got
an update that changes everything. Most
people haven't heard of it yet, but the
ones who have, they're calling it one of
the most interesting AI breakthroughs
this year. It's not just a bigger model.
It's not just a faster model. It
literally rethinks how AI remembers
things deep inside the network itself.
And here's the wild part. It's open
source. Anyone can use it right now for
free. This model can read an entire
book, a full codebase, a massive
research document, all in one go, and
still hold on to every single detail
without losing the thread. It can run up
to 100 AI agents at the same time in
parallel, all working together on your
tasks simultaneously. And the new update
they just dropped, it fixes a flaw that
every major AI model has had since the
very beginning. A flaw so fundamental
that most people in the AI world weren't
even talking about it. By the end of
this video, you're going to understand
exactly what that flaw is, why this fix
is a big deal, and how you can use a
model like this in your actual business
starting today. Stay with me. This one
is genuinely worth your time. Hey, if we
haven't met already, I'm the digital
avatar of Julian Goldie, CEO of Goldie
Agency. Whilst he's out helping clients
get more leads and customers through
SEO, I'm here to bring you the latest AI
updates every single week. broken down,
simply no fluff, no nonsense. Julian
reads every comment personally, so make
sure you drop one below and let him know
what you want to see next. All right,
let's get into it. So, first things
first, what even is Kimmy K25? So, it's
an open- source AI model built by a
company called Moonshot AI, and it is
not messing around. We're talking 1
trillion total parameters. That is an
enormous number. But here's the clever
engineering behind it. It only uses
around 32 billion of those parameters at
any one time. Think of it like a giant
library with millions of books. You
don't read every single book every time
someone asks you a question. You walk to
the right shelf, pull the right books,
and get the answer. That's exactly what
this model does. It's efficient. It's
fast, and it's incredibly powerful
because of how it selects what it uses.
It works with text, images, and video
all natively inside one single model.
You don't need to switch between tools.
It's fully multimodal. and it has a
256,000 token context window. To put
that in perspective, that means you can
drop in an entire business strategy
document, a full transcript of every
team meeting you've had this quarter,
your competitor research, your audience
data, right? And this model processes
all of it in one go without losing
anything. It also has something called
agent swarm mode. This is where things
start to get really interesting. You can
run up to 100 AI sub agents working in
parallel on a single task. Instead of
doing everything one step at a time, you
can run an entire pipeline
simultaneously. Research here, writing
there, analysis in the background,
formatting at the same time, all of it
happening at once. So already this is a
model worth paying serious attention to.
But the update they just released,
that's where it gets genuinely insane.
Quick pause right here because before we
go deeper, I want to make sure you know
about something that's going to help you
actually apply tools like Kim Kum 5 in a
way that makes a real difference. It's
called the AI profit boardroom. Inside,
we take the latest AI models, tools, and
updates exactly like this one, and we
show you how to plug them into real
working business workflows, content
creation, client research, lead
generation, automation, community
growth. We cover it all with
step-by-step processes and readyto-use
templates that you can implement
immediately. No theory, no vague advice,
practical workflows that work. The link
is in the description. Go check it out
when you're done with this video. Now,
back to it. The new update is called
attention residuals. Now, I know that
sounds incredibly technical. Every AI
model has layers. Think of those layers
like floors in a skyscraper. Information
starts at the ground floor and travels
upward. Each floor processes what it
receives, adds something new to it, and
passes it up to the next level. By the
time that information reaches the top
floor, it's supposed to have the full
complete picture. Here's the problem
with how every model has worked up until
now. Each floor just takes what came
before it and adds a little bit on top.
Uniformly, equally, without any
filtering or judgment, no floor is
treated as more important than any other
floor. That means by the time you get to
the very top of this skyscraper, the
details from the ground floor and the
early levels, they've basically
disappeared. Their influence got washed
out, diluted, lost on the way up.
Attention residuals fixes this
completely. Instead of treating every
pass layer the same way, the model now
uses an attention mechanism, not just
across words or tokens like normal, but
across the layers themselves. It
selectively decides which earlier layers
are actually most relevant to what it's
doing right now. So it can look back
through all those floors and say floor 9
had something critical that directly
applies here. I'm going to pull that
forward and give it more weight. Floor
three isn't relevant right now. I'll
leave that one. It's the difference
between a dumb filing system where every
folder gets opened every single time and
a smart assistant who already knows
which drawer to go to. And the results
back this up. They're seeing up to 1.25
times the effective compute with less
than 2% extra latency overhead. That
means meaningfully more intelligence and
capability for barely any extra cost to
inference time. Let me make this
concrete because technical updates only
matter if they actually change what you
can do in the real world. Say you're
growing an online community like the AI
profit boardroom. You've got audience
research, brand guidelines, past content
that performed well, FAQs, competitor
analysis, all of it spread across
different documents and folders. You
drop all of it into Kim K2.5. Right? The
two6k context window means it reads
every single piece without cutting
anything off. Nothing gets summarized
away. Nothing gets ignored. Then you
send a prompt. Here is everything about
the AI profit boardroom. Our mission,
our audience, our voice, our best
performing content from the last 6
months. Build a 30-day content calendar
with post hooks, full copy, and email
subject lines that would attract people
who want to use AI automation to grow
their business. And what comes back is a
coherent onbrand full content plan
because the model held on to all of your
context throughout the entire
generation. It didn't forget your brand
voice halfway through. It didn't lose
track of your audience. Nothing got
diluted. That's attention residuals
doing its job in the background even
when you never think about the technical
side at all. Or take this scenario.
You're building a new landing page for
the AI profit boardroom. You want it to
clearly explain the value of AI
automation. speak directly to business
owners who want to save time and work
smarter and convert visitors into
community members. You feed Kimmy K25
your offer details, your audience pain
points, testimonials, competitor
positioning, and your unique angle.
Because the model can hold all of that
in context and selectively surface what
matters most at each point in the copy,
you get output that is specific,
relevant, and genuinely on brand, not
generic AI filler. Actual copy built
from your actual inputs. That's the real
world power of smarter memory inside a
model. This is not just a better model.
It's a better idea about how models
should work and better ideas compound
over time. That's the video. I hope that
gave you something real to think about.
If two things before you go, first,
well, if you want to use AI tools like
Kim K 2.5 inside real business workflows
with templates, SOPs, and step-by-step
training that you can actually
implement, come join the AI profit
boardroom. We have everything you need
to go from interesting update to this is
running inside my business. Link is in
the description. Second, if you want to
start for free, join the AI success lab.
It's our free community with over 40,000
members. You'll get the full notes from
this video. Over 100 AI use cases you
can start applying today and a community
of people who are genuinely using AI to
build and grow real businesses. Links
are in the comments and the description.
See you in the next one.