New Miniax M2.7 is insane. This AI just
helped build itself and now it can build
stuff for you. We're talking full apps,
full projects, full workflows. No joke.
And I'm going to show you exactly how to
use it today. So, here's the deal. Most
AI tools work like this. You type
something in, you get an answer back.
That's it. That's how chat GPT works.
That's how most of these tools work. You
ask it answers done. Miniax M2.7 is
different. Way different. This thing
doesn't just answer your questions. It
runs entire jobs for you like a team,
not one assistant. A whole team of AI
agents working together. And the
craziest part, it helped improve itself.
The AI made itself better. Let that sink
in for a second. Now, before you think
I'm making this up, let me break it down
real simple. Mini Max built something
called an agent harness.
Think of it like a brain upgrade for AI.
It gives the model its own skills, its
own memory, and its own tools. So
instead of forgetting everything after
one chat, it remembers, it learns, it
gets better over time. And here's where
it gets wild. The model runs these
loops. It goes analyze, plan, fix, test,
repeat over and over on its own. No
human needed. That's what they mean by
self- evolving. The AI is literally
improving itself through practice, like
a student who does homework, checks the
answers, fixes mistakes, and keeps
going. Except this student never sleeps.
Now, let me tell you what this thing can
actually do because that's what matters,
right? Hey, if we haven't met already,
I'm the digital avatar of Julian Goldie,
CEO of SEO agency, Goldie Agency. Whilst
he's helping clients get more leads and
customers, I'm here to help you get the
latest AI updates. First up, it can
build full software projects start to
finish. You give it a goal, and it
writes the code, tests it, fixes the
bugs, and ships it. The benchmark score
on real coding tasks is 56.2% on S. E
Pro that's up there with the best models
in the world right now. Second, office
work, presentations, spreadsheets,
documents, it scored 1495 ELO on office
tasks. That's the top score for any open
source model. So if you need a pitch
deck or a report or a data breakdown,
this thing handles it. Third, research.
It can dig through information, pull out
what matters, organize it, and give you
a clean summary. They say it can handle
30 to 50% of real research and
development workflows on its own. That's
not a small number. And it has a massive
context window around 200,000 tokens.
That means you can feed it huge
documents, long conversations, big code
bases, and it keeps track of everything.
No cutting corners, no forgetting
halfway through. Now, let me show you
how this actually works in real life.
Say you're running a business like the
AI Profit Boardroom, and you need a full
onboarding system for new members. You
could tell Miniaax M2.7 something like,
"Built me a welcome email sequence for
the AI profit boardroom that explains
the value of AI automation, walks new
members through their first week and
gets them excited to take action." And
it doesn't just write one email. It maps
out the whole sequence, subject lines,
body copy, timing, everything. Or say
you need a content calendar. You can
say, "Create a 30-day content plan for
the AI profit boardroom that covers AI
automation tips, case studies, and
community highlights to drive engagement
and attract new members." And boom, it
plans all out topics, angles, hooks,
dates done. Or maybe you want a landing
page outline.
You tell it, "Design a high converting
landing page structure for the AI profit
boardroom that shows the value of AI
automation, lists the benefits of our
community, and gets more customers,
leads, and traffic. It gives you the
full layout, headlines, sections, call
to action spots, the whole thing. That's
the power of an AI that works like a
team. You give it one goal and it breaks
it down into steps and executes. And one
more thing, if you're creating all this
content, but nobody's finding it online,
you got a traffic problem. That's where
SEO comes in. If you want more leads,
more traffic, and more customers, my
team can help you rank higher on Google.
Check the link in the comments in
description to order AI SEO online and
let us handle your back links while you
focus on growing your business. And if
you want to rank number one and get more
customers, join the SEO elite circle.
That's where we actually teach you how
this works. No theory, no recycle tips,
just the exact AI SEO systems we're
using right now. We break everything
down step by step with real workflows,
weekly live support, and clear actions
you can follow without guessing. If
you're serious about scaling with SEO
and AI, this is where you start. Hit the
link in the description and join the SEO
elite circle today. Okay, so let's talk
about why this matters for you. Because
there's a bigger picture here. Up until
now, AI has been a tool. You use it, you
control it, you tell it what to do every
step of the way. Miniax M2.7 is one of
the first models that starts to change
that. It's not just a tool anymore. It's
a system that can manage itself. Think
about what that means for the next few
years. Right now, you need to sit there
and prompt the AI over and over. Write
this, fix that, try again. But with
self-evolving models, the AI does that
loop on its own. It tries something,
checks if it worked, makes it better,
tries again without you babysitting it.
That's huge for anyone running a
business because time is the one thing
you can't get back. And if an AI can
take a task that used to take you 3
hours and do it in 10 minutes with no
handholding, that changes everything.
Now, here's something I want you to
think about. The multi- aent part. This
isn't one AI doing one thing. This is
multiple AI agents working together. One
handles the code, one handles the
research, one handles the writing, one
checks for errors, they pass work back
and forth like a real team. Imagine
having that for the AI profit boardroom.
One agent builds your email campaigns,
another one creates your social media
posts, another one analyzes what's
working and what's not, and they all
talk to each other. That's not science
fiction anymore. That's what this model
is built to do. Now, I'm not saying
Miniax M2.7 is perfect. No model is.
It's still early. The self-evolution
stuff is still in its beginning stages,
but the direction is clear. AI is moving
from being a thing you talk to to a
thing that works for you. And the people
who figure out how to use these tools
first are the ones who win. Let me give
you one more example. Say you're
building out a new course for the AI
profit boardroom on how to use AI
automation to save time. You can tell
Miniax M2.7. Plan a six module course on
AI automation for business owners.
Create lesson outlines, suggest
practical exercises, and draft copy one
prompt. Multiple outputs all connected.
All done by the AI team inside the
model. That's the future and it's
happening right now. So, here's what I
want you to do. Go try Miniax M2.7. Play
with it. Test it on real tasks. See what
it can do for your business. Push it.
Break it. Learn it. Because the people
who learn these tools early are always
the ones who come out ahead. Julian
Goldie reads every comment, so make sure
you comment below. Tell me what you
think about self-evolving AI. Does it
excite you? Does it scare you? Drop your
thoughts. I read every single one. And
one more thing, if you're creating all
this content, but nobody is finding it
online, you've got a traffic problem.
That's where SEO comes in. If you want
more leads, more traffic, and more
customers, my team can help you rank
higher on Google. Check the link in the
comments and description to order AI SEO
online and let us handle your back links
while you focus on growing your
business. And if you want to rank number
one and get more customers, join the SEO
elite circle. That's where we actually
teach you how this works. No theory, no
recycled tips you've heard a thousand
times, just the exact AI SEO systems
we're using right now to grow real
businesses. We break everything down
step by step with real workflows, weekly
live support, and clear actions. you can
follow without guessing. You don't need
to figure it out alone. You don't need
to waste months testing stuff that
doesn't work. We've already done that
part. All you have to do is follow the
system. If you're serious about scaling
with SEO and AI, this is where you
start. Hit the link in the description
and join the SEO Elite Circle today. All
right, thanks for watching and I'll see
you in the next