This new Chinese AI model is insane.
This new Chinese AI model is insane. It
just replaced an entire industry with
one single model. And the crazy part,
nobody is talking about it yet. So, let
me show you exactly what it does, why it
matters, and how you can use it right
now. Today, I'm going to show you a
brand new AI model that just dropped out
of China. It's called Chenfan OCR, and
honestly, it's one of the wildest things
I've seen in AI this year. This thing
reads documents like a human. Tables,
charts, formulas, invoices, you name it.
One model does it all. No complicated
setup, no messy tools, just pure clean
results. And by the end of this video,
you're going to understand exactly why
this changes everything. So, let me
break it down for you. First, you need
to understand the problem right now. If
you want AI to read a document like a
PDF or an invoice, you need a whole
chain of tools. You need one tool to
figure out the layout, another tool to
read the text, another tool to
understand the text, and then maybe
another tool to give you a clean output.
That's four or five different steps. And
here's the thing, every single step can
break. Every single step can mess up.
And when one step fails, the whole thing
falls apart. It's like building a house
of cards. One wrong move, and it all
comes down. And this is what most
businesses are dealing with right now.
Messy pipelines, broken workflows, hours
wasted fixing, errors. It's a nightmare.
And I know this because at my agency, we
deal with documents all day long. SEO
reports, client data, invoices,
contracts. The amount of time spent just
getting AI to read stuff properly is
wild. But that's about to change. And
here's why. BYU, one of the biggest tech
companies in China, just dropped this
model called Chan OCR. It's a 4 billion
parameter model. And what it does is
simple but insane. It takes that entire
pipeline I just told you about and
crushes it down into one single model.
One step, one pass, done. You feed it a
document, any document, a table, a
chart, a scanned receipt, a research
paper in any of 192 languages, and it
spits out clean, structured data,
markdown, JSON, whatever you need. No
chain of tools, no pipeline, no mess,
just one model that does everything.
Now, let me tell you the feature that
really blew my mind. And stick around
because this is the part nobody else is
going to explain to you. Hey, if we
haven't met already, I'm the digital
avatar of Julian Goldie, CEO of Goldie
Agency. Whilst he's helping clients get
more leads and customers, I'm here to
help you get the latest AI updates.
Julian Goldie reads every comment. So,
make sure you comment below. Okay, so
back to this insane feature. It's called
layout as thought. And when I first read
about it, I had to read it twice because
it sounded too good to be true. So,
here's how it works. Before this model
even reads a single word on your
document, it thinks about the layout
first. It looks at the whole page. It
figures out where the tables are, where
the headers are, where the columns start
and stop. It draws invisible bounding
boxes around everything. And then, and
only then does it start reading. Think
about that for a second. It's like chain
of thought reasoning, but for documents.
And the model literally thinks before it
reads.
That's why it's so accurate. It's not
just guessing. It's planning. It's
understanding the structure of the
document before it pulls any information
out and that's a game changer. Now,
here's where it gets even crazier. This
model is beating some of the biggest
names in AI right now. On the
benchmarks, it's outperforming models
from Google and other major players. And
it's doing it with just 4 billion
parameters. That's tiny compared to most
large language models, which means it's
faster, it's lighter, and it's way
easier to run. And here's what I want
you to think about. This isn't just
about OCR anymore. This is about a whole
new way. AI interacts with documents.
This is document intelligence. Let me
explain what I mean. Right now, most AI
tools read documents like a scanner.
They just pull text off a page. But
Shenfanocr doesn't just read. It
understands. You can ask it questions
about the document. You can tell it to
extract specific data. You can tell it
to summarize a table. You can tell it to
pull out key figures. And it does it in
one pass with one model. Now, if you're
sitting there thinking, "Okay, Julian,
this sounds cool, but how does this
actually help me?" Let me give you some
real use cases.
Number one, legal documents.
If you're a lawyer or you work with
contracts, imagine feeding the 50page
contract into this model and getting
back a clean summary with every key
clause highlighted. No more reading
through pages and pages of legal text
done in seconds. Number two, business
reports. If you run a company, imagine
feeding your quarterly reports into this
model and getting back clean structured
data you can drop straight into a
spreadsheet. No more manual data entry.
No more copy paste errors. Number three,
research papers. If you're a student or
a researcher, imagine feeding a dense
academic paper into this model and
getting back the key findings, the
methodology, and the conclusions in
clean bullet points. Hours of reading
done in seconds. Number four, receipts
and invoices.
If you run a business, imagine feeding
every receipt and invoice into this
model and getting back organized data
ready for your systems. No more shoe box
of receipts. No more headaches. Number
five, AI agents reading PDFs. This is
the big one. If you're building AI
workflows or automations, this model can
sit inside your pipeline and handle all
the document reading for you. One model,
no complexity. Just plug it in and go.
Now, here's the bigger picture, and this
is really important. This model is part
of a much larger trend in AI right now.
We're moving away from messy pipelines
where you need five or six different
tools chained together and we're moving
towards single models that do
everything. One model that sees, reads,
understands, and acts. That's the
future. And Chenfan OCR is one of the
first models to really nail this for
documents. Now, I want to be straight
with you because I always keep it real
on this channel. This model is not
perfect. is a 4 billion parameter model,
which means it's still heavy if you're
trying to run it on basic hardware. It's
not going to nail every single complex
layout perfectly, and it's still early
stage tech. So, don't go throwing out
all your other tools just yet. But as a
signal of where things are headed, this
is massive. And by the way, if you want
to learn how to use AI tools like Genfan
OCR to automate your business and save
hundreds of hours, check out my AI
profit boardroom. It's the best place to
scale your business. get more customers
and build real AI automations that
actually work. We're covering tools like
this every single week. I'll drop the
link in the description and comments
below. Okay, so let me tell you why
China keeps dropping these insane
models. And this is something most
people are completely ignoring while
everyone is focused on what's happening
in Silicon Valley. China is quietly
building some of the most powerful
document AI and vision language models
on the planet. BU alone has been pushing
the boundaries on this stuff for years
and Chenfan OCR is just the latest
example. Here's what you need to
understand. The AI race is not just
about chat bots. It's not just about who
has the best large language model. It's
about who can build models that actually
do useful work in the real world. And
reading documents, that's one of the
most useful things AI can do for
businesses. Every company on Earth deals
with documents. Every single one. So,
whoever cracks document intelligence
first gets a massive edge. And right
now, BYU is making a serious move. Now,
let me give you the quick breakdown of
what makes this model different from
everything else out there. Old school
OCR uses multiple steps. Detect the
layout, recognize the text, understand
the meaning. Each step is a separate
model. Each step can fail. Kenfan OCR
does all of that in one single pass. One
model, one step, clean output. That's
the difference. It's simpler, it's
faster, and it's more accurate. And the
fact that it supports 192 languages
means this isn't just for English
documents. If you're working with global
clients, multilingual reports, or
international data, this model handles
it. That's huge for anyone running an
international business. So, what should
you do with this information? Here's my
advice. Keep your eyes on this model. Go
check out the hugging face page. Read
the research paper on a archive. start
testing it with your own documents
because the people who learn these tools
early are the ones who get the biggest
advantage. That's always how it works.
Early movers win. And look, this is just
one example of the kind of AI
breakthroughs that are happening every
single week right now. The speed of
innovation is insane. And if you're not
keeping up, you're falling behind.
That's just the reality. So, here's what
I want you to do right now. If you want
to stay ahead of every AI update like
this one and you want to learn how to
actually use these tools to grow your
business and automate your workflows,
join my AI profit boardroom. We break
down every major AI tool, every new
model, every automation strategy, and we
give you the exact steps to implement
it. Link is in the description and the
comments. And if you want the full
process, SOPs, and over a 100 AI use
cases like this one, join the AI success
lab. It's our free AI community. Links
in the comments and description. You'll
get all the video notes from there, plus
access to our community of 38,000
members who are crushing it with AI.
Make sure you smash that subscribe
button. Drop a comment below telling me
what you think about Tianfan OCR. Julian
reads every single one. and I'll see you
in the next