Hey, so I think that these scissors are
broken. These two different pieces came
apart. Do you know how I might be able
to fix this?
>> I see. It looks like these are designed
to come apart for cleaning. If you align
the rivet on one blade with the slot on
the other, they should slide back
together securely. Can you give that a
try?
>> There we go. I think I got it working.
>> Perfect. That's exactly how they
connect. They look like they're working
just fine now. Hey, so I was just
scrolling through my school community
and I was curious if you know you were
able to see these different posts and
specifically the one about the clawed
usage limits.
Yes, I can see the different posts in
the AI automation society community. I
see one from Vashal Chojik titled Claude
limits me four times in 20 hours. Anyone
else facing this? Is that the one you
were referring to?
>> Yeah. Wow. I scrolled past that really
quick and you were still able to pull
that out. All right, so Google just
dropped Gemini 3.1 Flash Live, which is
their latest voice model that has a lot
of upgrades. In fact, you can even see
right here in this video, they're
calling it their biggest upgrade yet.
The whole idea is that this is way more
human because it's no longer doing
speech to text and then text to speech.
It's just straight up speech to speech
and it can also see things as you guys
saw in that quick demo beforehand. So,
this model is said to have improved
precision, lower latency, and just more
fluid natural interactions. Now, this
first benchmark is about multi-step
function calling, which it has
outperformed the previous Gemini 2.5
Flash model by about 19% here, as you
can see. And here's another one called
Audio Multi- Challenge, where it's not
only outperforming the previous Gemini
models, but also different models from
different providers. One thing that I
think is really cool is this is
apparently a huge step up when it comes
to the agent being able to listen in
noisy environments. Like if you're on
the side of the road or if you're in a
noisy restaurant or workspace, which
obviously if you're in a real world
environment and you want to set up voice
agents for a business, that's probably
really important. So here's a quick
example and I'm going to call out some
of the benefits. So we know that it's
speech to speech. We know that there is
less latency and we know that it can
work in noisy environments. So there's
the first one. You might hear, you know,
on the side of the road, things like
traffic, things like horns. I can look
you up with your registration plate and
postcode instead. Could you provide
those for me, please?
>> Whoa. And it's still able to be unfased
by stuff like that. It also has a higher
level of accuracy when it comes to alpha
numeric strings. And because it's
interpreting speech rather than speech
being transcribed into text, there's way
more contextual awareness because the
audio is coming through and it can
understand things like sarcasm or stress
or frustration, which is obviously very
important if you're setting up something
like a customer support bot or maybe
like a sales type of agent. Now, because
of the reasoning and thinking and the
tool calling ability, there's also this
cool demo here where this person is
talking to Gemini 3.1 Flash and the
talking leads to things actually
happening. So, in this case, they're
basically vibe coding, which is their
voice. They're saying to zoom in.
They're saying to change the background.
They're saying to do all these things.
And on the side panel, the agent is
actually coding as well. And I think
it's really cool because I could
definitely see a world where at some
point our operating systems basically
just work with voice. So, if you want to
try this out, you can do it for
completely free. Just go to Google AI
Studio and then come to this screen that
looks like this. And all you have to do
is in the top right, you just have to
find the model. So, by default, when you
get in here, it might just be on all or
whatever. You're going to go over here
to live and then you're going to click
on Gemini 3.1 Flash live preview. Now,
yes, there are some prices down here,
but you'll notice when I click on this,
you can see that it says no API key. So,
that means I'm on a free plan right now.
I've not given it any billing
information, and I could later switch to
a paid API key to unlock higher quota
and more features. But, right now, you
can get in here and just play around
with it for completely free. Now, the
first thing I noticed when I started
talking to this thing is that it is way
quicker and that it actually lets you
interrupt it. So, a lot of times with
other voice agents, you get into this
awkward like game of chicken of like
who's going to speak or if you try to
interrupt it, you guys both sort of like
say, "Oh, sorry. No, you go. You go."
And it's just like weird. But in this
case, and I'll I'll show you guys when I
start talking over it, it just stops
like immediately and it feels a lot more
human. So, I'm basically just going to
go ahead and just do the talk. Earlier,
you guys saw that I could do a webcam or
share screen, but for right now, I'm
just going to go ahead and talk. Now, it
is listening to me right now. Hey,
Gemini. How's it going? Can you hear me?
Yes, I can hear you clearly. Things are
going well here. Just ready to chat or
help with whatever you need. How are you
doing?
>> Yeah, I mean the voice sounds really
good. The latency is good. Um, once
again, how are you doing?
>> I'm doing great.
>> Actually, you know what? I don't really
care about how you're doing. Can you
just tell me a little bit more about the
voice model?
>> Sure, I can tell you about it. it.
>> Okay, so I was just a little rude, but
basically what I was trying to show you
is how fast it is and when I interrupted
it, how fast it stopped talking, which I
think was really impressive. Now, what
you can do in here in Google AI Studio
is basically just build your own little
voice agents right in here because we're
able to set up system instructions. So,
right here, we can create instructions
and we can save them. So, let's say in
this one, I'm calling this my coach and
in here I can give it tone and style
instructions. So, I can say, "You are my
personal um fitness coach. You will help
me get on a plan to eat healthier, build
muscle, stuff like that. And you also
have a very strong Scottish accent."
So, that is the new prompt here. This
has been saved and we can create new
ones. And now, if I go ahead and talk to
my coach, let's hear it.
Hey there. I'm thinking about taking a
break from the gym for about three
weeks. What do you think about that?
>> Three weeks? Hey. Well, it depends on
why you're taking the break. If it's for
rest and recovery.
>> Wow, you got a pretty strong accent out
of nowhere.
>> Ah, well, sometimes it just comes out
stronger, you can. But back to your
break. What's the reason behind it? Are
you feeling burned out or is there
something else going on?
>> Okay, that was funny. I just had to show
you guys though um how you're able to
really quickly change a lot of the stuff
about these agents. Yeah, let me just go
ahead and do one more webcam example.
Hey Gemini, how's it going? Just wanted
to make sure you can see me and that we
can have a conversation.
>> I can see you. You're in a room with
light gray walls, a shelf behind you
with some trophies, and a microphone in
front of you. Everything looks good from
my end, ready to chat. What's on your
mind?
>> What kind of microphone do you think I
have?
>> That looks like a shore MV7.
probably connected to that road arm. Is
that right?
>> Yeah, that is. You can see right here,
I've got the road and you can see right
here, this is the Shore M7. Well,
actually, I don't even know if this is
an MV7, but you probably know better
than I do.
>> Based on the design and the logo, it
definitely looks like an MV7.
>> I mean, I just think it's really cool
because you think about like, okay, you
know, there's still some flaws, but
where is this headed? And where might we
be able to at some point have like
agents that we can talk to almost like
it's a Zoom call? and we can see them
and they can talk to us and it's just
way more real feeling. And what other
doors does that actually open? And then
with the whole screen sharing thing and
vision, think about like where we're
also headed with computer use and the
fact that now when the agent can
actually take over your screen and take
control of your browser and click on
things, but it can also watch over you
and you can talk to it at the same time.
Like at some point we really might be
able to just like throw out our
keyboards, throw out our our mice and
just be able to sit here, look at our
screens and talk and things will just be
happening and happening and like you can
be so productive in that way. Now there
are some other things you can do in
here. You can see you can change the
voice. If I end the session, we can
change the voice right here. There's
different ones to choose from. You can
change the media resolution and you can
also change whether they are low,
medium, or high thinking or just no
thinking at all, which is the default.
You can also come in here and play with
the session context. So there's a lot
bigger max context as well as target
context. And down here you can see that
we have a few other things. We have
function calling which you can turn on.
You have automatic function response.
And then we also have grounding with
Google search which means when you're
talking to it, it will do Google search
on the back end to answer your
questions. Now what you might notice in
here is okay, giving it tools, giving it
functions. That's awesome because you
might want it to do things in your
calendar or you know look at the emails
or look at the support tickets or
whatever it is. And so if we go ahead
and try to turn this on and we click on
edit we can basically define different
functions but we would have to give it
those actual you know code snippets or
whatever it is. So if we go to the API
documentation for examples, this is
where we could understand how we can
actually give our voice agent here in
Gemini hands basically tools. And that's
where the Gemini live API comes in
because this lets us actually connect
this voice model to different things
like our websites or potentially even
phone numbers and other things like that
so that we're not just stuck to using it
right here in Google AI Studio. Now in
here you can see that it goes over some
really nice use cases like e-commerce
you know shopping assistance even gaming
interactive NPCs nextG interfaces
healthcare financial services education
and something I think is really cool is
multilingual support. So it has over 70
supported languages which means not only
could you talk to it in a different
language but this thing could be a
really good real-time translator which
could be a very important use case. Now,
all of this kind of stuff right here,
the API documentation and, you know, the
different SDKs or ADKs that you can
actually use, this is where cloud code
really comes in and makes this thing
powerful because without cloud code or,
you know, a different type of coding
assistant or, you know, agent, you're
kind of stuck to using Gemini 3.1 Flash
Live in Google AI Studio. And so if you
wanted to connect it to something else,
you would have to be pretty technical to
understand how to do that because of the
way that this thing actually works on
the back end with websockets.
Now what I did is I gave my cloud code
project all of this documentation and I
had to do research and I had to figure
out how this stuff works so that it
could help me embed this into other
things and it could help me set up tool
calls and stuff like that. So let me
show you two quick examples of what I
was able to do with cloud code and this
new model. Okay, so here's a first
really simple example where we have this
embedded into a fake website. This is
called Apex. It's just like a keyboard
website. Obviously, this thing looks
very vibe coded and it is. And I just
wanted to do a really quick demo. So,
let's pretend that I wanted to embed
this on my product website, right? I
have this little button down here that I
can now click on and I get a Gemini 3.1
Flash agent. So, open this up.
Hey, so can you tell me a little bit
about Apex, like the brand and what I
can do here?
Welcome to Apex. We make premium
mechanical keyboards with great
switches, customizable features, and
durable builds.
>> Okay, cool. So, I don't really know that
much about keyboards, but could you help
me figure out which one might be best
for me out of these four options?
>> I'd love to help. To give you the best
recommendation, are you looking for
something for gaming, typing, or office
work?
>> Uh, no. I'm really just going to be
working in my office, but I might be
doing some traveling
>> for office work and travel.
>> Actually, you know what? I'm just going
to go with the 60% mode, but can you
tell me about the uh the shipping and
how long is this going to take?
>> Great choice. Free standard shipping
takes 5 to seven business.
>> Okay, so I was interrupting it there and
I was just showing you that you can give
it knowledge and that it feels super
super conversational. So the second
example is Arya and obviously this is
you know a very ugly interface but I
just wanted to show you guys what you
can do. So this one is one where I
actually gave it tools. So, it's able to
look at my ClickUp and it's able to look
at my calendar. So, this is obviously
just a few examples, but showing you how
you can build some functions around this
in case you wanted to have your agent do
things rather than just be
conversational. So, I'm going to start
talking to Arya.
Hey there. How are you doing today?
>> Hey, I'm doing pretty well. Thanks for
asking. Just here ready to help with
whatever you need.
>> Yeah. So, the first thing I need you to
do is can you look at my calendar for
tomorrow?
>> Sure thing. For tomorrow, Saturday,
March 28th, you have two things
scheduled. First, you've got a walk from
9:00 a.m. to 10:00 a.m. and then a
meeting from 12:30 p.m. to 1:30 p.m.
Anything you'd like to add or look into
more about those?
>> Yeah. Can you block off 3:00 p.m. to
5:00 p.m. and call it my research block?
>> Done. I've added a research block to
your calendar for tomorrow from 3 p.m.
to 5:00 p.m. Anything else?
>> Awesome. Yeah. So, for that research
block, if you could go into my ClickUp
and look up my research queue and see
anything that I currently have to do,
and also if you could go ahead and add
another to-do in here called uh
Microsoft.
>> I can definitely do that. First, I need
to navigate to your lists. Which
workspace should I check? Up at AAI or
rootrise media?
>> Yeah, the Upai space. And it will be in
um an upai consulting space. You're
looking for research queue.
All right, I've got it. In your up at AI
consulting space, I found the research Q
list. Currently, you have one task in
there called Chipotle. I've also gone
ahead and added a new task named
Microsoft to that list. Anything else?
>> Okay, so I went ahead and stopped that
and I just wanted to show you guys that
that works, right? But what you will
notice is that there was pauses while it
was actually calling those functions and
that is a current limitation of this
model. A lot of times what you want to
do with voice agents is you want to have
them keep talking as they are calling a
function because they call the function
and they have to wait for the response,
right? And you can usually prompt them
and have them working out so that they
talk so there's not awkward silences.
But right now with this Gemini 3.1 flash
live, it doesn't do that. And I think
that's just a matter of time till
obviously it it can. But it's it's
basically like you've got your
asynchronous or synchronous. So that is
one thing that you will need to keep in
mind right now with this model is that
when you call a function, the agent will
not be speaking. It's just going to stop
and it's going to wait till it gets a
response. And also keep in mind that
both of these sites and integrations
were made in under 30 minutes with me
just spinning up two different cloud
sessions and saying, "Hey, in this one I
want you to build me, you know, this use
case and in this one I want you to build
me this use case. Here are my API keys.
Have at it." The point is once you
actually sit down and you give it a
structured plan and you iterate and
iterate with cloud code, you can get way
better outputs than this. So this is the
project that I created just to spin up a
few demos, right? And what I did
basically is I opened up a fresh project
of cloud code. I threw in the
documentation like you know this API
documentation, this one, the function
calling. I gave it all this this
information and then I just said hey I
want you to analyze all this. And what
you even could do is say hey create a
resource guide in this folder called you
know Gemini
flash MD and just store all of this
information so later you can reference
it. And then from there I just started
asking it questions. How does this work?
What can you do? What should we do as a
demo? And then it was able to help me
come up with these two use cases that
are kind of different. And you can see
that everything has been organized into
this project. So what I'm going to do is
drop this exact folder, this whole
project into my Free School community.
The link for that is down in the
description. It's completely free. So
you guys can grab this and just kind of
analyze it and ask questions about it.
Now, along with that, I'll also attach a
resource guide that basically says,
"Hey, here's what the project does.
Here's all the things you need to know
about it. Here's where to find the
things and stuff like that. Really, the
best way to learn is just to get your
hands dirty and to ask a ton of
questions. Now that we're in here
though, there are a few things that I
wanted to tell you guys about. The first
one is kind of about the pricing. So,
yes, it is free, but what you'll notice
is that if we're in the studio, you can
see that it says switch to a paid API
key to unlock higher quota and more
features." So, what does that actually
mean? So, here's what that pricing could
look like once you start paying. It's
still really, really cheap, which is
great. But what's the difference? So,
obviously, it's free or it's paper
token. But on the free tier, your data
is used by Google to improve the
products. On the paid tier, it's not.
So, you're getting enterprisegrade
privacy. Your rate limits on the free
tier are much lower. Um, I think you can
only have like three active sessions
going or something like that. You get
obviously way more flexibility here if
you are paying. You also get things like
context caching and batch API. So, what
does all that pricing and token stuff
mean practically? So, for a 10-minute
call, you're roughly going to be paying
maybe about 14 cents. You have a
different charge for your input tokens
and a different charge for your output
tokens. But, of course, if you're just
playing around and you're testing
things, definitely just stay on the free
tier. Now, I will be honest, using a
platform like 11 Labs or something else
like that makes it so much easier to
actually just embed a widget on a
website because 11 Labs server basically
manages all of that and just puts it
onto your site. So, both of these two
demos right here are local hosts and
they're local hosts because it's really
easy for me to then just connect the
websocket with Gemini to my machine and
it all talks to each other really nice
and it works. So, if I wanted to then
push this website to versel or you know
somewhere live or if I already have a
website that is live and I wanted to
push you know this little widget onto
that site, it's not just super super
simple the same way that it would be
with something like 11 Labs. It's still
doable and cloud code will definitely be
able to get you there if you give it the
right planning information and you know
you give it the right documentation. But
I will just say it's not as simple. It's
not one click of a button the same way
that 11 Labs is. So that is what I
wanted to end off this video talking
about. So like we just talked about
11labs basically handles everything.
They host everything and it makes that
persistent websocket connection easier.
So you could basically just embed it
anywhere. But with Gemini Live, it
requires a persistent server process.
And this isn't stuff I understood,
right? this is stuff that I had at cloud
code research for me based on all the
documentation and figuring out how it
works. So that's really the mindset
shift here is a lot of things you're not
going to understand and you need to
understand them enough to understand how
do you communicate things and what do
you need to look into and how do you
make things safe but when I'm teaching
myself things I just have claude code or
perplexity or some AI research it I
prompt them in a way to make sure that
it's not hallucinating I always you know
am factchecking things as well but you
just adopt this mindset of being
genuinely curious and that's how you can
push this stuff a lot farther so
basically the point that I'm trying to
communicate here is Gemini's 3.1 flash
model is awesome And if you come into
the playground in the studio, you can do
a lot of cool stuff here with it. If you
want to start to think about how you can
embed it somewhere else or, you know,
customize your own tools and stuff,
cloud code helps you get there way
faster, way easier with natural
language. And then finally, if you want
to push this all onto like a live
production phone number or a live
production website, cloud code once
again will get you there, but you do
have to go back and forth a little bit
more and you have to be thinking about
how you actually transfer over things
like your keys and your connections and
a few things like that. But anyways,
that is going to do it for today's
video. So, if you guys learned something
new or if you enjoyed, please give it a
like. It helps me out a ton. And as
always, I appreciate you guys making it
to the end of the video. I'll see you on
the next one. Thanks everyone.