Antropic just released something huge
which is a brand new certification
program called the Claude Certified
Architect. It's a real exam pass or fail
and one of the most important things is
that it's based on five core domains.
Now whether you're trying to get
certified or you just want to get better
at using cloud code and becoming a
master of it then this entire syllabus
that they've put together will act as
the best resource for you to learn
exactly how to go from zero to hero. So
here's the deal. I went through the
entire exam guide myself, not through an
LLM. I read through every single page.
So, I'm going to synthesize this entire
exam guide into this video and break
down each and every concept for you. And
as a bonus, I'll share some resources
that should supercharge your learning
journey. So, this is the very guide that
I was discussing before. It is 40 pages
and it walks through everything from the
target candidate description of what
it's like to be a master of cloud code
in anthropics. Each and every paradigm
you should master and be prepared for.
There are some exam content response
types. There's some preamble around what
the exam entails, what the format is and
this is the most important part which is
the content outline and this is where it
breaks down the distribution of each and
every part. And beyond that, in each
area, it walks through a series of
scenarios. And you'll see that it's very
specific. It's not just about knowing
MCP tools. It's about understanding
exactly how to conceptualize each and
every part of said tool. If you scan
through all of this, you'll see exactly
how detailed it is, and it can be
overwhelming to many, which is why I
want to break down each and every
concept and go through every domain with
a fine tooth comb. So like I said, there
are five different domains that
Anthropic thinks that you need to know
before you can call yourself a Claude
code master. So the biggest one which is
27% of the exam is agent architecture.
So this is basically how Claude thinks
step by step how it coordinates with
other agents and most importantly how
you enforce rules that just telling
Claude in a prompt can't guarantee. If
you only study one domain, this is the
one. Now tool and MCP integration is at
18%. So this is how Claude connects to
the outside world, your databases, your
APIs, your file systems. And the number
one reason why agents call the wrong
tool is actually embarrassingly simple.
And we'll get to that shortly. So cloud
code configuration sits at 20%. This is
your CloudMD files, your skills, your
commands, and things like plan mode. And
most people dump everything into one
giant file. But the exam guide teaches
you how to split that into three layers.
So Claude isn't loading irrelevant tools
every single time you ask us something.
Ultimately, we have the prompt
engineering section. And this isn't just
about writing better prompts. The
certification is actually very specific
here. If you want Claude to give you
consistent output, show it two or three
real examples of exactly what you want.
That works better than writing a whole
paragraph of detailed instructions every
single time. And last but not least is
context management and reliability. So
here's the thing. Claude reads the
beginning and the end of what you give
it really well. But the stuff in the
middle sometimes can get fuzzy and
that's called lost in the middle logic.
So now that we've set the tone for
what's important, let's go through every
single one and we'll naturally start
with the largest and most important
which is the agentic architecture and
orchestration. Let's start with the very
engine that powers each and every cloud
agent which is the agentic loop. So
whether you're using cloud code, the
anthropic SDK or any agentic framework
that is built on top of claude, this is
what's happening each and every single
time you run an agentic workflow. So
your code first sends a request to
Claude and then Claude naturally
responds. The most important thing to
keep aware of is this stop reason right
here. You want to check this all the
time. If it says tool use, that means
Claude wants to go use a tool like
reading a file or running a command. you
can execute said tool, feeds the result
back, and then it goes again into this
endless loop. But in this case, it's not
actually endless. It goes up until a
very certain point. If it says something
like end turn, then that's essentially
Claude saying that I'm done. And that's
pretty much the entire engine over and
over again. Now, the exam guide points
three different areas where people make
mistakes in understanding the agentic
loop. And these are basically the anti
patterns. So, first reading clawed text
looking for phrases like I'm done or
task complete. That's unreliable and it
breaks all the time. Second, you don't
want to set limits like stopped after 10
loops. You don't know the level of depth
that Claude code needs to do yet to
accomplish a specific task. So, you
might be cutting off work that genuinely
needs 11 steps. And third, you don't
want to look at what Claude said to
figure out if it's finished. There's a
very specific field like I said
stop_reason
that exists for exactly this purpose.
It's the only thing that you should be
checking. Now if you're using cloud code
in a terminal then sometimes you won't
see this stop_reason. Every time cloud
code reads a file, executes a tool, runs
a command or spins a sub agent. This is
exactly the process and the patterns
that drive that forward. Understanding
this will really help conceptualize
everything else we're about to cover. So
when Claude needs to do complex like
research a topic from multiple angles or
process a really large project, you
don't need to send one agent to do
everything. You basically have one agent
that sits in the center and this is the
main agent. It breaks the task down,
hands off pieces to specialized agents
and then combines the result at the very
end. So these would be examples of the
other sub aents. So one synthesis agent
that uses tools to verify and write
another search agent that uses tools
like search and fetch URL. Then you have
the analysis agent that uses tools like
read do and extraction. Now the exam
guide mentions this specific concept. So
each one of these agents has its own
separate window, its own separate set of
tasks and technically its own world. So
there's no communication in between
different sub aents. That's actually
what the newer agent teams feature was
designed to do, which is enable that
communication through providing the
equivalent of an email inbox to each
agent. So they can email each other, see
who's blocking who, and execute the task
in unison. So it's important to
understand that sub agents don't
maintain track of memories of other sub
aents at the same time. So sub aent A
will have no idea what sub aent B did.
it will all kind of come together at the
very end once the main agent takes the
TLDDR of each's outputs and or findings
and then disseminates that back to you.
Now, there's one major mistake that many
people make when it comes to
understanding sub agents and it's the
following. So, let's zoom in here. Even
though you have a main agent, it's
completely possible that the coordinator
could break down tasks too narrowly. And
this is something you have to look out
for. So, in practice, it could look like
this. You say research AI in creative
industries and the coordinator only
creates subtasks about visual arts. So
digital art, graphic design or
photography, but it completely misses
music, writing, film and game design. So
the sub aents did their job perfectly,
but the coordinator just scoped it
wrong. It's basically like having a bad
manager for a great team. So the fix is
to give broad goals, not narrow
checklists to this main coordinator
agent. You want to let the sub aents
figure out how to break down all the
subtasks based on their narrow goals
that are defined by this broader goal.
So instead of me just breaking this down
conceptually, let's go down into the
terminal and see an example of this. So
if we go into warp here, I'm going to
copy paste this prompt and we'll send it
over. And while we send it over, I'll
read it through. So it says, I want you
to research the impact of AI on content
creation by spawning three sub aents in
parallel. The first sub aent is to
research how AI is changing video
content creation. The second one is to
research how AI is changing written
content creation. And the last one is
how it's changing audio. And then we say
each sub aent should search the web and
return a three bullet summary. So it's
very broad in terms of what they're
looking for. We're not micromanaging
exactly how they're going to do said
thing, but we're giving them the overall
assignment. So, you've taken the
equivalent of an employee, you've
onboarded them, and then after
onboarding them, you trust them enough
to give them a very well situated task
and allow them to execute independently.
And after completes, you can see right
here, all three agents are finished.
Each one used its own set of tools, its
own set of tokens. Then we have the
results from each one. And then we have
the overall synthesis. So this is the
main agent compiling all the results of
the sub aents. And this is how this
coordinator sub aent pattern works. So
this might be the most important part of
the entire exam guide where they
differentiate between prompts and hooks
and when and where to use each. So
prompts are what I call best effort. You
can tell claude something like always
verify customer before processing a
refund. And most of the time it works,
but sometimes it doesn't. If we even hop
into their exact scenario, they have
this question where they say production
data shows that in 12% of use cases,
your agent skips this invocation of a
function get customer entirely and just
goes straight to look up an order based
off of the stated name occasionally
leading to misidentified accounts. So
from a business perspective, this is not
okay. 12% of accidentally provided
refunds to the wrong person or to people
trying to take advantage of this becomes
a big issue. Now, hooks are completely
different. A hook is basically a small
script that runs automatically before or
after Claude tries to do something. And
it can literally block Claude from
taking an action unless a specific
condition has been met. So, it's not
99%, it's not 99.9%, it has to be 100%.
And the action physically can't happen
if the hook says no. So, you can think
of prompts as suggestions and hooks as
laws. So, the exam guide draws a very
clear line on when and where to use
prompts versus hooks. And when it comes
to what it's good for, it's primarily
around style, tone, and formatting.
These are things that you can execute
well 90% of the time, and it won't land
you necessarily in an area of harm or a
land of hurt. Hooks are optimized for
compliance, financial stuff, and
security. So, anywhere where one single
point of failure can cause some real
issues. And this overall concept is
where a lot of people go wrong because
they just think that if something failed
90% of the time, they can just tweak the
prompt to perfection. And as running a
company called prompt advisors, where
initially all I would do for companies
is help them prompt engineer every
system prompt in a system in a
production use case for content
creation. There is a level where a
prompt is just not good enough over a
thousand iterations or 5,000 iterations.
If you're not as familiar with hooks and
you want a little bit of a debrief, then
you have two options. If you pop into a
terminal, you could always do slash
hooks and then this will show you each
and every way that you can invoke a
different tool. And this list goes on
and on and on. And if you click on one
and you click enter, it will show you
exactly what it would do. And option two
is, I showed this in a prior video, you
can use my favorite function in Claude
Code, one of the most underrated, which
is the Claude Code guide agent. And then
you can ask it what are the best hooks
for X use case and then it will go
through with full knowledge of what
hooks it has at its capacity and which
one is optimized for your use case and
whether or not you should be using a
hook or a prompt to begin with. So
whereas the last concept the enforcement
piece is probably the most important
this is the highest leverage which is
getting tool descriptions correctly
which is basically giving claude code
which you provide it with whatever tools
you want at its arsenal as well as its
native tools the right tool at the right
time with the right description for the
right use case. So tools are basically
how claude decides which tool to use
when it has multiple options. And that's
typically not a small feat because you
can have two tools that have vague
overlapping descriptions, like one that
retrieves customer information and
another that retrieves exactly what the
order entails. So that could lead to
some form of communication issues. So
Claude has to essentially guess. And the
exam guide covers this very clearly.
Ambiguous descriptions cause frequent
misouting. So Claude ends up calling the
wrong tool way more often than you'd
expect. And one really important thing
to note is that when you invoke these
tools, sometimes you see the final
result being executed properly. But back
when everyone was using no code tools
like Naden, you would have the agent in
that platform work and execute the
workflow and you would see it fire the
right result. So you could get the exact
result you're looking for in cloud code,
but you have no idea that it actually
did the wrong thing three or four times
to eventually do the right thing. So
it's not just about the outcome but also
the efficiency in getting to that
outcome because as it tries through all
the ways it doesn't work it spends your
tokens and you want to be as token
efficient as possible. So to give you
something more tangible let's say this
is one of your functions get customer
you would basically say that you want to
use this tool whenever you need customer
ID and profile data and you want to use
the lookup order instead when you have
an order number and need a shipping
status. So you essentially want to be
intentional in saying do not use this
tool when this happens versus just
saying when it should use that tool. And
this is pretty much the highest leverage
tip from the entire guide, which is the
description of the tool is really the
interface of tooling. And fixing the
descriptions to make sure it knows the
optimal path, the critical path is the
most critical thing that you can do in
your workflow. Now, while MCP servers
are increasingly falling out of favor
for different use cases, there are times
where they make sense. So the exam guide
does cover where to use different levels
of scope for your MCP servers. You have
project level and you have user level.
And I'll walk you through the difference
of when and where to use both. And this
essentially allows Claude to connect to
external tools like GitHub, Slack,
Outlook, whatever it is, it's one of the
vectors that you can use. And if you've
ever used Claude chat or Claude Co-work
and use their connectors feature, it's
essentially using an MCP under the hood.
So project level MCP lives in a file
called theMMCP.json
at the root of a project. So any
passwords or API keys go in what are
called environment variables where
they're denoted as N for environment and
they never directly end up in the core
file. So for example, if you had an MCP
server for GitHub, which is essentially
code version history, you would have an
environment variable. it would be set to
the token of your GitHub and this would
be written to an environment file. So
every single time that an agent would
try to use an MCP server, it would then
be authenticated through this file then
go and invoke this specific service.
User level MCP lives in a file in your
home directory. So this is basically
your personal sandbox. You have
experimental tools, personal API keys,
things you're testing before rolling
them out to the rest of the team. Now,
the practical takeaway from the exam
guide is that essentially you can use as
many community-based MCPs. These are not
necessarily open-source MCP servers,
which sometimes aren't too safe, but
more so the native MCP servers from the
platforms themselves. So, if you look at
the major providers like Salesforce,
GitHub, etc., everyone has some form of
instruction for using MCP servers and
only build custom servers when you
absolutely need to. And it's important
to remember that an MCP server is purely
a function. So if you just need your
functions executed in a slightly
different way or different order, you
might not need a custom MCP. Now, real
quick on the terminal side of things,
all you'd have to do is go into your
terminal and you could do one of these
two things. You could say claude MCP
list. This would go and invoke if you
have any MCP servers whatsoever. Now,
personally, I've migrated my entire
ecosystem to skills, CLIs, etc. So you
won't find any that are already
authenticated. You'll find just the
shell of the ones that I used to use. So
the Gmail, Google calendar, Canva, and
Zapier. All of them I used to use, but
now I've migrated all of them to use the
skills primarily just for token
efficiency, security, etc. But if you
wanted to see which ones you had out of
the box, that's the way you'd do it.
Now, if you're using MCP servers at the
project level, then you could just paste
a command just like this where you could
say, "Show me the MCP.json JSON file in
this project and explain the MCP server
configuration and then you get this
response where in this case I don't have
in this particular project an MCP.json
file and it walks through what needs
authentication like we saw before how to
configure it and there's that command
that I showed you before claude MCP
list. It basically invoked that. So
whether you're asking for it through
natural language or going straight to
the source with this command then you
can have full visibility on what's
happening with your MCP servers. The
next principle in the exam guide is the
tool overload problem. And this is
essentially making better decisions by
having less options. So you can think of
it like this. Giving an agent 18 tools
is like hiring a brand new employee and
giving them access to every single
system from day one. They're going to
use things that they shouldn't call
tools outside their lane. You want to
keep each agent down to a maximum of
four to five tools that are directly
relevant to what they're doing. That
constraint is really what makes them
precise. And if you need a reminder
earlier I showed you an example of
spinning up three sub aents and you'll
notice that all of them used four or
five tools at max. So this is really a
paradigm that's built into cloud code
and that allows it to have a process
create SOPs. So this one would be
search, fetch, extract and save. So the
goal is being precise, reliable and
always on task. Now there's also a
setting called tool choice that controls
how Claude picks its tools. There are
three main modes. One of them is auto
where basically Claude decides on its
own whether to use a tool or not. And
then you have another one called any and
this is essentially forcing Claude to
use a tool but it has to pick which one.
And finally we have forced meaning we
are making it use this tool and there
are no options. It's not just
independence it is forced dependence on
a particular outcome. So the guide
alludes to the fact that you can force a
tool call to make sure that step one is
always consistent and predictable and
then you can loosen that proverbial
leash of cloud code to run freely and
make more autonomous decisions as long
as you know you've steered it in the
right direction. So you're essentially
putting guard rails on its first move or
couple moves and then allowing it to run
freely and really tap into that power of
the agentic harness. Now, next up is one
of the most contentious topics in cloud
code, which are claude MDs, which are
the heart and soul of your operating
system. Your air traffic control of your
repo or project if you will. And pretty
much it covers all the different layers,
three different layers, the user level,
the project level, and the path specific
rules. Now, most people dump everything
they know into CloudMD and they think
that it's a proxy for a knowledge base
or rag. But essentially, it's not.
People dump their preferences, their
rules, their style, their tone all in
one place and then complain why there's
so many tokens being wasted all the
time. The big issue is that every single
time you open a brand new session,
Claude auto injects that straight into
memory. So you're wasting time and
you're wasting tokens. So the guide
splits it into three different layers.
One is the user level, the next is the
project level, and the last one are path
specific rules. So you can treat your
top layer as your personal preferences
file. This lives in your core home
directory. So you have your editor
settings, how you like your explanations
formatted. So this one's just for you
and not meant to be shared with anyone
or through something like GitHub. So the
middle layer is a project level CloudMD
and this is where you have things like
team rules, coding conventions,
architecture decisions and this
essentially allows you to share it with
your team assuming you have one so that
everyone's on the exact same page. So
this is where having some version
control makes a lot of sense. And
finally, we have the bottom layer here.
And this is really the golden nugget of
the three levels. These are path
specific rules. So you create a small
rule file that lives in the do.claude
rules folder. And at the top of each
file, you put a pattern that says when
to load it. So when something like only
load this when I'm editing files is a
very good example. So your testing rules
only show up when you're writing tests
and your API rules only show up when
you're in the API folder. And lastly, if
you have something like React
components, if you're a developer, then
you know what that is. If not, then
don't worry about it. The TLDDR is this
is huge because cloud code can get
focused. So you can have a lean and mean
CloudMD and rely on rules to carry the
path forward for any nuances that need
to be taken account for a specific use
case. So I know I'm throwing a lot at
you right now, but the next section
tries to bring everything together into
cohesion. So, it's really about when to
use what because we haven't even started
speaking about things like skills, like
commands, plan mode versus direct
execution, when to use each. So,
commands are basically reusable prompts.
You save them once and then you can
trigger them with a slash command. So,
you can have slashre PR slashgenerate
tests slashming if you want to execute a
walkthrough of what your day looks like
based on your calendar, your Gmail,
anything you've hooked up maybe using
the Google CLI. But one thing to note is
that teamwide commands go in a commands
folder in your project so everyone can
use them via something like git whereas
personal ones will end in your root
folder and these are your personal slash
commands. So these are specific to you
and tailored to exactly what you want to
do day-to-day. Now we've gone through
skills at length in this channel but
just in case you and I are meeting each
other for the first time we'll go
through that as well. So skill is a step
above a command. A skill has its own
file that defines what it can do, what
tools it's allowed to use, and it runs
in its own separate context. So, you can
think of it like this. A skill can do
messy exploratory work like research
files, do pretty much anything you want,
and none of that clutter ends up in your
main conversation. It's like sending
someone to go do research in another
room, and you're just bringing the
summary back to the main conversation.
Now moving on to another existential
question that many people ask and the
guide goes through. To use or not to use
plan mode. So if the task touches
multiple files, it's ambiguous or it
could go in a few different directions,
then using plan mode is the way to go.
Claude explores, reads, and proposes
changes without actually modifying
anything. Just review it, approve it, or
tell it to go in a different direction.
But if it's a very obvious and
straightforward single file fix, then
you can just let Claude execute it
directly. So you don't have to over plan
in this case the same way many people
will overengineer things. Now this next
part is fairly advanced. So if you're
non-technical, this part might leave you
squinting a little bit, but I'll try to
explain it as best I can. So this is
about using clawed code in what's called
a CI/CD pipeline. What this stands for
is continuous integration and continuous
development. So if I were to break down
this concept into one sentence to make
it as accessible as possible to
everybody, it would be the CI/CD
pipeline is an automated conveyor belt
where a developer will push code, that
code will be reviewed, and then it will
be shipped and pushed to the end user.
All without any form of buttons being
pressed along the way. So the guide
really focuses on this step three right
here, but we'll get to that in a second.
Step one is like I said you have a
developer that pushes some code. Then
this triggers the CI the continuous
integration pipeline to go and check it.
Step three is where the magic happens
and this is what's called claude-p
is not a very straightforward concept.
So again I'll try to break it down. The
-p essentially allows claud code to run
without asking you for anything. So no
prompts, no confirmation. It's
essentially bypassed permissions mode in
a way and it just runs the task you give
and it gives you the result back and
then you have a flag that gives you a
clean structured output that other tools
can read. It's actually called the dash-
output format JSON flag. When you put
these together, these two flags turn
cloud code from something you can chat
with solely into something that you can
use to automate different parts of your
process. So the main learning here is
that you can trigger this from any CI/CD
pipeline, any system that essentially
tests and deploys your code. Now it's
hard to make that part less gibberish,
but this part will be the main takeaway
from that section. And this is their
important note on using separate cloud
code sessions for reviewing code versus
writing code because there is some level
of pollution. When you write code, you
essentially are biasing the language
model to say, "Yeah, yeah, I wrote
amazing code." Because why would the
language model write poor code on
purpose? So you need a stateless session
to go and review any form of code,
anything that was produced in session
one, assuming you're doing something
more on the technical end of things. So
if you need a little anchor to remember,
then you can remember that fresh eyes,
even AI eyes can catch more. Two heads
are better than one. In Claude Code's
case, 5 10 15 heads sometimes are better
than one at reviewing code as long as
it's in a separate session. So for
example, if I said claw-p list all
python files in this project and
summarize what each one does output this
format, then you will see it goes
through every single python function in
my folder which I won't get into in
depth and then it comes back with the
full key patterns here. All scripts use
Gemini 3 pro preview for images. This is
my thumbnails generation folder and
dated output folders, report lab for
PDFs and one script per video topic
design. So, when it comes to making
outputs reliable, this is a whole
portion of the guide that's dedicated to
dealing with inconsistency in Claude's
responses. So, your instinct when Claude
gives you inconsistent outputs is to
write more instructions. So, for
whatever reason, your instructions
involve number crunching, something like
handling different currencies, different
decimal places. You try to shove all of
that in there. But Claude interprets it
differently each time. One response can
give you one number versus another
depending on the day, the model you
choose, etc. So you can have the same
set of instructions but three different
results because people keep forgetting
that this isn't magic. These are
language models. Now to fix this,
Anthropic recommends going to fshot
examples. If you're not familiar with
what fot are, these are from the
beginning of prompt engineering time one
of the best ways to get consistent
outputs. So you give an example. In this
case, the input could be Acme Corp
reported 4.2 million in revenue for
2024. And this is the output you want
exactly. So you give it exactly the
parameters. In this case, we're putting
it in JSON. This could be in whatever
format you want. And same thing for
example two. So multishot gives it
enough of a hint to generalize and
better understand which direction you're
going for. And the interesting thing
here is that claw doesn't just copy
paste your examples. It learns the
underlying patterns behind them. That's
why two to three examples will beat a
full page of instructions each and every
single time. Now, in the same vein of
consistent and reliable outputs, this
also generalizes to JSON, which stands
for JavaScript object notation. Very
common when you're dealing with agents
with toolings and tool calls. So, this
is also more of an intermediate to
advanced use case, but it's important to
know because it's covered in the guide.
So, I'll move from left to right and
again try to make this as accessible as
possible. So step one is you define a
tool which basically acts as your
template providing the exact structure
you need. So every field, every data
type and whether or not it's required.
Leaving something as optional is
beneficial for Claude because otherwise
if you don't tell that it's optional,
then Claude will make it up. So making
it optional allows Claude to say I don't
know in a very legal way. So your
legalized way of allowing it to say I
don't have this. I don't know what to do
with this. In step two, building on what
we referred to before, you can force
Claude to use a specific tool. So
there's no option to respond with plain
text, no option to use a different tool.
It has to fill your template as is. So
just as a takeaway, this eliminates
syntax error. So anything like malformed
JSON, this is just broken JSON or
markdown wrapping, but it does not
eliminate semantic errors. So anything
with a wrong value insert field. So step
one is you extract the data. And
assuming it's correct, then obviously
this is all done. But if it's not
correct, this is the part where you
really need to dial in. You're not meant
to just say try again. You're meant to
actually send very specific feedback. So
instead of saying retry, you would say
the original document, the field
extraction, and the specific error. And
this is how you would frame the specific
error. Revenue field says 0, but
document clearly says 4.2 million. So
now you're giving it multiple areas to
zero in on and see what might be
happening. But just like everything,
there's nuance. You don't want to just
keep going in this endless loop. If the
answer isn't there, if the information
isn't in the source document, then
retrying, even with the best of
instructions won't help. So it's not
just knowing how to validate and test,
but also knowing when to stop. Now, as a
segue to the next section, back when I
used to drive a Honda, once in a while
you'd get this notification, which
politely asks you to take a break. And
typically, it's because they want you to
have attention to the wheel, especially
for longer drives. You can take this
exact same paradigm in mind for the next
principle. So, instead of worrying about
driving sharply, this focuses on keeping
claw sharp throughout the lifetime of a
context window. So, when you give
something to Claude Code to read, it
pays really close attention at the
beginning. The first 40% of context
window is really well primed. You have
the system prompt, you have the first
messages, you have your cloud MD
injected at the beginning as well and it
really pays attention. And this is also
true near the very end where you have
recency bias towards the latest
messages. But the context in the middle
or the monkey in the middle starts to
get a little bit fuzzy. So information
buried in the middle starts to get
compartmentalized in a way where it
can't maintain that full fluency or flow
of thought. Now, the problem can get
worse over time because every time
Claude uses a tool, the result is added
to this middle section. So, a customer
comes back with 40 fields when you only
need five. Each one pushes the important
stuff further into the fuzzy zone. So,
naturally, how do we fix this? Well,
Enthropic comes up with three different
ways to accomplish this. First, you can
pull out the key facts and put them at
the very top of a conversation,
essentially pinning them in a place
where Claude will always see them. So
you can think of it as a key fact
summary block. Another method you can
employ is trimming verbose tool outputs.
And what the word verbose means here is
you get a series of data from a tool. A
lot of this data could just be pure
metadata that doesn't actually move
anything forward and you can get rid of
it. And by trimming it progressively,
you just keep the tool outputs that
matter which will flood the context
window less. And the third way is to
delegate tasks to sub agents so they can
maintain all of their messy output in
their own individual context and box.
It's all isolated and boxed off and you
just get a clean summary back. The guide
actually mentions explicitly that it's
infinitely better to start a brand new
session with a summarized version of
outputs from before versus pushing
through a conversation. Even if you're
at that million context window because
you have all of this different set of
information, tool calls, different
trials, pivots in the conversation that
pollute your context window. If you're
ever curious at what is in your memory
at a single point in time, you can
always go into cloud code, do
slashmemory.
Then in here, it will tell you that
automemory is on, what your project
memory looks like if you want to check
in at your cloud MD, the fact that you
have some certain rules here, some level
of user memory, and then you can also
open your automemory folder to see
exactly what's in there. So you can
click on enter right here. This will
open it up in another window. Then
you'll be able to see a series of
markdown files that denote exactly what
it's remembering about your current
session. And to close the loop on
reliable outputs, there's a section
related to human in the loop, which is
basically when do you escalate a
particular scenario to an agent. So if
you have some form of chat agent in the
wild and someone asks to speak to a
human, then the goal should not be to
try to fix the issue first using a
language model and not to try one more
thing. It should be to respect this
request and execute it right away. And
it's important to zero in on this
because it explicitly says that this
will probably trip up people because
you'll try to get creative with how AI
can answer something. But if someone
asks for handoff, you give them handoff.
Now, in the second scenario, the rules
could be unclear and the agent could be
unsure about what policy applies.
The prescribed action here is to
escalate, but escalate using what's
called a full package. This full package
includes what the customer information
is, the ID, the root cause, what was
attempted and tried and what is the
recommended action. So very similar to
managing an actual customer system like
Zenesk or similar, you would execute
this in a very similar way. So the agent
would technically come to the conclusion
that it can't make any meaningful
progress. And this is what it could look
like in terms of a final package to hand
off. And for the third scenario, if it's
a straightforward issue, the policy is
clear, which is to allow the agent to
resolve it. But it comes with a big
caveat. Even if it resolves it
perfectly, it should still ask, "Would
you prefer I transfer you to human
agent?" So, you wouldn't want to give
the agent itself a confidence score and
escalate it when it's low. And one of
the many reasons why it thinks that
sentiment analysis can miss the mark is
it can misread sarcasm, cultural
differences, and tone. So, I actually
had to double check whether or not this
was legit. So, I noticed that this is
the question in the example guide here
where it says, "Your agent achieves 55%
first contact resolution well below the
80% target." And you can see here it
says that sentiment doesn't correlate
with case complexity, which is the
actual issue. All right, and we're
getting near the end here. And this
portion of the guide just covers error
propagation. Basically, what to do when
things go wrong. Now compare that to a
detailed error that includes what went
wrong, what was attempted, any partial
results that came back, and what else
could be tried. So now the main agent
can actually make smart decisions,
meaning trying a different search, using
data from a previous run, switching to a
completely different source, or just
basically noting that gap and moving on.
So the TLDDR of the TLDDR is this just
breaks down how to allow your agents to
fail gracefully. Meaning failing in a
way where you get meaningful errors so
you can get meaningful outputs and
meaningful retries. And just to bring
everything together cuz we've had all
kinds of thoughts and examples and
paradigms. What are the five rules that
you can take away that will set you on
the right path whether you're just
learning cloud code or you're preparing
to dive into the cloud code architecture
exam. So rule numero uno is if it has to
work 100% of the time whether it's money
related security legal don't rely on
telling claude in a prompt use a hook
that physically blocks the action. So
prompts are suggestions and hooks are
the laws. Rule number two is when
something breaks never return a generic
error. Always include what broke, what
tried, what partially worked and what
else could be done. Rule three is keep
your agents focused. four to five tools
max per agent and an agent with 18 tools
makes infinitely worse decisions than
one with five that are directly
relevant. So less choice and better
decisions. Number four is review your
code in a separate clawed session. The
one that wrote the code is naturally
biased toward thinking it's correct. A
fresh session with no history catches
what the first one will never.
So, two or three real examples of what
you want produce more consistent results
than a full page of written
instructions. Claude learns the pattern,
just not the format. And the real trick
here is understanding that although
these are five separate rules, they're
all kinds of the same concept, which is
if you need to rely on building proper
agentic systems in the wild, then you
want to focus on the right tool that has
the right level of determinism, which is
its ability to execute something
predictably every single time. And the
main thing to take away from this is
that although these are five different
rules, they're essentially the exact
same concept just showing up in
different patterns. And the TLDDR of it
is to be structured, to be explicit, and
to not have a whatif or a probably will
work with something like a prompt when
you need the firepower of something like
a hook. So, if you nail understanding
these core five principles, it will give
you the 80 of the 8020. And more
importantly, it will give you the
foundation to keep adding on additive
knowledge. Now, you might think that I'm
going to end off there. You might be
even hoping for it, but I'm going to
leave you with one more thing before we
depart for this video. So, I found this
really good guide by this user on X. I
can't pronounce the username, but he
came up with this article here that
says,"I want to become a claude code
architect." And in it, he came up with a
series of prompts that break down each
and every section of the official
architecture guide. He's created these
very bespoke prompts, I would imagine,
using AI. And you can just pull this up
and go into cloud code. You can paste it
and then it will ask you and interview
you on your competence on a particular
domain. So if we take this behemoth
prompt for section one. This says you
are an expert instructor teaching domain
one architecture and orchestration of
the claude certified architect
certification exam. And then at the
bottom it says welcome. It tells you the
waiting of this particular section. And
it asks you how familiar you are with
the Gentic systems. And if you say
something like none, then it will create
a custom learning path for you to start
going back and forth through these
concepts. So you see here it breaks down
what an agentic loop is. And at the very
bottom there's a concrete example, the
critical field. We already alluded to
this, the stop reason, the anti pattern,
the correct pattern. It's going to keep
going telling you which part of the
guide to reference. And this is awesome.
So kudos to this individual. I'll leave
the link for you with some other goodies
that I'm about to tell you right now.
Now, as I recover from filming this
video, I'm going to leave you with a
mega guide going through everything I
walked through today with the actual
visuals themselves, a breakdown of the
concept, hopefully in a better way than
I was even able to articulate. And I'll
make that available to you in the second
link in the description below. And for
those that want to go infinitely deeper
on cloud code and be in a whole
ecosystem where you have coaches,
myself, a brand new upcoming course
which is bound to blow your mind in
terms of what you can do with cloud
code, then you'll want to check out the
first link in the description below and
maybe join me in my early AI Doppers
community. And for the rest of you, if
you found this to be a helpful labor of
love, one thing that you could do as a
thank you is just leave a like and a
comment on the video. If you like my
stuff and you want me to go deeper on
these kind of concepts, then subscribe
to the channel and let me know.