These new Chinese AI models are insane
and they are completely free. Today I am
going to show you three brand new AI
models that just dropped out of nowhere.
One of them has over a trillion
parameters. One of them can see, hear,
and think at the same time. This changes
everything. Let me break it down. So
here is what just happened. A mystery AI
model showed up online. Nobody knew who
made it. People tested it. They were
blown away. Everyone thought it was from
Deepseek. Nope, it was from Shyomi. Yes,
the phone company. They secretly tested
it under a code name called Hunter
Alpha. And it went viral before anyone
even knew it was them. Now they have
officially dropped three new models. And
I need you to pay attention because this
is a big shift in how AI works. The
first model is called Myo V2 Pro. This
is the big one. It has over 1 trillion
parameters. To put that in simple terms,
this thing is massive. It also has a 1
million token context window. That means
you can feed it entire books, entire
websites, huge amounts of data and it
just handles it. But here is the part
that matters most. This model is not
built for chatting. It is built for
doing. Think about that for a second.
Most AI tools right now are like having
a conversation. You ask it answers. Myo
V2 Pro is different. is built to plan
tasks, execute workflows, use tools, and
complete entire jobs with very little
input from you. So instead of you
telling AI what to do step by step, you
give it a goal and it figures out how to
get there on its own. That is a huge
difference. We are talking about AI that
actually works for you like a team
member. Hey, if we haven't met already,
I'm the digital avatar of Julian Goldie,
CEO of SEO agency Goldie Agency. Whilst
he's helping clients get more leads and
customers, I'm here to help you get the
latest AI updates. Now, imagine this for
a second. Let's say you run a community
like the AI Profit Boardroom. You can
tell this model to go research the top
10 AI automation tools this week, write
a summary for each one, create social
media posts about them, and draft an
email to send to your members. And it
just does it step by step without you
holding its hand. That is the power of
an AI agent, and that is what Myo V2 Pro
is built for. It is also strong at
coding and reasoning. So if you need it
to build automations, write scripts or
solve complex problems, it can handle
that too. They say it is already
processed over 1 and a.5 trillion tokens
globally. That is not a small test. That
is real world scale. Now before I get to
the next two models, I want to share
something with you and one more thing.
If you are creating all this content
with AI but nobody is finding it online,
you have got a traffic problem. That is
where SEO comes in. If you want more
leads, more traffic, and more customers
finding you, my team can help you rank
higher on Google, check the link in the
comments and description to order AI SEO
online and let us handle your back links
while you focus on growing your
business. And if you want to rank number
one and get more customers, join the SEO
elite circle. That is where we actually
teach you how this works. No theory, no
recycled tips, just the exact AI SEO
systems we are using right now. We break
everything down step by step with real
workflows, weekly live support, and
clear actions you can follow without
guessing. If you are serious about
scaling with SEO and AI, this is where
you start. Hit the link in the
description and join the SEO elite
circle today. All right, let us keep
going. The second model is called Mimo
V2 Omni and this one is wild. It is a
multimodal model. That means it does not
just work with text. It works with text,
audio, images, and video all at the same
time. So you could give it a video and
it understands what is happening in that
video. You could give it an audio clip
and it breaks down the conversation. You
could show it a picture and it analyzes
it all in one model. No switching
between different tools. They tested it
against other big models and it beat
them in audio reasoning, speech
understanding and video forecasting.
That is not me making things up. Those
are their benchmark results. Think about
what this means for someone running a
business. Let's say you have a sales
call recorded for the AI profit
boardroom.
You could feed that entire call into
this model and say, "Pull out every
objection the prospect had, summarize
the key points, and suggest how to
improve the pitch next time." And it
does it because it understands audio
natively. Or let's say you have a bunch
of tutorial videos. You could feed them
in and have the model create written
guides, pull out timestamps, and
generate social posts based on the best
moments. That is real automation. That
saves you hours every single week. Now
the third model is myo V2 TTS. TTS
stands for text to speech. This one
converts text into realistic sounding
speech. It is built for things like
narration, voice assistance, and even
scenarios where you need multiple
speakers. Now, I will be honest with
you, text to speech is still hard.
Getting it to sound natural over long
pieces of content is a real challenge.
Short clips can sound amazing, but the
longer it goes, the harder it is to keep
quality consistent. So, keep that in
mind. This model is impressive, but the
technology still has room to grow. But
the fact that Shyomi is building their
own TTS model tells you something. They
are not just making one tool. They are
building an entire AI ecosystem. The
brain, the senses, and the voice all
from one company. Now, let us zoom out
and talk about why this actually
matters. Number one, AI is moving from
chat bots to agents. That is the big
shift. We are going from asking AI
questions to assigning AI tasks. Myo V2
Pro is built for exactly that. It plugs
into agent frameworks. It can run
workflows end to end. This is not future
talk. This is happening right now.
Number two, the AI race is speeding up
fast. China is not sitting on the
sidelines. Shyomi is going all in on AI
over the next few years. That is a
serious commitment and it means the
competition between these big AI
companies is only going to get more
intense which is great for us because
more competition means better tools,
faster improvements and more access for
everyone. Number three, these models are
not just smart, they are practical.
Strong reasoning plus the ability to
actually execute tasks is the
combination that makes AI useful in the
real world. Not just for demos, not just
for benchmarks, but for getting actual
work done. So what should you do with
this information? Start thinking about
AI differently. Stop thinking of it as a
chatbot. Start thinking of it as a
worker. Look at your business. Look at
your workflows. Ask yourself, what tasks
am I doing over and over that an AI
agent could handle? Content creation,
research, data analysis, email drafts,
social media outreach, all of these are
fair game. Now, if you are part of a
community like the AI profit boardroom,
start sharing what you find. Test these
models. Build workflows. Show others
what works. That is how everyone levels
up together. Julian Goldie reads every
comment. So, make sure you comment below
and let us know what you think about
these new models. Which one are you most
excited to try? And if you want to rank
number one and get more customers, join
the SEO elite circle. That is where we
actually teach you how this works. No
theory, no recycled tips, just the exact
AI SEO systems we are using right now.
We break everything down step by step
with real workflows, weekly live
support, and clear actions you can
follow without guessing. If you are
serious about scaling with SEO and AI,
this is where you start. Hit the link in
the description and join the SEO elite
circle today. And if you want to rank
number one and get more customers, join
the SEO elite circle. That is where we
actually teach you how this works. No
theory, no recycle tips, just the exact
AI SEO systems we are using right now.
We break everything down step by step
with real workflows, weekly live
support, and clear actions you can
follow without guessing. If you are
serious about scaling with SEO and AI,
this is where you start. Hit the link in
the description and join the SEO elite
circle today. All right, thanks for
watching. Hit the like and subscribe
button and I will see you in the next