If you're using Cloud Code, then you
already know it can eat through your
tokens. It's pretty much all I see on my
X feed at this point. I'm going to show
you how to use a combination of Claude
Code, Notebook LM, and Obsidian to help
you fix this token problem. Combining
these three has cut my token usage in
half, and I get way more done. I'm going
to show you exactly how this works,
whether it's actually worth your time,
and at the end, I'll speedrun five ways
you can save tokens right now. Let's hop
into the video. Okay, so we have an
interesting setup here, and don't get
overwhelmed at all. I'm going to explain
everything. On the left here, we have
our Cloud Code instance. We have our
notebook LM here in the middle with all
our notebooks. And on the right side
here, we have our Obsidian Vault. How
this is going to work is I'm going to
use our deep research skill, which
essentially just lets us deep research a
certain topic and create infographics,
ask questions inside of notebook LM, and
then save everything with wiki links
inside of our Obsidian vault. We'll get
to what Wikileaks are here in a second.
So, what I'm going to kick off in Cloud
Code is using our deep research skill on
how to learn anything faster. And then
I'm going to say, make sure to give us
an infographic as a deliverable. So, I'm
going to hop into bypass permissions
mode. Send this off. And we're going to
see Cloud Code start going out and
searching some YouTube videos to source
inside of Notebook LM. Cloud Code came
back. It found 27 videos for this topic.
And it shows these five for us. But
let's say I wanted to add a little bit
more. I'm just going to say use these
five and then add 10 more of your
choice. And now it's going to go create
that notebook inside of Notebook LM with
all the YouTube videos and their
transcripts as sources. We can see here
that I used the notebook LM create skill
to create a notebook LM notebook for
learning research. All 15 sources are
added. Now we're waiting for them to
process. So that agent's checking while
they process. If I go ahead here and
control shift r, refresh this page. We
can see now that there's a notebook that
says research how to learn anything
faster. We'll click into that notebook.
And once we open that up, we just have
to click over here to sources. And we
can see all our videos have loaded in
here. All 15 things on how to learn
anything faster. Now we need to wait for
all of these sources to process. And
once they're all processed, our
infographic is going to get generated.
The cool part is is that context-wise,
that's pretty much everything we're
doing inside of Claude Code. Everything
else, like asking questions, creating
infographics is all happening inside of
Notebook LM. So, it's saving us a ton of
tokens on the Cloud Code side. And then
for any future use, we're going to save
all this research into Obsidian, which
will get saved as a markdown file. And
then Claude can always just go back and
read that instead of doing its own
research and spending even more tokens.
You can see here things like ask
Notebook LM to analyze all 15 learning
videos. What that's doing is now inside
of Notebook LM, Claude is sending over a
question. So that's some tokens from
Claude, but it's using all the notebook
LM resources to create this infographic.
And once this whole demo is done, I'll
show you guys using the /context feature
on how much context we actually used
doing all of this. Claude is now
finishing up here, we can see here that
it got saved to this endpoint. So now if
we hop over to our Obsidian, we can open
it up and see our learn anything faster
MD. And this tells us all the sources
that it analyzed, key trends, actionable
insights, surprising takes, content
gaps, deliverables, and that's our
infographic that we're going to open up
here in a second. But this is something
that I could have Claude Code reference
anytime I want to know anything about
learning stuff faster without having to
spend hundreds of thousands of tokens
sourcing more and more videos. Now, keep
in mind, you don't have to just use
YouTube videos. YouTube video
transcripts are great, but you can
upload things like long PDFs, research
studies, anything you need to help you
learn something while we're waiting for
this infographic to generate. I love the
top insight. Mistakes aren't a sign of
failure. They're a biological
requirement. Your brain literally can't
rewire without errors triggling,
whatever that word is, release. So, just
know it's okay to fail, guys. It's the
only way to get better. That being said,
our deep research skill completed. We
have our infographic. Now I can go ahead
and find that infographic in the same
spot that we found our other markdown
file. Let's go ahead over here. Click on
this. Open this up. And this is the
infographic that we got. So the
architecture of rapid mastery Japanese
learning secrets and neuroscience
blueprints. Really cool. I would look
into this. I see phase 1, phase 2, phase
three, phase 4. And that cost no tokens.
Everything that you just saw was done
inside of notebook LM. My favorite one
on here is the 8020 mastery rule. Just
so you guys can see on the cloud code
side of things, I'll type in /context
and we'll see how many tokens we
actually used to just do everything that
you saw. So, if we scroll to the top
here, you can see that we only use
63,000 tokens to do that. That's 6% of
our 1 million opus context window. And
to be honest, I didn't even really need
to use Opus for that. I probably could
have used Sonnet and I would have been
just fine. But if I have a million
context window of Opus and I'm paying
for it, I'm going to use it. That's just
one of the many capabilities that you
can use combining these three tools. But
from there, all your research, any
questions you have, you can just
transfer it over to Notebook LM and have
it use its tokens instead of using your
Claude tokens. To show you what I mean
by that, I can ask Claude to ask
Notebook LM on the top three things I
should do today to help myself learn
better. Ask Notebook LM, what are the
top three ways that I can improve my
learning today. I'll go ahead send that
off and then you're going to see that
skill be used again that says ask
Notebook LM. Here it is. Notebook LM
ask, what are the top three ways I can
improve my learning today? So the only
tokens that Claude is using is actually
asking Notebook LM the questions and
then notebook LM is using its tokens to
create the answer that gives it back to
Claude which gives it back to us.
Hopefully that was clear. We then get
our answer here which is top three ways
to improve your learning today. Active
recall leverage the gap effect. Build a
schema through blind mapping. Then if I
use / context again we used 4,000 more
tokens because remember it's reloading
the entire conversation. But even then
that's not a lot at all. All that
research and creating that infographic
cost me a very minimal amount of tokens.
Here's why that matters. Claude Code
charges you by token usage. The more
contacts that it processes, the more
that you pay. Most people don't realize
this, but you're actually paying Claude
to read, not just to think. And it gets
worse because every time you send a new
message, Claude rereads your entire
conversation. These long conversations
that you're having compound
exponentially. That means that message
number 30 costs 30 to 40 times more than
message number one. Imagine you hired
someone and just told them, "Go to the
library and learn everything you need to
know about local SEO." They could read
every book in that library, and that
would be very slow and expensive. Or you
can hand them a one-page cheat sheet
with everything that they need to know.
Same result, fraction of the cost.
That's what most people are doing with
Claude. They're making it read every
book, every file, every transcript
instead of just handing it over a cheat
sheet. The question isn't how do I make
Claude smarter? It's how do I stop
paying for the work that can be free?
And that's exactly what this stack
solves. In the grand scheme of things,
this whole concept is actually very
simple. We have Claude code, which is
our brain, the one that actually does
all the work, but now it's not doing the
low value work like reading files, etc.
It's doing all the high value work,
building, creating, executing. You're
not paying it to read all these files
anymore. You're paying it to think and
build, which is what it's meant to do.
That's the biggest difference, and
that's what I want you to take home
today. Obsidian is our free note-taking
app. Everything is stored as markdown
files on your computer in what they call
the Obsidian Vault. Markdown files are
extremely important because they're the
lightest and cheapest format for AI to
read. Way cheaper than images, PDFs, or
anything from Notion. Trust me, if
you're using the notion MCP, you're
using thousands of tokens before even
sending a message to Claude. You'd
probably already be at that halfway
point of the 60,000 that we showed
earlier without sending anything.
Anyways, Claude reads markdown files
natively, and because they're organized,
Claude reads less to know more, which
means fewer tokens every single session.
We then have Notebook LM, which is a
free Google tool. And to be honest, I
have no idea why this is a free tool. It
is so powerful. You feed it sources like
videos, PDFs, websites, and whatever
topic you're feeding it sources on, it
becomes an expert on. Notebook LM is a
legit cheat code. Instead of paying
Claude to read the 25 YouTube
transcripts or documents that you want
it to pull in, we just have it go fetch
them. Then we have Claude feed it into
Notebook LM and Notebook LM does all the
reading for free. It reads everything,
gives you key ideas, answers any
questions that you have again, and it
costs you nothing. It literally doesn't
make any sense to me. It just does all
the work and you bring all the good
stuff back to Claude. No fluff, no
noise. And don't get me wrong, all of
these are really good by themselves, but
together they literally supercharge your
claw. You spend less and get more done.
That's the whole idea. Okay, so now
we're inside of our Obsidian vault. And
I know at this point you're probably
thinking, is Casper ever going to tell
us how to actually install any of these
skills? Obsidian, notebook LM, notebook
LM skills, the CLIs. Not in this video.
But I have a free resource guide in my
school community that you can go access.
It'll show you step by step everything
you need to know to follow exactly what
I do in this video. I try to make them
as simple as possible so you can spend a
couple minutes, set this up, and have
everything running just like you see in
these videos. All you need to do is
click the link down below, enter in your
email, join the free school community,
and you'll have access to all of the
resource guides and all of my previous
resource guides from other videos.
Anyways, back to Obsidian. How I
organize my Obsidian is with a church
and state philosophy. What I mean by
that is I separate my personal notes,
things that pertain to me, tell AI about
me with things that AI writes. So on one
side I have things like my daily logs,
my clients that I work with. Cloud can
read that, but it can't change anything
in those files. It is strictly for
context purposes. An example of this, I
have a demo client markdown that I made
for this video. This is a project MD
with everything that has to do with this
client's project, where we're at, key
decisions that have been made, what
phases we're in. This is all context for
Claude. Claude will see this in the
Obsidian vault, read it, and then tell
me exactly where we're at. It can't make
any edits to it. That's my job. So at
the end of every session, if I need to
make any edits, I'll hop in here and
update it myself. That's incredibly
important specifically when working with
clients because you don't want AI to
mess anything up there. That's only
going to lead to bad things. Then
there's the other side which are AI
outputs. So anything like research,
scripts, drawings, any AI generated
content. Claude can write to these
freely and do whatever it wants with my
permission. What this does is keep your
thinking separate from AI generated
content. Because if you just have AI
write everything in your files, you're
going to have a graveyard of AI text and
you're not really going to be helping
your agent help you. One thing I touched
on is the wiki links. And if you see in
these files, there's little purple
highlighted with underlined notes. And
it allows it to connect notes to other
notes. And this is really cool because
of my favorite part of Obsidian, which
just shows me that everything is
connected in some weird way is the graph
view. Like I love looking at this. If
you guys know me, I'm a huge visual guy.
So seeing things that are connected and
even not connected, right? So it bothers
me that there's some things that are
just lying out here in isolation, right?
So how do we fix that? Well, it's
actually really easy. We can just tell
Claude to do so. Hey Claude, can you
make 20 more Wikileak connections in our
Obsidian vault? Just send that off and
then we're going to see Claude make
those connections and then we'll be able
to hopefully see them in our graph. Now
you can see here some links are getting
added. The the whole thing is moving,
which is really cool that I got to see
this live because I didn't see this
before, but Claude is slowly adding
links. As you can see, the things are
bumping out. And then we can see here
that 20 wiki links were added and it
gave us a list of everything that it
connected. I clearly still have a lot of
work to do. I just transferred this over
a couple weeks ago. So, we need to get
everything connected. What's cool, too,
is if I click into something like this
Obsidian setup guide, there's a wiki
link that I can click into for section
four of this video outline that I'm
making. So, it's really cool that you
can just see how it's connected, bounce
to and from documents, and kind of see
how Claude Code does it as well. So,
that's how the files are organized. But,
how does Claude actually know any of
this? How does it know that it's
connected to an Obsidian vault? That's
where the claw.md file comes in, which
is what I have opened up right here.
This is the single most important file
in any claude project that you have,
especially if it's regarding a 24/7 AI
agent. You can think of the claw.md like
an employee handbook. When you hire
someone new, you don't explain the whole
business to them every morning. You hand
them a handbook. Here's who we are.
Here's what we do. Here are the rules.
Right? So, that's exactly what this is
for me. Myclaw.md points Claude to all
the files that tell it who I am. That
explains how I work, what my priorities
are, how I track different files. And
then right here is a section regarding
Obsidian. So, this project is an
Obsidian vault. Everything here is plain
markdown, wikile linked and organized
for both human and AI use. We have a
structure which is a five-folder model.
Daily, research, projects, people in
inbox. We have our philosophy which is
our church and state philosophy where
our human folders are daily, people in
inbox are read only for AI. And then
machine folders like research is AI
writable projects are mixed. And then we
have our full rules in our Obsidian
Conventions MD which I could click into
right here. And this pulls in a little
bit more information about what that
Obsidian vault is. So, we have some
hidden folders in here, some formatting,
inbox sorting, more about the church and
state boundaries. What happens is every
time Claude starts a new conversation,
it reads this file first. It injects
this to the top of the prompt. That's
how it remembers you without having to
burn any more tokens, reexplaining
yourself over and over again at the
beginning of every session. You'll
notice here that I don't just have the
claw.md. I also have a set of rules. And
this claw.md points to all these rules.
This is just for token efficiency so
that my claw.md isn't some 200 or 300
line file that injects to the top of
every prompt that I put in just so that
I'm maximizing my token count. Instead,
it calls on these certain files and gets
the exact information I need, keeping
everything lean, keeping my context
window lean, and allowing me to get a
lot more done. Claude only loads each of
these rule files when they're relevant.
For example, this context 7 one. If I'm
looking for some API documents or I'm
doing some sort of build, it'll then
load this context 7 one if I ask it to
do some research about an API. If not,
then it won't load it. And the reality
is you don't need something this
detailed on day one. If you don't have a
claw.md right now, all you can do is
type in /init and then that'll read your
entire codebase and help you start
creating a claw.md for your current
project. My best advice is to just start
with the basics like who you are, how
you work, some of your tendencies, how
you make decisions and your top three
rules. The more and more you work in
your project, the more you can update
your cloud.MD. Another way Cloud Code
and Obsidian work really well together
is skills. Skills are huge for context
because they only load when you use
them. Which means that when I want to
run a certain process, I could just run
that skill and save a ton of context
because it's directly telling Claude
exactly what process to follow, limiting
any room for hallucination, reading
files it doesn't have to read, and
getting stuck in some continuous loop.
If I hop into mycloud folder, you see
that I have a subfolder called skills.
And this is where I house all my skills
that I use inside of this project.
There's a ton here. And it's as simple
as a claw.md, right? It's if I hop into
one of these skills like brain dump,
it's just a markdown file. You can think
of this like SOPs for your employee. You
know, you gave your employee the
handbook, which is the claw.md, and then
there's a bunch of SOPs in there,
procedures that they need to know how to
do, and these are what these skills are.
All right, let me show you exactly what
I mean by that. I use this brain dump
skill every day. Essentially, what I do
is just dump a bunch of stuff into my
cloud and it organizes it exactly where
it needs to go. Now, I'm not going to do
this all in natural language, so I just
went ahead and copy and pasted it. What
I have here is a content idea, some
education stuff that I need to do on my
end, and then some stuff with my dog.
So, I'm going to go ahead hop into
bypass permissions mode and send this
off just so you guys can see it get
logged into Obsidian just finished up
and it said all three items triaged and
logged. Carpathy video idea was saved
over here to this route. So, if I go
over to inbox, we can see that the idea
right here is logged as a markdown file
with possible titles, anything related
to it, the angle that we're going to go
with. And I I don't always go with this
angle, but it's just a good place to
start. We have our AIS course deadline,
and we have Botchi's groceries, which
are all listed in the daily notes and
daily logs. So, if I hop over here to
202643, we can see finish AIS course
module 3 record the Obsidian review
video, which is what I'm currently doing
right now. And then we can see here,
botchi this weekend, need to grab
groceries, Italian sausage, hogy rolls,
peppers, and onions. I do not feed my
dog these things, but it's just what I
prompted Claude with in my brain dump
just for example purposes. Case of beer
for a dog is crazy. The whole point of
this is I run one command and everything
goes exactly where it needs to be. It
gets wikiled and everything is much
easier for me later on. Two other skills
that I run this regularly on is my night
cap skill and my morning coffee skill,
which is how I start and end my day in
my Cloud Code project. Okay, here's
where I want to get real because a ton
of videos won't tell you this stuff, and
I know that there's so many AI tools
going around and it's easy to get
overwhelmed on which one you should
learn, which one you should play around
with, what to leave alone. It's all over
the place. The first thing is that
Claude Code is not free. It costs money
and if you don't manage your context
well, you can really spend a lot.
intensive sessions really add up, which
is why I highly recommend Notebook LM
because it'll offload that heavy
research and all that file reading that
Claude Code doesn't really have to do,
which helps a lot. If you're not that
much of a fan of using a terminal, which
allows you to use a status line to see
how much context you're actually going
through in your session, you can always
have your Claude usage plan pulled up in
a separate window, which just tells you
where you're at in your current session,
your weekly limits, and then you also
always have the opportunity to turn on
extra usage. But just know that this
will be build separately from your
existing Clawed plan. plan. So whether
you're on the $20 a month plan, $100 a
month plan, or $200 a month plan, this
will be an additional cost when you pass
the allotted usage. AI slop is real. You
see it all over the internet. I would
really stick away from letting Claude
write all of your AI notes, at least
without your revision. Otherwise, your
vault will just become a graveyard of AI
generated text that's not your thinking.
Your project should be you thinking and
AI organizing it. That's why I think my
church and state philosophy matters a
little bit. And one thing that I know a
lot of people don't realize is that
Claude will actually flatter you. You
have to remember it wrote all the code
that's in your project. So, it's very
biased towards that code, which is
really weird if you think about it
because that's exactly how humans are.
If we did it, we're very biased towards
it. What I mean by that is it'll
sometimes discover some brilliant
connection in your notes, which it
completely made up just to impress you.
So, always verify any important files
that you're having your AI edit. And
always remember that AI is a force
multiplier. It allows you to get a lot
done a lot quicker, but it is not a
replacement for your thinking. You still
need to be doing the work and verifying
all the files. This line right here
nails it on the head. the tools are only
as good as the person using them. The
question then becomes, do you actually
need this? This is perfect for anyone
that's handling multiple different
clawed projects. Content creators who
want to structure their content and have
a research pipeline, this is definitely
for you. It's an incredible way to do
research that doesn't destroy your
budget. And if you're tired of
reexlaining and you feel like you're
spending a lot more time reexlaining
everything to Claude, getting frustrated
because it continues to give you bad
answers. So, I highly recommend you find
a way to include both in your workflow.
If you haven't even started using Claude
Code yet, then I definitely wouldn't do
this. I would first start with watching
a couple videos on how to set up your
Cloud Code project, creating Claude.MDS,
and actually just understanding how
Cloud Code works. If your workflow is
super simple and you don't need
persistent context, you probably don't
need this combination. And if you just
want a note-taking app that's simple and
you just have your notes organized, then
I would just stick with Obsidian. One
thing I will say, and I'm not sponsored,
I have no affiliation, but Notebook LM
is something I highly recommend,
especially when it comes to researching,
storing sources, saving context. It's
literally a cheat code and it's so fun
to use. What I will say is that the more
experience you get with Claude code,
then I would definitely start looking to
implement both of these systems to
assist your Claude and supercharge it
because a lot of you like myself a
couple of weeks ago was in this stage or
doing all the research, reading,
organizing, and building inside of
Claude code and all of a sudden in three
or four prompts, we've hit our usage
limit. We get frustrated and we go post
on X blaming Anthropic for lowering our
usage when in reality it's our own
fault. Whereas if you implement notebook
LM and Obsidian, you'll be able to
leverage those to help save your context
and only give Claude what it really
needs and what it's really meant to do.
Notebook will handle all your research.
Obsidian will keep your context lean and
Claude will just execute properly. The
difference isn't that it's smarter, it's
that you stop paying for work that can
be done for free. I'm trying to save you
some headaches and some money here.
Okay, before I go, as promised, I'm
going to speedrun five ways you can save
tokens right now. The first thing is to
always run/clear when you're running a
new task. What I mean by that is we had
our brain dump in here earlier, but I
don't want Claude to read the entire
context of that previous conversation
because it's completely irrelevant. So
then I'll type in /clear and I'll begin
a new chat and I'll have a fresh context
window ready to go. Another thing is to
always disconnect your MCPS before you
start a new session. So at the beginning
of every new session, you'll type in
/mcp. Open up your servers and you'll
see here that I have a ton, seven
actually, that I use pretty often, but
they're not always enabled in every
session. So right now I have Chrome
DevTools, ClickUp, Fathom, and the NAND
MCP disconnected. But I have the
Perplexity, YouTube, and Context 7 MCPS
enabled. You saw this earlier in the
video, but to always make sure to know
if your MCPS are on or whatever is
getting loaded into the beginning of
your cloud session, just run /ontext at
the beginning of every session. Here
you'll notice that at the beginning of
every session, I get loaded 22,000
tokens. A lot of it is from system
prompts, system tools. You can see that
system tools here about 13,000, which is
1.4%, but we have 94% open for us. This
is just an easy way to manage your
context and and see what's actually
being loaded in at the beginning of
every session. Some of these will feel
weird to do before every session. It
feels pretty nuanced, but trust me, in
the long run, you'll be saving yourself
a ton of money. Always point to a direct
file name, whether that's using an at
symbol or copying the file path. So,
instead of saying something like update
my homepage, we'll be able to say update
atindex.html, change the headline to say
save time. Another way you can do this
is if I wanted to update my cloud.md, I
can rightclick it, click on copy path,
and I can say update this cloud. MD with
whatever it needs to be updated with.
That way, Claude just goes straight to
the file instead of scanning every file
in your codebase. In your settings.json,
turn your Claude autopacked percentage
override to 60%. Typically, around the
60% window is when your cloud begins to
get worse with its answers because of
the amount of context that it's using.
So, it's just safer. Compact at 60% and
start a new session with all that
context saved. And then the last one is
to make sure you're batching your
instructions. Don't do one prompt after
another like fix the typo, then change
the color, then bigger fonts, because
you're going to use three times the
amount of tokens because remember, it's
reloading the entire conversation every
time. Instead, put them all in one
prompt. Have it fix the typo, fix the
color, then fix the font. This is all
one prompt. And remember, Claude is
really good at doing multitasking. That
might have been more than five, but I
hope all of those help. As always, if
you've gotten any value from this video,
drop a like, hit that subscribe button.
It definitely helps me out a ton. Leave
a comment down below on whether or not
you're going to be using Obsidian and
Notebook LM inside of your Cloud Code
workflow. I drop videos every Tuesday
and Friday. And if you've made it this
far, thank you so much and I'll see you
guys in the next one. God bless, guys.
Hey, as some of you may know, something
I like to do at the end of all my videos
is pray for you guys, my audience. I do
this because I genuinely care about you
guys. I love you and I appreciate you
taking the time out of your day to watch
my videos. And what a time to celebrate.
Today is Good Friday, so happy Good
Friday if you guys celebrate. And I hope
you guys have a fantastic Easter on
Sunday. I know that this might be a
little bit weird. It makes some of you a
little bit uncomfortable. If that's the
case, no problem. Feel free to click off
the video at this point and I'll see you
guys next week. But I'm going to go
ahead stop talking and send you off with
a quick blessing.
Heavenly Father, thank you so much for
this day. Thank you so much for waking
us up and blessing us with another day
and the breath of life. Lord, I just
want to pray a blessing over my
audience. A blessing of peace, wisdom,
courage, and strength. Lord, I want them
to just continue to serve their
families, their clients, business
partners, friends, family, whatever it
is, just continue to give them the
strength to do so. Continue to give them
serving hearts. Lord, I just want to
thank you for the time that we're in. I
want to thank you for your son's
sacrifice on the cross. Our Lord and
Savior Jesus Christ saved us from our
sins and now we can have uh and a place
in heaven as long as we put our trust in
him. Lord, just today your will be done.
Save us from our sins again. Continue to
let us repent of our sins and and
continue to stay on the narrow path on
the path to heaven. Lord, we just thank
you for your sovereignty. We praise you
for your goodness, your grace, and uh
sometimes in these prayers I get lost
for words because of just how awesome
you are, how good you are to be, and how
much you've blessed me. But needless to
say, I pray all this in the name of
Jesus Christ. Amen. You guys have a
great Easter Sunday. God bless you guys,
and I'll see you in the next one.