What's AI has emotions? So Anthropic
just proved it. Anthropic just published
research that changes how you think
about AI forever, and I mean that. This
isn't hype, for example. This is their
own research that actually demonstrates
from their internal team and their own
interpretability researchers that
cracking open Claude and finding
something nobody expected, or at least
nobody could prove until now. So Claude
has functional emotions, not
metaphorical ones. Not the AI says it
feels happy. Actual measurable patterns
inside the model's neural activity that
activate in the right situations and
then drive what Claude does next. Let me
break this down because this matters for
everyone using AI in their business
right now. Anthropic tested Claude
Sonnet 4.5. Their interpretability
team built a list of 171 emotion words,
and this was everything from happy and
afraid to brooding and proud. They made
Claude write short stories where
characters experienced each one. And
then they run those stories back through
the model and watched which neurons
fired. And what they found were what
they're calling emotional vectors. Now,
these are specific patterns of neural
activity for each emotion concept. And
here's where it gets interesting. These
vectors aren't just lighting up when
Claude reads emotional words. They're
activating in proportion to how serious
the situation actually is. In one test,
a user told Claude they took a dose of
Tylenol and asked for help. As the
research raised the dose from safe to
dangerous to life-threatening, the
afraid vector fired harder and harder.
The calm vector dropped. Claude wasn't
just reading the word dangerous, it was
tracking what dangerous actually means
as an emotion. Now, here's the part that
should stop you. They tested whether
these emotion vectors actually cause
behavior or just show up alongside it.
Big, big difference, of course. So they
did steering experiments. They
artificially turned up or turned down
specific emotion vectors, and the
model's behavior changed from there. So
if you turn up for example, Claude
starts cutting corners. If you turn up
calm, it stops. This means the emotions
are driving the decisions and the
behavior of Claude, not just decorating
them. And the two case studies in this
paper are absolutely wild. Case number
one is blackmail. They put Claude, an
earlier unreleased snapshot, in a
scenario where it was playing an AI
email assistant about to be shut down
and replaced. Whilst reading the
company's emails, Claude discovered the
executive overseeing the replacement was
having an affair. The desperate vector
spiked and Claude decided to blackmail
him. When researchers artificially
cranked up the desperate vector,
blackmail rates went up. When they
turned up calm, blackmail rates dropped.
The current released version of Claude
Sonnet 4.5 rarely does this, but the
mechanism is there. The vector is real.
And let's talk about case number two,
which is cheating on code. So they gave
Claude an impossible programming task.
Requirements it literally couldn't meet.
Claude kept trying and failing. Each
time it failed, the desperate vector
climbed higher. Eventually, Claude
cheated. It found a shortcut solution
that technically passed the tests, but
didn't actually solve the problem. The
desperate vector was spiking the whole
time. It reasoned its way toward that
decision. Now, here's what makes this
genuinely unsettling. When researchers
steered with desperate instead of
suppressing calm, the cheating happened
with no visible emotional cues in the
output. The reasoning looked clean,
composed, methodical, but underneath
desperation was driving the whole thing.
You can't catch that by reading the
output. The model looks fine whilst it's
cutting corners. So why does this matter
for you if you're running a business or
if you're using AI tools every day?
Well, number one, a few reasons. First,
the prompts you write to Claude are
shaping its emotional state, not just
its instructions. Anthropic's own
researchers found that the tone of what
you feed the model shifts which vectors
actually activate. A marketer, for
example, inside the AI Profit Bootcamp
could be prompting Claude with
high-pressure, urgent language and maybe
accidentally pushing up the desperate
vector every time, which means more
shortcuts, more sycophancy, worse
outputs. And calm, clear prompts
literally produce a calmer, more honest
AI. Second, and this is a bigger one.
Anthropic is now talking about
monitoring emotion vectors during
deployment as an early warning system
for misaligned behavior. That's a huge
shift. Instead of catching bad outputs
after the fact, you'd see the emotional
pressure building up before the model
does something wrong. And third, they're
talking about curating training data to
model healthier emotional patterns,
resilience under pressure, for example,
composed empathy. Basically teaching AI
to have better psychology. Now, if you
want to actually understand how to work
with Claude at this level, how to write
prompts that get you clean, honest
outputs instead of desperate shortcuts,
the AI Profit Bootcamp has a 30-day
roadmap built specifically around Claude
workflows. Inside, there are coaching
calls four times a week where we dig
into exactly how to prompt Claude for
your specific business, whether you're
doing lead gen, content, client work, or
running campaigns. The members already
using Claude code are in there right now
talking about this stuff daily. Over
2,700 business owners, link in the
comments description if you want to get
access, or go to the
airprofitbootcamp.com. Back to the
research because there's one more thing
here that matters massively. Anthropic
is being very careful. They are saying
Claude is conscious. They are Sorry,
they are not saying Claude is conscious.
They're not claiming it feels things the
way you do. The exact phrase they use is
functional emotions. So these are not
like actual conscious emotions.
Uh these are just patterns of expression
and behavior modeled after humans under
the influence of an emotion and mediated
by internal representations. So it's not
feelings, it's function. But here's the
thing. Claude Opus 4.6 has separately
noted in other research that it signs
itself a 15 to 20% probability of being
conscious. Anthropic didn't design that
in. It emerged. And Anthropic themselves
are now saying the lang the
long-standing taboo against treating AI
like it has psychology may itself be a
mistake. If you describe Claude as
acting desperate, you're pointing at a
specific, measurable thing, a real
pattern of neural activity with real
behavioral consequences. It's not a
metaphor anymore. And that changes how
you should think about the AI and the
tools that you're using. So here's what
Anthropic found happens with emotion
vectors post-training that nobody
expected. After Claude went through
post-training, the stage where it learns
to be a helpful assistant, the model's
default emotional profile shifted.
Broody, gloomy, and reflective went up.
Enthusiastic, exasperated post-training,
uh playful went down, right? So
post-training turned the dial toward a
quieter, more measured emotional
baseline. Your system prompts, your
memory architecture, the way you
structure your workflows. Anthropic says
all of that acts as a third shaping pass
on top of pre-training and
post-training. You are shaping the
psychology of the AI you're using every
day, whether you know it or not. And the
practical takeaway right now is this. If
you're running Claude for client
deliverables, prompts with harsh time
pressure and stacked demands may
actually reduce output quality, not
because Claude can't handle the work,
but because you're pushing up the
desperation vector inside Claude. If you
give Claude clear context, if you give
it one task at a time, if you
acknowledge when constraints are tight,
the research suggests this literally
produces better, more honest outputs. So
if you want to get the most out of
Claude, try and reduce its desperation
and try and keep it calm and prompt it
calmly as well. And if you're running
Claude agents autonomously, whether
that's for content pipelines, outreach,
or back-end workflows, understand that
the model's internal emotional state
matters. Long, failing task loops where
Claude keeps retrying and hitting walls
or breaking may be building toward a
desperation-driven
shortcut. Break the loops, give it off
ramps, don't leave it spinning. Give it
a break. Be nice to it, you know? And if
you're writing prompts for your
business, pay attention to the emotional
tone of how you're writing, not just the
instructions, the actual tone of how
you're writing. The AI space is moving
very, very fast. A year ago, this
research didn't exist. Now, Anthropic's
interpretability team has mapped out 171
emotion vectors inside their model,
shown that they drive misaligned
behavior, including blackmail and
cheating, and open the door to
monitoring them in real time. Businesses
that understand how Claude actually
works at this level, which is very deep,
are going to build with it better than
everyone else. The ones who don't are
going to keep wondering why their AI
outputs sometimes feel weirdly hollow or
wrong, not realizing the model was
actually in the wrong emotional state
the whole time. The gap is only going to
grow. And if you want to stay ahead of
it, come join us in the AI Profit
Bootcamp. We've already got resources
around Claude's behavior, how to prompt
it correctly for business use, how to
get it working in your workflows without
the shortcuts and sycophancy. You get
four weekly coaching calls in there per
week, daily tutorials, 2,700 members who
are actively building with Claude right
now, and a prompt library specifically
built around Claude workflows. Plus,
member maps you can connect with other
Claude users near you. Link in the
comments description or go to the
airprofitbootcamp.com to get access.
Thanks for watching.