Are you using clawed code and it just
seems like every conversation you have
with it, it's getting dumber and dumber.
I know your pain all too well. And
there's actually two simple fixes for
this problem. So guys, I want to
introduce you to the creator of these
two solutions called Bass and Carl.
We're excited to have you guys here.
This is episode three of the Agentic
Operators where we go balls deep on all
things Claude code. The other problem
aside just claude getting dumber after
every conversation is hitting your usage
limit. It seems like one MCP, one CLI
tool, and you've already maxed clawed
out for the week and managing all of the
plugins that you're downloading from
GitHub. Managing your file system. Maybe
it's just me, but when I hopped into a
terminal and VS Code for the first time,
I felt like I was in the cockpit of a
jet fighter. I had no idea what was
going on. But with the entrepreneurial
spirit, we figure it out. and we're here
to help you figure this out. So on that
note, Chris, what is Bass and how does
it solve any of the problems that we're
all dealing with?
>> Yeah, absolutely. So BAS stands for
builder automated state engine and it
sits at the workspace level and
essentially works as a layer that
manages and maintains your entire
workspace. Now, when we talk about
Claude code getting dumber and dumber,
let's look at that a little bit more
honestly. So, Claude's actually really
smart, but we all know that the quality
of output you get from any LLM or AI
tool is equivalent to what you give it.
Now, a lot of people when they work with
Claude, they boot up a session and they
ask Claude a question or they want to
send it in a direction and Claude's
going to scan the file system and pull
in whatever details and information it
can find. Now, if you're not keeping
this information relevant, if you're not
keeping it current, it is susceptible to
entropy, aka it decays, it goes stale,
it gets outdated. Claude pulls all of
this information in and it's already
generating bad output and we look at
this and say, "Oh, Claude code is
getting dumber and dumber." It's really
just about how we manage our workspace,
>> right? So, how does it essentially solve
that problem?
>> Yeah. So, it's a combination of commands
that run uh different workflows. Then we
have various JSON files. These are what
manage all of the information that it's
working with. So, we log everything
about your workspace into these files.
Claude uses an MCP server that comes
with base to query and to update these
JSON files. And then there's a couple
hooks and the hooks are designed to take
the signals that are in these JSON
files. It'll run calculations and then
it'll send into Claude's system message
a very concise and direct signal that is
designed to be low on the overhead side
but extremely valuable in terms of
information and awareness.
>> Interesting. So, what we're going to
have to do is if you don't know about
hooks and JSON files and MCPS, we go a
lot deeper in that on our school
community. We're releasing the zero to
dangerous flagship course for claw code
where we show you the entire ecosystem.
We explain all these little details and
how they work together so this nerd and
ease can make more sense to you because
Chris and I are just weaponized nerds at
this point. Cool guys, of course. But on
that note, let's roll over into Carl.
How do these two play together? What is
Carl and how does it solve these
problems?
>> Well, yeah, I I want to uh clarify that
bass and Carl are completely independent
of each other. You don't need Carl to
run bass, and you don't need bass to run
with Carl. But the way Carl works is
it's essentially a it's a vehicle. It's
just a layer that kind of sits on top of
everything else. And this layer is just
a reinforcement layer to Claude. So the
issue it's solving is this. People work
with Claude and Claude has behaviors and
it does things that they don't want it
to do. So they say, "Okay, put that in
my cloud.MD to never do this again." And
they do that over and over. And you've
got people that have like three, four,
500 line clawed MD files. Now, that is
not helping solve the problem that
they're actually trying. What's
happening there is you have a bunch of
noise in an in a bloated clawed MD file
that is loading all of these rules
whether they're relevant or not every
single session.
>> That's an issue,
>> right?
>> Exactly. Wasting tokens, sending more
noise than it is actual signal. The
rules don't get adhered to. halfway
through a session, Claude MD is now kind
of drifted in the context. So, there's
not really much value to that. What Carl
does is it takes more of the
instructional aspects that we're trying
to tell Clyde and it puts them in these
in categories. So, for example, you
might have instructions related to
building apps that are different than
the instructions you want when you're
writing content.
>> Okay? So, we call these categories
domains. And then each domain gets its
set of instruction
>> domain expansion out of like
>> Yeah. So they they each get their own
set of instructions. And what happens
with the domains is you set keyword
phrases that you would naturally use uh
when working in that area. So I would
tell Claude, I'm building this app. And
then I would take building this app as a
keyphrase and put it in my development
domain or my app bu building domain.
Right?
>> That keyword is going to be matched by
the hook. It's going to then detect the
domain for those rules and it's going
going to put those rules into the system
message right before Claude reads my
prompt. So, it's going to have all of
that fresh this is how you should behave
sent to it right at the moment. It's
processing what I'm telling it to do,
not 20 messages ago from a 500line C
claw MD file.
>> Right now, 100%. We're serving relevance
at the point of time or just in time for
when it's needed the most. That's what
Carl does,
>> right? 100%. And when I've when I've
used Carl, it only pulls the relevant
rules, saving me a bunch of context
instead of pulling this bloated MD file,
the clawed MD, wasting all this context
in the beginning of a conversation,
leading to hitting your your usage
limits way quicker, and it's just not
effective. So, as a beginner not knowing
any of this and just bloating these
files up, it's a huge waste of time. So,
>> can I add one thing to that? This gives
you one added bonus as well because you
are now using Carl to do a lot of the
heavy lifting that you were once using
Claude MD to do. Now, you can get really
smart about how you use your Claude MD
and you can strategize it. So, I've got
a whole like approach to how I build my
claw.mmd that I don't see anyone else
really doing and it's a strategy that
goes into it. It's not a dump file.
>> That's a huge takeaway I think people
might overlook.
>> We're going to have to to gate keep
that. We're going to keep that zero to
dangerous, but we're still going to drop
some awesome sauce here. So, the most
exciting part of this video is yet to
come. And what we're going to show you
in the next three segments is how these
tools actually work, the best use cases
to solve the problems that we're talking
about, and how to install them with some
golden nuggets dropped in between as we
do in all of our episodes. So, if you
guys want to check out those episodes
before watching this one, you're more
than welcome to. They all flow into one
another. We've been doing this for 3
weeks now. They'll be linked below, as
well as the school. It's going to be the
first link that you guys see below. So,
Mr. Christopher, let's dive in.
>> Excellent. I'm excited to
>> drop the base. We got it here. We're
looking at this repo here on GitHub. So,
what I want to look at, Chris, is some
of the commands, understand how the
readme works, and then we can go over
some use cases. So, the floor is yours.
>> Yeah. So, we are on the GitHub repo for
Bass, and I just want to kind of
highlight a couple sections here. First,
let's look at what Bass actually does.
So what it does is it turns cloud code
into a managed operating system. So
instead of things being scattered
everywhere, it consolidates it all into
JSON files that are machine readable.
Meaning I can now have a hook scan those
files and present signals to Claude. So
what it looks like is for example these
these types of blocks hitting Claude
codes system messages and this is right
here for any active projects that I
would have going is going to show the
active project one and a little bit of
information about it what it is and what
its current status is. Now this is just
for awareness um at this point. Uh base
also helps manage the relevance which is
a timebased thing. So if something was
put in place two months ago, it may not
be relevant 2 months later, right? So
we're tracking the drift of the
information that is in your workspace.
And as that drift increases, these
behaviors start to change and base will
start to signal to Claude, hey, we need
to tend to this information and get it
up to date. So what that does is it
prevents the issue of stale data. Most
people with their clot, if they're not
managing their workspace, they're
working with a tremendous amount of
stale data. And that's just as bad as
context rot. It's essentially context
rot at the workspace level. And so let's
scroll back up to the menu and there's
one other thing. Let's get to the how it
works session. Um so there's data
surfaces and it's a core concept. Data
surfaces exist as individual JSON files.
All right. So I quickly want to talk
about how it works and go over a core
concept called data surfaces.
So a data surface exists as a JSON file
and base automatically registers and
reads these that gives base or claude
the signals that are relevant and matter
to you. Now you can create a surface for
just about anything that you want to
persist the state of and have Claude
just passively know about. Essentially
the data surface is what unlocks the
Jarvis from Iron Man with Claude code.
So you could just run a simple command
uh to create the surface and it's going
to walk you through defining what is
important to this or you know the schema
that goes into it how you want it to be
sent into claude then it's going to
generate everything and wire it up for
you. Now I'll show you what a data
surface
kind of looks like inside of my VS Code.
What I'm looking at here is the main
workspace JSON. Every time that you use
base, you set it up, it will install
this single folder in your main
workspace. This is what manages
everything.
The primary file is your workspace.json.
Now, as you can see, there's this
section here for areas. An area is
essentially a data surface. I'm for me
I'm saying that projects, clients, tools
and content are important to me. You
might have different things that are
important to you. Everything here is
being tracked and monitored by the hooks
and by claude. Also, if you happen to
use Paul, which I understand that this
Paul isn't what we're talking about
today, you can register all of your Paul
projects within this satellites section.
And this gives Claude immediate
awareness on every single session of
what all of your projects are and it
will help you stay focused and aligned
on what you're trying to do with the
work that you're doing. But today we
want to talk about bass and we want to
talk about Carl. So one thing I want to
do is I want to show you how Carl is
maintained using bass and then we'll see
how Carl is effective in and of itself.
And this is where the actual sauce is
going to be dropped because Chris is
going to show you how he's going to use
bass and a conversation with Claude. You
guys are gonna be like, "Wow, I didn't
know you could do that. Thanks, Chris
and Charlie or Chris." And then we're
going to walk into Carl. We're going to
do the same thing. We're going to go
through the readme. We're going to show
you a legitimate use case of how it
works. Then we're going to just show you
how to set it up so you guys can walk
away having these installed for
yourselves. Awesome. Right on. So, what
I'm going to do is I'm going to send in
this quick message to Claude, and we're
going to see these things start to
happen here in real time. So, I'm
basically just going to ask it to review
active projects and to let me know what
I should work on today. The suspense is
killing me. There we go. So, here is the
Friday picture. Um, we're talking about
some deadlines. We got nine days out.
Both of these are stale. I need to
essentially do a grooming session and
make sure all of the context is caught
up. So, it's letting me know that it's
been a few days since I've posted some
updates. That's a good signal for me.
Um, also at the bottom of this message,
you're going to notice there's a Carl
dev mode block. Now, this is where Carl
really does come in handy is turning on
the dev mode. What you can see is that I
had two different set of rules load into
the system messages for Claude like I've
been talking about with Carl. We have
the global global loads every every
time. No keyword matching needed. But
you'll see that projects was loaded as
well because I asked it to review active
projects and that's one of my key words
and I chose that because it's something
that I say to Claude.
>> Is that your safe word, Chris?
>> Review active projects. more.
>> I thought SL clear would be your safe
word. All right, Chris, enough with your
safe words. I could care less. So, if
Bass can solve your file structure, your
organization, and help you pull up
relevant data like he just showed you,
what can Carl do? So, can you pull open
the read me for Carl and we could just
do a highle analysis and then come back
to dev tools or dev mode because dev
mode is like the coolest thing in my
opinion with Carl. Yeah, absolutely. And
I second that. I love the dev mode. But
talking about Carl, um it stands for
context augmentation
and reinforcement layer. The whole thing
is about reinforcing the relevant
information at the right time to augment
the quality of your context as you go
through any session. But the dev mode is
a little bit different. it it's actually
not even related to the rules aspect
whatsoever because Carl is using a hook
and this hook is set to trigger every
time a prompt is sent in from me. I seen
that as a good opportunity to get some
insight into what's happening under the
hood every time I send a message to
Claude. What is really going on as it's
thinking and churning and doing all
these things that I can't see? How is it
coming up with its rationale? what rules
is it actually seeing and what rules is
it applying? Are there any gaps or
issues that it identified that gave the
results that I'm seeing now in the
output? That's what the dev mode block
is meant to do. So, it helps you to dial
in Carl. Um because if you're asking
Claude to do something and you have
rules or you have something set up and
you expect a certain behavior and then
you don't get that, you can reference
the dev mode and find what's going on a
lot easier. You can see the signal. So,
we're going to look at uh Carl a little
bit here, but I've already kind of
touched base on it. It's just categories
of areas that are important to you and
then the rules or the instructions that
you want. And Chris, I I just want to
add the fact that there are no specific
commands other than the initial setup of
Carl and base. The only thing that we
should probably show an example of is
the star commands because you can pull
it's kind of like on demand domains, but
you don't necessarily need them if your
keywords are specific enough because
Claude is smart. So, is there any I
don't think there's anything else here.
Let's dive into to Claude now and let's
show them the sauce because we're about
to get saucy. Man, I'm so weird.
Anyways, go ahead, bro.
>> That's okay. You're in good company.
>> Safe word. Safe word. Yo, my
>> active projects.
>> My safe word is pineapple.
>> Um, that's dangerous.
>> Have you ever seen Little Nikki?
>> My safe word is keep going.
>> Does that work out well for you?
>> Ask me to keep going.
>> Keep going.
>> See what happens. No, I'm still turned
on. Keep going. Cool. So now we're back
in VS Code and one of the the concepts
that we've been talking about is we've
got Carl that's got rules and we've got
Bass that manages like the whole thing,
the whole system and how healthy it is.
All right. Well, here's an interesting
combination between Bass and Carl
itself. So you've got Carl running and
let's say you've been using it for a
couple months now and you've got all
your rules loaded in. Well, Carl is also
susceptible to becoming stale. your
rules become outdated or maybe they're
just not optimized. That's where Bass
can help you keep Carl really dialed in.
And we're gonna actually kind of run
through this here and now. So, real
quick, um I'm going to look at my
Carl.json. This has all my domains and
all of my rules. My global is written in
a very specific way. You see all of
these never uh patterns here. Never
this, never that, never this. I have
found in my testing that this pattern
works extremely well and you get much
better compliance. Let's say let's look
at our projects which
>> when you want your AI to perform better
specify what you don't want rather than
what you do want. That is a huge factor
in our success with getting AI to
perform the way that we want. And Chris,
I'm excited for you to go over context
bracketing, but keep going.
>> Yeah, we're going to uh definitely touch
base on the context brackets, but first
I want to show kind of what the solution
here is to the problem that we're
facing. The problem is is that our
context gets outdated. It's not kept
kept up or maintained properly. And so
Claude gets dumb essentially. But it's
not about Claude being dumb. It's about
the workspace going stale, drifting, not
being maintained. And I want to show
this in real time actually because I
just got hit by stale information and
it's signaled me that I need to groom
this. What we'll see here is the
project's domain loaded and it brought
in all of my projects rules. Now
remember when I was showing you my
global rules, everything had that never
pattern that is the my most up-to-date
standard. And I haven't actually groomed
my projects uh domain in I can't really
tell you when. Looks like it says 316,
but that was actually whenever I set
this JSON up to begin with. So, what I
want to do is actually go through that
process and show you how bass helps you
keep your Carl rules and your context
relevant and up to date. I'm just going
to put in this simple command of base
Carl hygiene and we're going to let this
run. All right. So, Carl hygiene has now
surfaced the full picture and here is
the assessment. It's showing that we
have staged proposals. So, what bass
allows you to do in combination with
Carl is as you're working with Claude
and you encounter in real time things
that you want Claude to do differently,
you make the correction. And what Bass
does is it logs that to a session
memory. You groom these logs and if
anything looks like it's valuable beyond
just being a moment within a session,
you can actually move that through a
process to become an actual Carl rule.
Now, when it comes to making new rules
for Carl, it's always better to do so
based on experience and not try to think
ahead of what you believe a rule should
be, but actually go through the
experience of it and use the pipeline so
that you make sure that your rules are
relevant and dialed in. And you know
what's great is that a lot of this
architecture is evergreen because these
are frameworks that are based off of
legitimate business frameworks that
translate into development. Like how
would you organize your file drawer?
Like how would you organize everything?
And think about each one of these
statements inside of this file here are
basically just different files and
folders inside of your drawer. And
that's why this stuff is always going to
work. Now the technical applications and
the actual repo might change but the
frameworks and the ideology like all
this stuff stays the same. So you can
learn something here like you ever heard
the microcosm and macrocosm saying right
like as below so above like whatever.
That's kind of what we're getting at
here. So what's really exciting is not
just that this is evergreen and that you
can take this and use it in a variety of
ways but it's actually going to help you
make money. It's actually going to help
you make your projects better. And it's
free and open source. If you notice,
Space had a command integrating with
Carl. You don't need them together, but
they sure as heck work wonderful
together because they're part of the
same ecosystem, all from Chris's brain.
And if you guys want access to our
exclusive setup called Apex, it is
releasing alongside the Zero to
Dangerous course. and he's going to go a
lot deeper in the hooks and the way that
all this is set up so that you guys can
go from level one to level five. I did a
whole video on level one to five, but in
any case, what are we looking at here?
Cuz now it's asking us if we want to
approve, kill, or defer. What the heck
does that mean? Yeah, so the when you
run Carl Hygiene, it surfaces up all of
the staged proposals. And these are
basically rules that were made on the
fly. They stay in a log. And when you
run a hygiene, it will surface this and
say, "Hey, is this something that you
want to keep or do you want to go ahead
and just let this go or maybe save it
for a next review?" So that's what keep,
kill, or defer actually stands for. And
what it's doing is it's looking at the
first proposed rule. And this is one
about our school community. And
essentially, um, I'd made a rule of
never using one of the tools in the MCP
server that we have if the category is
broken. Now, this to me uh could
actually be an actual rule, but I'm
going to just for the sake of time defer
all of these. And I'm actually going to
tell it to defer all staged proposals.
Move to next phase. So, we're going to
move on away from reviewing the stage
proposals. I just wanted to show you
what that actually would look like in
practice. Uh so, as you're using the
whole base system, you're going to start
seeing these stages happen
automatically. It's something that
Claude does proactively for you as
you're just working with it naturally.
And then anytime you groom or run Carl
hygiene, it naturally surfaces these
things as well. So you get a second
look. And a lot of times we give a
correction to Claude. We forget about
that ourselves. Like we forget we ever
even corrected it because we're kind of
doing that all the time. But Claude with
base doesn't forget. It remembers that
you corrected it. And then when you go
to maintain your uh space and do the
hygiene, it's going to remind you, hey,
you corrected me on this thing. Do you
want this as a rule? And that is where
this staging pipeline allows you to keep
awareness of these corrections and if
you want to keep a rule, move it into a
Carl domain.
>> Yeah, it's either that you know and
you're dealing with Claude getting
dumber and you're frustrated, you're
hitting limits and you're just like what
the heck is going on or you're somebody
who's completely new to this and you're
like I just have no idea. So I'm kind of
like learning this from beginning to end
right now watching you guys. That's
totally fine. And then there are your
clawed codes of people who have created
their own solutions, but I haven't seen
a full-blown ecosystem for claw code
like we have. So he's went over the
hygiene aspect. We've looked over how
the Carl JSON is set up. And Chris, have
you went you have you went over domains
yet? Now we're looking at the domain
health check. Um, all of them are
active, all 12, but there is one flag
that it determined. my projects is at 15
rules. Now truly the best practice is to
keep it around nine rules, seven to nine
rules. I don't go over that. Um so this
is a candidate for cleaning up. Now I'm
not going to clean it up here and now.
Um that would take a little bit of input
for me, you know, to make sure that
certain rules are relevant. I would go
through and actually
>> you also you do that deeper in the
school anyway. So that's fine. I think
what I think what I want to see and I
think what everybody wants to see here
solving this biggest problem with
domains.
>> So you could see he has those domains.
Maybe you could scroll over on the JSON.
We could look at those domains. And
setting up the domains is literally as
simple as telling Claude, I want you to
set up a domain for this. So whenever I
use this, you pull in those active
rules. And then the coolest part is
honestly is going into your claw.md and
saying, "Hey, take a look at my claw MD
and let's dissect it. Which of my rules
on my MD can I just turn into domains
for the sake of simplifying and making
you smarter?" Something as simple as
that prompt will set up your domains for
you.
>> That's a good That's a good point to
make because like Bass actually has the
audit claude MD command. So what it will
do is it will read your claude MD using
the strategy approach to what makes a
good claude MD and it will also
determine what aspects inside the claude
MD are candidates for Carl domains and
Carl rules and we'll generate those
domains and rules for you rewrite your
claim MD as a separate file and let you
decide if you want to use it.
>> Right on. So before we do that, tell me
why Carl is better than just having a
claw.md because people are like, "Well,
I was just told to set up a claw MD. Now
you're telling me to use Carl." So why
is it better? Why is it making this
better? Well, it lets you use your claw
MD more strategically. So you can
actually be targeted about what you're
putting in there as opposed to it
becoming a junk drawer of rules and
instructions. You can take the rules and
instructions out and put them into a
framework that matches your intention in
the in real time. So you're typing a
keyword because that is what your
intention is. And then it goes to claude
and pulls in only the relevant
instructions instead of 500 lines that
loaded 20 messages ago in your Claude
MD. So it pulls it in right when it's
needed and only what's needed. And it's
direct signal given to Claude so it
performs better,
>> right? reducing noise, the 8020 rule,
2080 rule, parados principle, the other
key word that you mentioned is
intentional. Being intentional with the
rules that are being pulled in. It's
like if I'm having a conversation with
you about the best cereals in the world,
then I start talking about my favorite
cars. It's like, why are you talking
about cars? We're talking about
Cheerios, my guy. So, dumb example, but
that's kind of the idea. So, you could
run the audit here, but is there
anything else that you want to highlight
on Carl before we move into how to
install this? Because I think honestly
you're spoiling the audience here.
You're dropping a lot of sauce, man. Is
there anything that you want to finalize
with before we get into that?
>> Well, uh, earlier you mentioned the
context brackets. So, Carl is not just a
set of domains and rules. There's also a
section for decisions that are made and
the decisions get grouped with the
domain that they're made about. And so
every time the global domain loads, it's
also loading decisions. And in addition
to decisions, we have commands. You did
mention the star commands. I use those.
They're they're more lightweight than a
slash command. Uh and they can work kind
of in real time. So Claude can be mid
drift into doing things. and I'll throw
in a star command just to change the
mode that it's working in. Um, for
example, I have a star command called
star meta. And as I'm working on
something, if I identify through level
five thinking that, hey, this should
actually be systematized into a
framework or it should be systematized
into a skill, I will just type in star
meta in the middle of it working. And
then it will acknowledge, all right, I'm
thinking in meta mode. It will continue
doing its work and then it will surface.
All right, you mentioned star meta. So
now I'm looking at everything that we've
done up till now as well as everything
that is going forward to see how I can
work on the system instead of within it.
So what we were just working on was XYZ.
Here's how we can make it into a
framework or a skill so that you can
reuse it. And it it just immediately
changes its behavior and its mode in
real time without like having to invoke
a slash command and go through that
whole ceremony of loading all these
markdown files. It's just some rules
that changes its behavior and it happens
in real time. Um, and then the context
brackets. So, this is related to how
much context you have left in any
session. When you boot up, you're at
100%. You haven't used any context. But
as you go through the session, that
window shrinks. Then you'll go into the
next bracket of, well, now we're in a
moderate zone. We have 70% of the
session remaining. Then you go down into
a depleted zone where it's around 40%.
And then there's a fourth one called
critical that the hook calculates. And I
don't have rules for the critical, but
you can I can put a critical in here and
it's going to give those rules. I don't
actually use critical anymore because
the token windows grown quite a bit. And
so I'll run with fresh, moderate, and
depleted. And that does the job for me.
But essentially what these brackets do
is uh Claude needs to behave differently
when the context window is has shrank.
And what it does for me is whenever
we're in like the depleted stage, I'll
show you the rules. It's going to go
into heavy reinforcement mode. So, it's
going to then put different messages to
itself, like restating the thing that
we're working on. And that refreshes its
own context and its own thinking process
into what we're doing. And it just helps
it work a little bit more efficiently
later on in the sessions. It's
interesting because Claude isn't
naturally aware of how much context is
left. Before we had 1 million tokens per
each context window, believe we had
200,000. With that being said, when
you're chatting with it, it's not going
to tell you when it's going to compact
the conversation. And then it says, "I'm
compacting the conversation." You keep
running into that. And then the quality
of the previous conversation and that
context that translates into the next
conversation is diluted and it's not
focused on the main things necessary to
take your project to the next level,
maybe the next phase. So it's a
self-awareness tool as well with
context. And when you reach that
threshold, it's going to reinforce what
it's doing and it's going to tell you,
hey, it might be time to create a
handoff document. We go deeper on that
with Paul. So if you're on Paul pause,
it'll generate a handoff. Then you can
walk away from the project or resume. Do
Paul resume after you clear the contacts
and then it'll pull in that handoff
document, put it in an archive file,
throw it away somewhere, and then
perfect context for you right there on
the money always. So
>> 100%
>> mic drop. I mean,
>> mic drop. Yeah, you you nailed it.
>> And most importantly, we need to show
you how to actually set this up. So
we'll start with bass. And Chris, you
could pull open that read me. We'll show
you how to install this. Very simple.
We'll do the same thing with Carl. We're
going to give you some final thoughts.
I'm going to ask him some questions, not
much. And then we're going to conclude.
And if you guys are getting some value
out of this video, please consider
liking the video. It's a great way to
support us. And subscribe if you're
enjoying this content because we do one
of these episodes every single week. And
I'm personally dropping anywhere between
one to three long form videos on all
things claude code workflows, guides,
MCPS, plugins, you name it. So Chris, go
ahead, brother.
>> Yeah, so you'll see here on the base
readme that we've got a few different
commands. Um, I've got this on npm
registry. So we can use npx command to
install this just directly from the
registry. I personally recommend running
this command um doing the global
install. What that does is it puts all
of the base commands that help you run
the base workflows into your global. So
you can then use it in any workspace
that you set up and the framework files
go into your global as well. That way
you're not installing things directly to
your workspace that you're working in.
That just becomes noise and it's just
clutter. So install it into your global
and then go into your terminal in
whatever your whatever folder you want
to make your workspace. You might
already have one pre-existing. You might
want to make a new one and start fresh.
Doesn't really matter. Just go into that
particular folder in your terminal and
run the base scaffold command. That will
scaffold out your workspace, set up all
of your JSON files, and then walk you
through how to dial it in from start to
finish. That's the only command that you
need. And on that note of this being the
only command that you really need and
from zero to dangerous, I actually walk
through this entire process in real time
and build a whole workspace from base
and show you exactly how to dial it in.
So there is no guesswork, there are no
questions. I walk through the entire
thing there.
>> So if you guys have any questions on
this, join the school, drop a Q&A post,
or just leave a comment below. Now let's
move into Carl. And it's pretty much the
same thing. if not easier.
>> Yeah. Um, so let's click on getting
started. Just put this in right here and
Carl gets installed. It's recommended.
So when you run this command, you'll get
some questions to answer. So it's
interactive and it'll ask you if you
want to install this in the project or
if you want to install this globally. I
recommend globally as well. Um, and then
you can put Carl folders
wherever [clears throat] you want Carl
rules to exist. And I do want to make a
note that if you have a doc carl in your
workspace
and you're in a subfolder, let's say
you're in an application that you're
building, you can put a carl in that
application
and set custom domains that are just
specific to that application with custom
rules. I do this a lot with Laravel. As
I develop a Laravel, I've got a lot of
patterns and rules that I want Claude to
follow. I'll just set custom domains in
a custom.c Carl at the at the project
level, not the workspace. And the way
Carl hook works is when it's installed
globally, it will walk up the file tree.
So if you don't have a Carl inside of
your subfolder, it will then go up to
your workspace level and use that. If
you don't have one in your workspace,
you can even put your carl in your
global and it will use that as the final
stopping point. And stop. Don't worry.
You might be thinking this is
complicated, overwhelming. Maybe you're
seeing a terminal for the first time.
Maybe not. But you don't need to be
technical to understand how to use all
of this. Truly, with our education,
you're going to be able to go very far.
But even if you don't join the school,
using Claw to teach you how to use these
tools is incredibly useful. Whenever I
don't know something, I screenshot it. I
feed it to another claw and I say, "What
the heck is going on?" And then I learn.
And if you feel behind with AI, good.
You should. But the good news is that
we're all behind with AI. It's just a
matter of how far behind you are. And
the good news is a little bit goes a
long way as far as educating and using
the tools. We talk about mastering one
agentic coding tool, becoming extremely
dangerous at it, finding the highest
levers that you can pull at any time,
creating solutions for them, using
clawed code to do it. And that's how you
learn with the ecosystem. One problem at
a time, not trying to solve everything
altogether. There is a certain level of
strategy that you have to know and
understand and actually be able to
articulate in words before you start
building stuff. In the same way that we
use seed and we use Paul to ideulate and
to build with phases, you need to be
able to outline your thoughts and
everything effectively before you go
into any of these phases. So Chris, my
question for you, would Bass and Carl
take somebody from level one to a higher
level?
>> I would say so. Um, really that's level
four. Um, because once again, level five
is thinking in terms of like level five
is a personal thing. Level five is where
you start looking at your way of working
with Claude and how you can have Claude
work on itself to make your job easier.
So, I can't say that just using
frameworks and tools gives you that
level of working with Claude, but it is
definitely level four where it's
multiple different frameworks that all
work and it's all a cohesive ecosystem
and you're using skills, commands,
workflows, hooks, the whole thing, all
for the sake of orchestrating a context
engineering ecosystem. Would you say
this two stack combo alone would cause
early onset dementia with Claude?
>> Early onset dementia. Um, it's more of
the preventative there. So, this is that
one vitamin or the two vitamin combo
that Claude needs to absolutely not get
dementia.
>> Right. Right. Vitamin B and vitamin C
are extremely important.
>> Yeah. And unbiasedly speaking from 1 to
10, how important is this for somebody
to download and start using as a cla
code user themselves?
>> It just depends on the type of user of
claude code that you are. If you are
more passive and just using it to tinker
and you're cool with that, you don't
need these things. But if you actually
want to build and you want to make
Claude a significant tool in your
arsenal and use it to help maintain your
business, make deliverables, grow your
social medias, run your websites, all of
that, then this is absolutely important
to have because that's too much to
handle at one time in clauding. And if
you're not managing everything around
claude, then you're not getting the
right outputs. So, on that note, guys,
we really hope you guys got a tremendous
amount of value out of this. I've
already told you guys to like and
subscribe if you want more content like
this, and we highly recommend joining
the school. We're going to be dropping
the new curriculum inside of the CC
Strategic community April 15th. We just
hit a little over 2100 members today,
and we're extremely blessed and
fortunate to have these new
relationships being cooked up on the
inside. And if you would like to be a
part of that, consider joining. and
consider joining premium to get access
to Apex Zero to dangerous and a lot of
the other assets we have included. So on
that note, we will see you guys on the
next episode of Agentic Operators where
we're going to be going over Aegis and
Skillmith where we're going to be able
to conclude the videos on the ecosystem
and we're not too sure what we're going
to be doing next, but with your guys
feedback, I'm sure we'll figure out what
to post about next. out. See you guys
soon.